Three years ago, I taught myself how to
build a personal brand without any prior
experience doing so. And since then,
I've turned normal people into thought
leaders, gained them thousands of
followers, and even became number one
personal branding expert in the process.
Started multiple businesses, generated
over $1.5 million in revenue, grown to
$270,000 followers on LinkedIn alone,
and work with creators, entrepreneurs,
and companies you probably love and
follow. Now, most people start building
their personal brands and get stuck
posting content that never gets reached,
building a new, overly complicated
system or strategy every single month,
and feeling like they're falling behind,
wondering why they're not growing. The
effort is there, but the results aren't.
But this stops today because I just
created an entire year of LinkedIn
strategy, including everything you need
to know to grow, scale, and attract
clients to you. Now, as you can see by
the length of this video, this isn't
just another generic video telling you
to just post or to be authentic. This is
the blueprint that has guaranteed me at
a minimum to grow my account each year
by 50,000 new followers and add an extra
six figures in income every single year.
Look, I've got 270,000 followers, gotten
millions of views across my content, and
in the process, I have spotted the exact
strategies and frameworks that are
massive opportunity right now for
entrepreneurs and creators like you to
win this 2025 because this is the year
of the personal brand, and those who
don't have one will fall behind. And by
the way, if you're looking to speedrun
this process and you're looking to build
a personal brand, then I left a free
7-day course for you in the description
below so you can start taking action
today. In this video, I'm going to walk
you through exactly the 12 phases that
will guarantee your success on LinkedIn,
and I'll be breaking down these
strategies within each one of them that
you can implement step by step. Now, I
spent the last year building this
strategy, made every single mistake
possible so you don't have to. lost
thousands along the way, but they made
me millions as a result. But it all
started with one key thing, adopting a
creative mindset. See, I study social
media day and night. I observed the
market, understand the trends, talk to
the biggest marketers and strategists
across the world. And what the best
personal brands get right is this one
thing, the research phase. And this is
where most people who wish to create
content fail before they even begin. But
now you won't. Let me explain. Building
a parcel brand has become so popular
that every single person adopts the just
post mindset. Gary Vee and many others
have created this narrative around quick
action. However, it often leads to
disappointing results leading you and me
to never want to post content ever
again, thinking that it just doesn't
work for you or me or anyone. But when
you prepare yourself knowing what works
before you create, then you're setting
yourself up for fast success. My first
LinkedIn post went viral, 4,000 likes
and nearly half a million impressions in
literally 42 hours. And it happened
because I spent hours and multiple days
researching what hooks people were
clicking on, what sentence formats made
people stop scrolling, what creators
were posting, and what they weren't. I
even went as far as putting every single
viral LinkedIn post I saw into a Google
document because then I wasn't using
Notion to then reference when writing
one post. And the key ingredient wasn't
luck. It was researching what was
relevant. Social media platforms don't
reward originality. They reward
relevance. And this goes handinhand with
phase number two, reverse engineering.
This is where research and just post
come together. Making sure your content
cracks the relevant element every single
time so you can reap the highest
results. So instead of posting and
figuring out what works along the way,
start identifying what type of content
you want to create and stick to that
style for as long as you possibly can.
Educational content is the safest bet if
you want to make money anyway. And
having a list of creators who do it at
the highest level is needed so you know
what type of content is working. Think
about it like baking a cake, but you
only have one hour. You can either buy a
prepackaged cake mix where you can just
add an egg instead of having to get
multiple different ingredients and
figure out where they go and how to cook
them. You can simply shortcut your time
and effort by simply nailing your
research. So, let's say you have five
creators who post educational content.
Then, every week you'd look at what
content looks like and what outperform
them every single week. Then you use
that as data to then write a post within
your niche using the same style, hook
length, and even format of the post,
i.e. a carousel or an infographic or a
storytelling post. I do this for clients
every time, and it works because we're
not leaving anything to luck. We create
it, get the right data, and then build
the correct strategy. Now, phase number
three is obvious, but the execution
isn't. Let's say now you have identified
five posts that you can easily recreate.
80% educate and 20% are personal updates
or stories. Now you're excited about
them. They seem highly intentional and
well written. But then the next week
comes and suddenly you don't have any
content to post because you run out of
content ideas and then you found
yourself in analysis paralysis. This
happens to so many of us, me included,
because we fear on repeating ourselves.
But the reality is that through
repetition comes authority. Alexi talks
about one thing, office. Cody Sanchez,
Boring Businesses, Immanangaji, SMMA,
Justin Welsh, the one person business.
It is the most effective way to reach
your ideal audience and build brand
equity because you are known for one
thing. You need to make it easy for your
ideal audience to categorize you
instantly into one specific bucket. So
they recognize you, then they like you,
then they trust you, then ideally they
will buy from you. Just think about it
like this. When you create content, you
are being pushed into a small percentage
of LinkedIn's total audience. Meaning
that the post that you post on a Monday
would have only been seen by a few
people. And it's the same with every
single post. Every time you create
similar content, you are testing what
approach, format, style, and vocabulary
works best for you. What people respond
to best, what gets the most traction,
what gets you the most leads, and what
doesn't get you leads, etc. And over
time, just like a Facebook ad, you
statistically understand what people
like from you. You consistently test,
learn, and iterate. And by then, you'd
also have gained more eyeballs who are
interested in exactly that. This is a
data approach, not just a vibes
approach, which then leads me to phase
number four. When you find winning
content for your personal brand and
business, the typical instinct for a
LinkedIn user is to pin it to their
profile. LinkedIn, if you didn't know,
has this feature where you can pin a
post at the top of your profile, so
everybody immediately sees it. For 99%
of entrepreneurs I've worked for, they
take the one viral post they had and pin
it and leave it there forever. Do not do
this. The feature section has a lot more
potential when used, right? I actually
spoke about it in this video here, as it
can be used to drive traffic to your
actual offer instead of that one viral
post that at best will get you one like.
What you should do instead is dissect
the post and understand why it performed
well and recreate it multiple times that
month until something else clicks and
double down until it stops working. This
is how you avoid burnout from creating
content and maximize your success on the
platform. Now, what I just showed you
isn't just content. It's actually also
part of a signature style series. The
reason why some personal brands outlast
others even if they have less followers
and engagement is because they built
repeatable posting patterns that their
audience recognizes. And our brains love
patterns. And this is why I'm so set on
the idea of repetition, familiarity.
Once you find what resonates with your
audience and make it familiar to them,
you can then turn that into a series
that your audience loves and remembers
you specifically for. Let me show you an
example of someone who did this exact
same thing and blew up and actually even
made up to $100,000 in revenue for a
brand new business he built off the back
of LinkedIn. This is Louis and I
actually met him when he had around
1,000 followers or even less. He
actually started building his pass on
LinkedIn through video. Video is quite
controversial and if you've seen my
videos before, you know I'm not so
bullish on video, but he started a
signature style breaking down content
creators every single time. Now, this
was part of his signature style that he
started repeating so often that it
became part of his brand. And so when he
built this system, he removed all the
overthinking of what he should post
about and then started generating leads
and build a business. Now, his business
is selling video through LinkedIn and in
the process, he's worked with ClickUp,
Clay, and so many others. And I even saw
him hit his first $100,000 in revenue on
LinkedIn live. So, if we just look at
his content, he's consistently repeating
the same things. He's talking about
video, he's showing photos, he's doing
the same similar type of styles of
video, etc. This built him a six-figure
business on LinkedIn, worked with the
biggest B2B businesses on the platform,
hasworked with the biggest creators, and
I'm sure he's 100% happy with the
business that he has right now. All
because he built a signature style. He
found what worked for him, doubled down,
and then templatized it until it stopped
working, then built a new series based
on the elements from the last ones. And
I assume he'll rinse and repeat that
until it stops working, then he'll find
something else. It's literally genius,
and anyone can do it. All you need is an
idea, a pattern, and elements that make
it yours. To the most basic level, your
idea can be how to content. The pattern
can be highle breakdowns, and the
elements can be that it is a carousel
with images and blue and green fonts,
just like my friend Jake, who has grown
to nearly 200,000 followers on LinkedIn
doing exactly that. And by the way, I'm
also building Cleo with him, a content
tool that I've promoted here before, but
we've made it 10 times better now. a
content strategist in your pocket who
thinks like you and writes like you. The
proof is in the pudding for this. We've
got multiple thousands of followers
combined, built million-dollar
businesses through that and landed us on
Forbes, led us to work with your
favorite brands such as Kajjabi and
Beehive, and now we're helping you do
exactly that by making writing content
easier forever. Now, I want you to pause
for a second and rewind to what I just
said a few seconds ago. The proof is in
the pudding for this. We've got multiple
thousands of followers combined, built
million-dollar businesses through that
and landed us on Forbes, led us to work
with your favorite brands such as
Kajjabi and Beehive. And now we're
helping you do exactly that by making
writing content easier forever. The
reason why I mentioned specific numbers,
companies, and our accomplishments isn't
a flex, is to trigger what psychologists
call authority bias, which is exactly
what phase number six is all about. When
you haven't made a name for yourself yet
and no one knows you or what you do, you
need to build on perceived value. I call
this strategic authority stacking where
you aren't perceived as a newbie trying
but as an expert leading. You need to
position yourself as someone who's been
seen as trusted by others and therefore
worth buying from. You can do this at a
micro or a macro level. Let me show you.
At a macro level, you create content
highlighting the work that you have done
with other clients and the results that
you've gotten them. You can highlight
the clients that you work with and what
they said. And even if you can visually
show the results or elements will put
you in a different echelon than your
competitors. To a micro level, you can
have all of these highlighted all across
your LinkedIn profile as stacks of
social proof. So when people look on
your profile, they immediately see
exactly that authority. This is how you
can manufacture trust before you earn
it. Think about it like a shortcut to
landing your ideal clients. Here you are
literally pre-handling objections of
like, can I see some testimonials or
have you done this for people like me in
X, Y, and Z niche? Yes, it's literally
highlighted in your profile. I've
leveraged this to the maximum to the
point where I no longer need to take
sales calls because people trust me to
the highest level that they will click
and buy a $5,000 offer instantly. Now,
phases 7 to 10 are going to be quick and
tactical so we can get you off this
video and into implementation as soon as
possible. The truth about content
strategy is that in order for it to work
for you, you need to engineer your own
personal flywheel so it attracts people
daily, engages them, nurtures them, and
then converts them. We've created the
strategy. You've got the fundamental
idea of how to get content clicking
without diving into too much theory.
Now, the flywheel to get this going is
not to only reverse engineer, but using
specific writing frameworks that always
work. One of my favorite ones is pass
problem, agitate, solution. like in this
post right here when I want to convert
and then I use my slave framework when I
want to storyt tell and educate. So
story, lesson, action, you. These two
frameworks work incredibly well because
they build emotion and trust fast ser no
corporate jargon just clear writing. The
aim is for you to have these frameworks
ready for when you see content and
recreate it. You have the winning
content. You have the winning
frameworks. Now the last thing you need
is an elite image because these
guarantee your growth. Just look at
these posts. All of them have an image
and it's for a reason. People are visual
even on LinkedIn. Now, what gets the
flywheel going faster, though, and I
hate to say it because you'll hate me
for saying it, is engaging. I mentioned
this in nearly every video on LinkedIn
I've ever created, but engaging on other
accounts on LinkedIn is crucial,
especially when no one really knows who
you are. So, you tell them who you are.
You comment giving your experience. You
comment giving people some praise. And
you comment a joke so they notice you.
And at the bare minimum, there should be
30 comments done per day on other
accounts. And every single comment in
your post should be replied to until you
can't handle it. Is because naturally by
manufacturing engagement, your post will
have higher reach indicating to LinkedIn
that the post is good and further
pushing it into people's feeds even when
they don't follow you. You are creating
hype for yourself and then people
inevitably will follow suit. I do this,
my clients do this, and some of you do
this. It just works. Granted, your post
has to be good to start. Now, over time,
your content will start reaching new
baselines. You'll go from 20 likes on
average to 100 likes on average to 200
likes to 400 likes and so on. The way
you build this up fast is to be quick
with your content iteration. Every time
you find an outlier post you posted, it
is in your best interest to replicate
it, not just on the topic, but in
multiple different topics. For example,
look at my carousel format here. I saw
it worked, then I replicated it, it
worked better, then I optimized it, then
it worked a h 100 times better, and I
doubled down until I gave up on
carousels. But I'm sure if I kept on
going, I'd be at a million followers by
now. Now, talking about followers
though, if you made it this far into
this video, please subscribe to my
channel. I've been filming this video
for way too long. You can literally see
the sun coming from behind, and my
editors told me that for every new
subscriber I get, I get a new um energy
drink, which means there would be more
videos coming. So thank you. Now the
last phases of this mega strategy is
building an algorithm proof brand and
mega growth. Both of them go hand
inhand. Becoming algorithm proof is the
one desire most people creating content
on any platform want where you can post
anything trending not trending templated
not templated and it works and it makes
money while you're sleeping. And many
people try to find the hack to this but
no one I know touches on the actual
thing that makes this happen at scale.
And it's not another engagement hack or
a specific type of post. It's actually
something else that I discovered by
accident. And if you go onto my LinkedIn
and you scroll a few seconds, you'll see
exactly what that is. See, there's viral
creators and then there's lifetime
creators. Viral creators create content,
but if you cover their name and profile
with your hand, you wouldn't know who
they are. They have interesting content,
but the interesting thing isn't about
them. It's usually about something else,
like a trend or an article or even an
update. It builds zero brand equity.
Lifetime creators who outperform the
algorithm create their own algorithm
where you can recognize them from a mile
off because even when they educate you
on their niche, you're staying for them.
Now, I'm going to run you through my
content to show you exactly what I mean.
If we quickly run through my content,
you can see that it is very unique to
me. It's got my storytelling. It's got
my photo. It's got my individual
experiences. And even when I don't use
my own photo, there's an element of me
plastered all over these posts. Now, the
reason why is because I honed in on what
I said at the start, repetition. I built
that credibility for myself by creating
repeatable content that resonates with
my audience. I found them by creating
content until I found that winning
trend. So, I've literally used this
exact step-by-step framework for myself.
So, I know it works. Every single piece
of content that I create cannot be
replicated by someone else because it's
very unique to me. Even if the topic is
as broad as copyrightiting, personal
branding, storytelling, you can tell
it's mine because of how I wrote it, the
stories that I've used and the
frameworks that I'm using. You can also
see different formats like I try video,
I try carousels, I try photos, I try
infographics, I try everything. And
sometimes it works, sometimes it
doesn't. Sometimes it converts,
sometimes it doesn't. But I still keep
on iterating until I find a new winning
trends because the algorithm changes.
But I am algorithm proof because I keep
on trying new things. And this is
something people fail to mention. You
need to try new things in order to get
new outcomes and better results.
Visibility and memorability are the keys
to our retained personal brand. They are
the core of what a brand actually does
and how content becomes easy and
ultimately how you become the niche in
the end. This sounds simple and it
literally is. Stick to this for 365 days
and watch your life change. I am
cheering from you from the sidelines and
I hope to see you on my timeline soon.
Also, if you like this video, then you
love this one on the screen right here.
I broke down the seven strategies that I
use that are so effective that they feel
illegal to know. These are the exact
same tactics that have gotten me
featured on Forbes and built multiple
sixf figureure success stories for my
students. Click on it now and I'll see
you over