What if you didn't have to pay for a
course? What if you didn't have to pay
for coaching? What if you didn't have to
wait for every single answer you've been
waiting for in order to start building
your personal brand on LinkedIn? What if
you could just sit? Well, today we're
live in Bosnia with my good friend
Jasmine Alik, Fortune 500 copywriter,
over 350,000
followers on LinkedIn. And today we're
in front of 50 people from 20 different
countries live and we're going to be
answering every single one of our
[music] from the algorithm, from how to
create content, from what content
actually gets leads, and every other
question that people have been
gatekeeping from you, [music] but we're
not. So, Jasmine, are you ready? Born
ready. Let's go. The LinkedIn algorithm.
Oh, that's a short answer. No one knows
how the LinkedIn algorithm works. I feel
like the one thing about the LinkedIn
algorithm is we try, we do our best. We
do our best to understand it. Like we do
our best to draw inferences and to kind
of deduce things. I'm using big words.
But, no one really knows how it works
because LinkedIn doesn't want to let us
in on that information, ever. I was at
the LinkedIn offices. I was at the
headquarters in New York City. I asked.
No one knows. Not even the employees
know how it works. But again, we as
creators, as coaches, as people who have
a little bit of more insight than the
average LinkedIn user, we genuinely do
notice certain things that are happening
that not everyone can notice. So, as far
as the LinkedIn algorithm hacks and
videos that are concerned, it's almost
never, almost never, LinkedIn confirmed
information. But it is user confirmed
information. I feel like that's a
distinction that needs to be made
already at the beginning of this
conversation.
>> I think that's what's caused all of this
controversy recently around the LinkedIn
algorithm came after the release of 360
Brew, the paper that got released, eight
pages, 42 sentences long. And it caused
a lot of confusion, more so than
clarity. And it was released by
LinkedIn's technical team officially.
But then later it was withdrawn. Then it
was found in archives where people were
able to draw their own conclusions. Now,
I read this paper back and forth many
times because I was doing a script for a
an algorithm video. The conclusion that
I arrived to is that not even the
LinkedIn engineers understands human
psychology and what the paper says
versus what is true at hands actually
doesn't make sense because what you and
I see versus what these papers confirm
is very different because ultimately
when these engineers are creating the
new algorithms and how, you know, now
it's just instead of different little
algorithms it's just one. That doesn't
take into account human psychology and
how everyone in this room, you and I,
interact with each other's posts because
you cannot engineer that. Surely it can
help, yes. And yes, some posts may get a
lot more reach, but if we're just
following from these data points and
saying that educational content is the
best content, is the only content that's
going viral, yet via our own research,
after we spent what, 5, 10 hours on the
platform every single day, we notice
what goes viral. It is not just
educational content. It's actually
memes, stories, and even comments. Our
two cents, yes, algorithm updates are
there, but they are not the only update
that you should be thinking about. Like
you say, LinkedIn is not B2B, it's not
B2C, it's H2H, which is Human to human,
guys. Always, forever.
>> At the end of the day we're dealing with
humans. You guys are engaging with our
content and I think when we are
optimizing for human interaction rather
than just mechanics, things actually
work and you build a truly authentic
personal brand without having to suffer
with the authentic type of content that
actually doesn't perform.
>> exactly it, right? Like we talk about
the algorithm as if there's some sort of
set of rules that we have to follow as
humans. And it's like someone else
controls it. But it's like literally the
other way around. What is an algorithm?
An algorithm is just a result of human
behavior. Like we, the users, create the
algorithm, right? It's like we love a
good meme. We love a good joke. So it's
not LinkedIn pushing memes. It's not
LinkedIn making memes go viral. It's us
as people. We're reacting to it. So
naturally, the more you react to it,
you're going to start to draw in more
content that is exactly like that. If
you react to more memes in the feed,
you're going to start to see more memes
in the feed. If you react to more
educational, businessy, niche content,
you're going to start to see more of
that in your feed as well. So I feel
like this whole conversation about, "Oh,
what's the latest algorithm update?" The
question is, "How have we, the users,
been behaving recently?" That's the
question. It's almost like, for me, like
when I said I said this on a recent
podcast and it got a lot of engagement.
Someone asked me, "What changed recently
on LinkedIn cuz you've been here for
years and years and years?" I'm like,
"Nothing's changed in the last 5 years."
And it was like complete silence for
like good two to three seconds. Like,
"What do you mean nothing's changed? We
keep seeing new algorithm, new update,
new this, new that." And I'm like,
"Literally nothing's changed." Every
piece of content, every bit of behavior
that has worked 5 years ago on LinkedIn,
on social media in general, still works.
It's just certain trends. The music, the
style, the colors, again, the type of
humor that exists on the internet. It's
only that that changes. But what's
underneath the behavior, the kind of
content, the psychology behind the
content, like if you can write a good
book, it's the same style that worked in
2000 as it is, you know, 20 years and 30
years later. It's the same style because
it's all psychology. It has nothing to
do with algorithms. If you're looking at
what makes a good image, what makes a
good photo, like I talked to you guys
about this a lot about distractions in
the photos, right? Like make sure you
center your face, like the rule of
two-thirds. Make sure it's not
completely in center, it's like off-axis
a little bit on the first line if you're
looking at two-thirds. It's like it's
psychology. These are evergreen
principles and no algorithm can change
this. Especially with LinkedIn, I feel
like you and I know this. There was a
time when there was only text-only
content. Mhm. Right? And we were doing a
lot more text-only content. But then
LinkedIn came out and said, "We are
building a LinkedIn feed." LinkedIn said
it. Now, imagine what the consequence
is. Like what could possibly be the
consequence of a platform telling you,
"Hey, we're going to push more video."
Naturally, what do people do? They
create more video. So then it's like,
"Oh, video is popping. Video is like
getting some love from LinkedIn." I'm
like, "No, it's not. It's just that
people started creating more video." See
how this works? It's almost never the
algorithm. It's just our behavior. And
yes, human behavior kind of changes over
time, year over year, with trends. That
is the key part, with trends. But human
behavior, in terms of psychology, in its
essence, in terms of how we think, in
terms of how the brain reacts to certain
things, this hasn't changed for hundreds
and thousands of years. Worth
remembering. Whenever you see a
conversation about the algorithm,
remember that. It's almost never the
algorithm, it's us and our behavior.
>> Talking about psychology and human
behavior, there's this bias that I like
thinking about, it's called novelty
bias. Mhm. And I recommend every person
watching this and you guys in the
audience to think about it anytime you
see a new update. Brand new LinkedIn
playbook. New way to get leads. How
often do we see these online? Multiple
times. But why do we see them? And more
so, force yourself to think, why do we
click on it every single time? Because
we are consistently thinking about the
next best way to do something. And hence
why when we see the new algorithm
report, the new algorithm trend, the new
algorithm PDF with 80 pages saying the
same thing, but covered under the
disguise that is for 2026, 2027, 2028,
forever, we are almost forced by our
brain, like main dominant brain, to
think, "Oh, there must be a new hack
that I can use to get ahead." And in
reality is that we as humans, we want to
look for shortcuts and that's normal and
that's fine. But when you understand
that in reality there is no shortcut to
build a million-dollar business, a
multi-thousand follower personal brand,
and there is just psychology, good
content, and great positioning, you
understand what you need to do faster
and you stop getting distracted by this
new shiny object syndrome of, "Oh,
LinkedIn just released this video feed.
Now I have to learn how to create video
and I have to be the best at doing video
forever." It's not that. It's, "How do I
use what I currently have to adapt to
the trends that are currently happening
while still using the same thing that
I'm still doing in order to still kind
of like benefit from these new algorithm
trends." For example, Jasmine and I do
this very often, but we do it with a lot
of tact. So we don't clickbait people
in. So there was this post that Jasmine
did, I think two months ago, and it was
like, "I went to the LinkedIn
headquarters. Here's everything I know
about the algorithm." And then it was a
listicle with 10 things. In the 10
things, they were like, one, they have
great LinkedIn headquarters. Two, they
love burgers, too. And three, something
else. Are you going to pull it up?
>> I could pull that post up. And in
reality, Jasmine was taking advantage of
that novelty effect, but also kind of
taking the piss in a very British sense
at all of these algorithm hacks and
trends because there is no news when we
go to the LinkedIn headquarters. You and
I have been to the LinkedIn headquarters
over like four times each. Do we learn
anything? No. Do we teach them stuff?
Yes, because what we learned is that the
LinkedIn headquarters and the people
around it, they're not essentially us.
Like they're not addicted to the
platform. They're looking at it from a
business lens and a marketing lens from
the outside. How to sell Sales Navigator
to more businesses. How to do that.
Rather than the algorithm saying this,
they don't know. I found the post, by
the What did it say?
>> The hook was, "Here's what I learned at
LinkedIn headquarters." And the rehook
said, "Including stuff about the new
algo." You see what I've done? New algo,
right? So you have a reason to click. I
said new for a reason cuz people are,
again, always looking for that latest
hack, that latest trend. So, here's a
list of 10 things. Number one, they have
the best fries I've tried in New York
City. Number two, they have logos in
different colors on every floor. Number
three, nobody knows how the LinkedIn
algorithm works. And then number four,
the Empire State Building entrance is
massive. Number five, not a single soul
mentioned video to me. But you see what
I'm doing? I'm literally not
clickbaiting people. I said, "Here's
what I learned at LinkedIn
headquarters." And I'm sharing my
experience. And there was just one line
to get you curious that said, "Including
stuff about the new algo." I didn't say
here's a breakdown, here's a strategy
doc, here's a PDF. I never said that. So
out of the 10 things I mentioned, only
two were like, "Oh, we were looking for
this answer." And I'm like, "Nope,
you're not going to get it." Cuz even I
can't get it. I can't get that answer
cuz no one knows that answer, right? So,
it's like you kind of got to make fun of
the fact that everyone wants to truly,
deeply, really get information outside
of LinkedIn, right? You want to talk to
them, you want to talk to the people who
work there, and you want to get a 100%
certain answer that says, "Here's what
to do, 1 2 3. Here's how you can get the
most success on our platform." And you
know what? You're never going to get
that answer. Trust me, I've tried. I've
been trying for the last 5 years. Never
have I gotten a single piece of insight
where it's like a 100% certainty. Let me
ask you a question. How does a top voice
badge on LinkedIn get awarded?
>> Wait, do you have a top voice badge?
>> I don't have a top voice
>> Oh, me neither. But Wait, how many
followers do you have? How many
followers do you have?
>> have no clue. 358,441
at the time of recording this. No top
voice badge. No top voice badge. How
many people do you think you have
converted to the platform?
>> Goodness gracious.
>> Mhm. But here's the funny part.
Recently, like a couple of months ago,
LinkedIn did this purge of top voice
badges, and they removed a lot of top
voice badges for a lot of people. I
can't tell you how many people messaged
me, and they were like, "Yasmin, did you
lose your top voice badge?" Same. Yeah.
And I'm like, I never had it. So, my
point is, you can be a top voice of the
platform without a freaking blue badge.
The badge is just meaningless colorful
thing you put on your profile to make,
you know, to make you feel good about
yourself. But ultimately, it's your
audience who decides. It's the business
that you build. It's the amount of money
you make from the business. And that
authority, that creates a top voice.
When people follow, heck, what are we
doing here? We got people from 20
countries who flew for no other reason
than to hang out, right? To meet me, to
meet Laura in person, to see Bosnia, and
to see each other, to meet in person.
So, it's like, to you guys, to each and
every one of you, you are top voices.
You are literally top voices to each
other. And do you really need a blue
badge to verify that? No. The answer is
always going to be no. I feel like the
point that we're trying to make is we
always look for shortcuts, somehow, for
whatever reason. It's human nature to
look for shortcuts, to find that shiny
new thing that works, and then we want
to try it, and we want it to work for
us. But it's like, there are just
certain things about human behavior that
will never change, that have never
changed. So, instead of focusing on
trends and hacks, let's just study a
little bit more about psychology, about
user behavior, right? Let's read those
books that are evergreen, right? I
always talk about the book Don't Make Me
Think Influence by Robert Cialdini.
Influence by Robert Cialdini, there you
go. I feel like it's these timeless
principles of human behavior. This one
talks about how to genuinely influence
people in the right way, and how to stay
top of mind, and how to never leave the
mind of the people you want to impress,
convert, and keep in your life. That's
influence. The book that I mentioned,
Don't Make Me Think, it's a freaking
UX/UI book about behavior in the online
world. But when you're looking at like
websites and landing pages and how we
behave, where do our eyes go? How much,
how fast do we scroll, and where do we
click? That is literally user behavior
that then you can apply to any platform
out there. So, let's study a little bit
more of that, right? Let's really fall
in love with psychology again. But let's
really fall in love with writing, the
craft of writing. And I feel like this
is the perfect time to kind of segue
into AI. Yes or no? Cuz I know you have
some thoughts on it, cuz you already
have an AI writing tool. Yeah.
>> I have a different perspective on it,
and you know it. I'm not against that,
but I feel like it's a great
conversation to be had.
>> AI versus no AI, let's go. I'm the
non-AI team, you know this.
>> I know this. Yeah. So, do you want to
fight?
>> want to fight, because you're going to
lose. Yo, I can't believe this. I always
win. Of course. It's you versus you, so
you always win. That was the quote.
Period.
>> it in a post a couple years ago. I feel
like that's also one more thing that is
kind of a timeless conversation. How
much do we really start to trust other
things? Not even going to say tools and
AI or whatever it is, cuz it's always
going to be something new. How much do
we trust other things, yes, things,
versus our own brain? The more AI
evolves, the more we lose touch with our
own thoughts. It's not the end result
that matters in this conversation. The
end result is ultimately, you're going
to get to it, right? Whether with or
without AI. You're going to get to the
end result, you're going to determine,
"Hey, this is good enough for me. I'm
going to put it out there." Then the
audience decide, "Okay, it's good
enough. We're going to put perfect." But
I feel like what's a very terrifying
conversation to be had is the first step
of that process. Who does the thinking?
Whose end product is it really? Right?
And that is exactly why I wanted to talk
about this, cuz it's a tough
conversation.
>> It's not tough for me. It's actually
quite dramatic, in my opinion. Oh, let's
go. Let's just we are on opposite
>> hear where you are, seriously.
>> opposite sides, but you're going to see
us like in our house. Our house fight?
Not for alive. That's fine.
>> Well, FYI, Yasmin and I fight literally
every single day, so this is normal for
us. All right. So, my case for AI
content. The winners of the future are
the people that you say I win they have
previous expertise that they can turn
into AI-generated content. The losers
are going to be the people that
over-rely on AI to create their own
thoughts, because they've never really
thought a unique singular idea by
themselves. So, people like you and I,
people like the people in this room that
have done the work, that have had
clients, that have had, you know, build
their own frameworks. Some of you guys
are authors, some of you guys are
coaches, some of you guys are students.
You've learned enough to be able to put
that specific expertise into an AI
model, and let it write your own
expertise for you in a more concise,
tangible, LinkedIn-friendly formatted
way that 2 to 3 years ago would have
taken every single one of you hours or
months. No, not even months or even
years to learn. Like, how many of you
took like, I don't know, over 5 months
to understand how to write a good hook?
Like, raise your hands. Yeah, many of
you. How many of you like still are
struggling to understand how to format a
good post or how to write it? Yeah? So
many of you like, when you have your
expertise put into one document, and
then you are able to enable AI to do the
hard work for you, because you guys are
busy. You guys run businesses. Some of
you guys are parents. And I think that
is what AI is enabling to do for people.
Save time while it's remaining an
expert. We're not intending to remove
that expertise part, because we've seen
what happens, and it just creates
generic But when you put an authority
that just doesn't want to spend the
hours that we spent learning copywriting
into it, they can actually win. And I've
seen it firsthand. Like, I've seen some
of our clients at Creo get their first
viral post. And you just well as I know
the power of being seen for the first
time. Mhm. And the outstanding effect
that it can do for someone's visibility,
and also your ego. Like, you feel good,
you finally feel seen. And I think that
is the role of Creo. It's not to take
over your brain, it's to enable it to go
faster and do better. Perfect point.
Now, here's me being the devil's
advocate there in that scenario.
Everything you described is about
learning and understanding and making it
easier, correct? Right? Cuz it's like,
it's going to save you time, correct. AI
should help you with that. That's what
you should use it for. Also, for
context, I'm not against AI. I've never
been against AI. I'm just against this
one piece of the process, one piece.
Everything you described, there's
learning things, do use AI, it's going
to save you a lot of time, right? In the
past, you literally had to go to 4 years
of university. Now, you can just ask AI
to summarize something for you, and
literally explain it to you in your
style of learning. That's crazy. You're
going to learn it, A, check. Do use it
for that. Save yourself time, save
yourself a bunch of stress and money.
Number two, learning and understanding
go hand in hand. So, number one,
learning for the first time, then
understanding it, you're going to be
iterating a lot. But then comes the
application part. And this is exactly
where I start to have a problem with
people, not AI, with people. There's
creating your own thoughts, and there's
managing thoughts created by AI. I have
a problem with the other one. This is
just me being very personal. I coach a
lot of people. I've coached hundreds of
people all over the world. And I hate
seeing people not use their brains. It's
like, if someone else creates the
thoughts for you, and then you manage
the thoughts so that it sounds like you,
bro, why didn't you just think for
yourself in the first place? Cuz if you
can manage the thoughts, and you know
exactly what to convey, why didn't you
do it in the first place? It's like, it
almost takes more time. That's the only
part of the process that I have a
problem with, the creation part. It's
like, 2% of the process. 98% is good AI
usage. The 2% is what I have a problem
with. Who creates the thoughts? And
we're already seeing this. There's
research out there that suggests the
signal that it takes to get to the human
brain, the electric signal to the
nerves, it's slowed down for the first
time in human history. That is
terrifying information. No one's talking
about it. It's slowed down in just 5
years. Meaning, we're not using our
brains to create, we're using our brains
to manage, and that is different. It's
almost like going to the gym, and
someone else is lifting the weights for
you. It's like, you have to have that
strain. You have to do the work, right?
It's like having a spotter on the bench
press. It's like, if you can do it by
yourself, best believe you're going to
get stronger. Best believe long-term,
you're going to be a different person.
But if you have a spotter, it's usually
a slower process, and you're kind of
relying on help. So, that's the part I
have a process with. And sure, it could
be a personal opinion, right? But that's
why I coach people, because I do have
personal opinions. I do have personal
agendas here that really don't align
with everyone. And I feel like that 2%
of the process, creation of thoughts and
managing thoughts, which one are we
doing? That's genuinely a question.
Which one are we doing? Are we thinking
for ourselves? Are we allowing AI to
think for ourselves, and then managing
that? You don't have to answer this
question. This is just something to
think about. This is just something I
love to ask. And everything you
described, it's a beautiful example of
how to use AI properly.
>> Well, that's how we should be using it.
But what you're describing is the
winners and losers of the next era of
AI. And you are backing the winners,
because the winners were always going to
win with AI or without AI. The winners
are winning faster with AI, because
they're using their own thoughts. They
understand that their own thoughts are
very valuable, and they're not just
putting, "Hey, ChatGPT, write me a
LinkedIn post that goes viral." And it's
like, "I am celebrating my new hire fire
emoji." Like, no. They're the people
that take that quick little write-up,
and then they add their own thoughts,
and that's who you love. That's who I
love.
>> to touch upon that. And I feel like
that's the easiest example ever, right?
So, just so we don't get misunderstood,
like, you shouldn't be using AI. No, no,
no. I I never said that. No, it's like,
yeah, absolutely.
>> There you go. It's like, when you're
given it instructions, there's a
specific type of way of prompting AI,
right? And I feel like the majority of
people, they just prompt it by trusting
it. It's like, "I need a post on XYZ
topic, write me something in the style
of this creator. Done. But that's not
enough. You've done zero thinking. But
if you can say this, write me a post on
this topic. Here's what I want to
communicate. Here are some thoughts that
have recently been on my mind. A, and
then give it some quotes. B, give it
some quotes. C, give it some quotes.
Maybe give it even a bullet point list.
Then write in the style of this creator.
Now you've done the thinking because you
already know what you want to say. But
it's like you're not a writer. You're
not a professional copywriter. Like you
don't know how to say it properly so
that it sounds attractive. It makes for
a good hook. And it makes for a great
structure of a post. That is the correct
usage of AI. Why? Only one difference.
You've done the thinking. And now when
you're managing the output, you're not
managing AI's thinking. You're managing
your own. It's just that AI helped you
save a lot of time. It's really that
easy. I feel like it's a 2-minute fix.
But most people don't do it. And that is
exactly why I have a problem. I see
people overly relying on AI. And those
are genuinely going to be the losers of
the next age of this online game. again,
they were going to lose anyway. They
were going to lose anyway. Because
they're like taking the fast track and
shortcut. But this needs to be talked
about. It's easy to fall into this trap.
For real. It is. But I think I've been
able to fall into that trap many times.
Luckily, I've had people like you to
save me out of a trenches of any shiny
object. But I think it's necessary to
fall into it to see how bad it can get.
And to feel like what you'd look like
when you're trying to be a carbon copy
of anyone else. Like how many times have
you logged onto LinkedIn and you read a
post and you're like, did I write this?
Wait, that's not me. Like literally,
that's my post.
>> But there are some tools out there that
I should probably sue. They're using
your name and your likeness.
>> then we see the difference. Like our
content would get 2,000 likes. Our
content would get 30 likes. Same
content, different like it's not just
the content, it's also the community
that we've been able to build. And I
think that also segues really well into
like the people that we have in the
audience right now. Like this is not
just from formatted AI content. This is
from like years of effort that we built
over the last four or five years. And
now we're able to be here in front of
all of you guys because of that. Not
just or perfectly formatted content and
the fact that we used an image that uses
your whatever thingy of that he screams
to everyone about. Or the perfect
carousel. It's been because we've
leveraged the thing that AI cannot do
well yet. I think that too ever. And
that is building a true connection and
emotional connection with people. And
that's what we've done very well. And I
think that's what's missing from a lot
of people's LinkedIn strategies or every
overall marketing strategies is the
thing that you cannot scale. And that is
community building. You cannot scale
that. Not everything should be scalable.
Like we cannot hire people to do what we
do, which is talk to you directly. And
we love it.
>> think the name of the game is in those
who love to play it even if you can't
pay someone else to do it for you.
Speaking of community, do you want to
take some community questions? Because
we did bring people here. There's about
50 people here in front of us. All
right. So, I have some rules. I want you
guys to ask us the hardest questions you
wish you had the time to ask either of
us. Like ask us something that you
actually want solved once and for all.
You have us both here. And I will say
this, even if it's a personal question.
Because I feel like a lot of times when
I write stuff that it's like behind the
scenes content, like how I approach
things, like certain problems that I
fixed. It's like you guys resonate more
with that compared to like a piece of
advice type of post that I would write.
So, even if it's like a super hard
personal question, feel free to ask. I
will be very genuine in my answers. Who
wants to ask questions? Let me just see
how many hands we have so far. Okay,
we'll go one by one. Hi, my name is
Lorraine. Hi Lara. Hi Yasmine. And I
flew from Singapore to Sarajevo to see
you guys and the amazing Linkup
community.
>> [applause and cheering]
>> Uh my question is, I do two things that
are very different. I'm a lawyer turned
coach. So, I'm an executive coach. And I
do data privacy consulting. And when I
meet personal branding people, they
can't stand it. So, they're yelling at
me going, no, one person, one brand.
Ditch it. To move your executive
coaching to Instagram. Only talk about
consult data privacy consulting on
LinkedIn. But my ICPs are there. And
being remaining in the lawyer community
gives me face time with my ICPs. I'd
love your thoughts on it. So, let me
just ask you this. What you're saying is
even though you have a two-pronged
brand, the ICPs pretty much still
aligned. Yes. So, why is that a problem?
It just looks like two different
services. It's not two different brands.
That is okay cuz here we are, we have
like three or four different company
brands, right? Both of us. This is just
a question that I will try to give an
answer to you personally, but it's also
a generalized answer to everyone. I feel
like the whole niche down conversation,
it's necessary, but at times it's also
very irrelevant for a lot of people.
Here's why. Sometimes you just happen to
do two different jobs, but the audience
is still the same. In your case, it's
about the audience you're speaking to.
You're just offering two different
things to them. So, two things you need
to remember. Number one, you can do it
that way. Continue. There's no one you
that can tell you you should just be
doing this, you should just be doing
that. Continue doing what you do. But
number two, do remember, and this is me
giving you an honest opinion based on
hundreds, thousands of people I've
coached. It will be harder for you to
position yourself. It will be harder for
you. The easiest way to position
yourself is to be remembered for that
one thing and that one thing first. It
takes a lot of years of branding,
positioning, and being out there, and
being successful with that one thing
first. I keep saying this because only
after that time period has passed, I
believe it's the right time to introduce
a second thing. My question, honest
question to you, and give me an honest
answer. Do you think enough time has
passed for you to be doing two things?
Have you positioned yourself in just one
of those like really, really well? Well,
I I'm known I just need a yes or no.
Don't complicate. Have you positioned
your well yourself well? See? So, just
remember this. You can continue doing
it, but it will be harder for you. It
will be harder for you. Okay?
>> My question back to you is, if there's
something that's been pressing on your
mind, right? Cuz you asked me this as
well yesterday. Is it impacting your
revenue or your ability to grow your
business or your personal brands? All
three. Like not knowing which niche to
go for and having to I don't know what I
don't know. I know why I'm doing two.
Are both making you money? Yeah. You're
good. Yeah, you're fine. You're good.
Cuz like if it came to a point where
you're like, I am struggling to make
money for either, then our conclusion
would be to drop the one that is not
gaining you any leads from LinkedIn. But
if you're doing well in both right now
doing what you're doing, then you're
fine. But if you're asking, hey, okay,
so now I want to double down on my
following, then what I would personally
say, being someone that's has four
different businesses in different niches
and uh sometimes it doesn't make sense.
I would say find the intersection
between what you do for one business and
the other. And there's always going to
be a middle ground where you can relate
to both audiences. And that to me will
always come from storytelling. So that
you can talk openly about the fact that
you have two different offers and why
you're passionate about them. And then
talk to those two types of ICPs, which
are essentially the same. And then
communicate that why you're doing both
and why you're excellent at doing both.
That's what I would do. Awesome. I I
love your refreshing answers. Thank you.
Thank you, Lorraine. Hell yeah. Who's
next? Hey. Hi. I'm Nikki. I want to ask
a non-LinkedIn related question, but
something we can all relate to. Is have
you ever experienced burnout? And if
yes, what exactly did you feel and how
did you overcome it? What what do I say?
What do I say? You know my answer.
Yasmine and I share this new favorite
quote that we both loved. And it says,
you can't burn out, you're not a candle.
Yep. I even have a hoodie that I
received from a community member. Shout
out Linkup community. The reason why I
personally don't think I've ever burnt
out is I understand that burnout comes
from when you're doing things that you
don't love, right? You can feel tired.
You can feel exhausted. But I think the
word burnout has been overly used. Like
ADHD, like OCD, like anxiety, and
everything else. If you're doing
something you love, you can't burn out.
And if you feel burnt out, maybe you're
just tired of doing the exact same
mundane thing without getting any
results. I think that's what leads most
entrepreneurs to exhaustion and feeling
burnt out because they're not seeing any
progress. think about all the
entrepreneurs like Elon Musk, Sam
Altman, that face endless hours of work
and they still don't burn out is because
they are tired. They're working
endlessly, but they're working with a
purpose and they're seeing micro success
cues. And that's what I've engineered my
life to become. Like if I'm feeling
tired and I'm feeling like I want to
quit, which by the way happens a lot.
Like you wouldn't think that I think
this often, but like maybe once a month
I want to quit all my businesses. I'm
like, I'm done. Done. I'm like, either
I've heard this. Yes. She's right. I'm
like, can I sell it? Can I go away? I
just want to go to sleep. This is not
for me. I just feel like I'm shadow
banned and something. Like, oh my god,
Yasmine, the algorithm hates me. He's
like, no, shut up. And I'm like, yes.
And then I'm like, how can I engineer a
micro win for myself so I can keep
going? And that's how I've dealt with
it. Otherwise, when I burn out, I'm
like, I'm tired. I just need a rest. I
just need a day off. And that's it. I
have a different perspective. I agree on
everything you said. But the fact is
during the process of building, whatever
you're building, right? And no matter
how old you are \slash} how experienced
you are, there will come a time when
things get overwhelming. There will come
a time when things just don't go your
way, no matter how much planning and
strategizing you do. There will come a
time when something happens in the world
and it affects everything you do, and
you had nothing to do with it. The other
problem is you can't impact it one bit.
But the key is in how you respond to it.
There was a podcast or a hip-hop song or
something I heard like years ago, and it
literally changed how I view adversity,
how I view challenging times. The quote
was, this is what hard is supposed to
feel like. This is what hard is supposed
to feel like. It's not meant to be easy.
It's not meant to be comfy. It's not
meant to hug you. If you're building
something, it's going to get hard over
time. And things that you have to work
for, they're usually the things that are
worth having. They're usually the things
that are worth fighting for. But in that
process, that's where burnout kicks in.
You know you have to fight for it. You
know you have to keep building, but you
get tired. It gets hard. It gets
overwhelming. Just keep repeating to
yourself. I swear it's like a mental
exercise. Literally, just close your
eyes and repeat to yourself, this is
what hard is supposed to feel like. This
is what it's supposed to feel like. Once
you accept that, it's like, okay, bro.
Good. Like genuinely, it's like, okay,
this is it. I'm literally on the way. I
feel like burnout and this feeling of
overwhelm convinces us that we're doing
something wrong. Like nothing is
working. I'm failing. I'm supposed to
quit, right? But once you tell yourself,
I'm exactly where I need to be. This is
part of the process. This is what it's
supposed to feel like. Things get
easier. Maybe it's just me, right? But I
love rewiring my brain and convincing
myself that everything's going to be
okay. Think of a diagram, right?
Something happens. Can you impact it? On
one end you have, yes. Why worry? On the
other end is, no. I can't impact it. So
my question is, why worry? Right? And
then like with all overwhelm, it's like,
can you impact it? Yes, you can. Because
that is exactly how it's supposed to
feel like and how you respond to it.
Whether you quit, whether you lie down,
whether you just drown in your sorrow
and cry for days, or whether you just
continue going and say, yeah, this is
literally what it's supposed to feel
like. This is the part of the process
that I'm supposed to go through because
it could literally just be 24 hours and
things are perfect again. So I feel like
we talk about burnout as if it's this
mythical creature that attacks us and we
have no cure for it. There's no weapons
against it. Hell no. It's really just a
tiny little signal you need to send to
your brain and say, I'm exactly where I
need to be. It's just part of the
process. I have to go through it and
that's it. Ultimately, it's like going
to school. We all hate exams. Everyone
hates exams. On the morning of the exam,
you hate going to school. You fear
something. But you know at the end of
the day, those couple or several years
of school and university, they're going
to pass or you're still going to
graduate. And you're not going to
remember all of those times because at
the end of the day, the outcome matters
more than the journey. Take a week off.
Yeah, but it also has a lot to do with
what Laura said about, you know,
engineering your life. Again, this is a
deep conversation, a long answer to a
very simple question, at least in my
mind. I take three-day weekends now in
my life. I didn't always do this, right?
There used to be a time in my life when
I worked 17-hour shifts daily, 7 days a
week. Was it hard? Hell yeah. Did I need
to do it? Hell yeah. Do I need to do it
now? No. But it took that to get to this
to now have four-day workweeks. And
heck, this week, because you guys are
here, because we're having a meet up
here in Bosnia in my home, worked 2
days. I'm now at a place where I have
this blessing, right? And luxury to just
wake up in the morning and say, I'm not
going to work today. But again, until
you get to that point, that little
feeling of, oh, burnout is coming, it's
going to be there. Just accept it. Tell
yourself this is exactly what it's
supposed to feel like and just go, push
through it. You'd be surprised how
powerful our minds are when we convince
ourselves that we can go through
anything. I want to add a little bit to
that.
There's this really good book that I
recently read. It's called What Doesn't
Kill Us. It's based on Wim Hof. Do you
guys know him? Yeah, cold plunge guy. A
guy, very cynical researcher, went to
see what the fuss was about around Wim
Hof and how apparently doing cold
plunges could really change your
neurobiology in your brain. And what he
discovered after being so cynical about
this guy that apparently could beat a
bacteria just by breathing. He came to
the conclusion, one of many, that we as
humans have evolved with technology to
the point where we have avoided doing
hard things and we have become resistant
to the hard things because we've been
enabled to the easy thing. When you as a
person, especially as an entrepreneur,
that truly wants to be successful, you
expose yourself to hardship on purpose.
You learn how to thrive in it and enjoy
it. It gives you this upper hand amongst
99% of people because most people avoid
the hard things because we have enabled
ourselves to avoid it. We have Google
Maps. We have Uber Eats. We have the
internet. We have ChatGPT that can
answer anything without us doing the
hard research, the hard work, the hard
client conversations. We now have AI.
When you're facing hardship, when you
are about to burn out, when you are
getting so many knows that it hurts so
much that you feel like you're not doing
anything wrong. And you stick to it and
you see the light at the end of the
tunnel. Maybe 1 week after, maybe 1
month after, maybe a whole year after.
You'll be so proud that you went through
all of that hardship because a lot of
people didn't and now you know what hard
really feels like and you enjoy the
success more. But you also understand
how to deal with it again. It's not as
hard. And then you do the hard thing
many, many times and you become really
good at it. That's what happened to me
when I started the business. And dealing
with businesses like building a B2B
SaaS, I had no idea. But now I do. But
it was really hard and I wanted to quit
so many times. So we almost pulled Cleo
out because it was so hard. We had
lawyers talking to us. We had so many
legal battles. We have competitors. We
had people that like were fighting
against us. I at some point didn't
believe in the product. It was so hard.
But I am so proud that I pulled through.
And it was hard, but now I can tell the
story. And that also makes you a more
interesting person to listen to because
no one roots for the person that is
winning. They always root for the person
that is an underdog. And when you are an
underdog and you give yourself the
stories to tell, you become a more
interesting person to listen to and
follow. So it's a great personal
branding piece of advice, too. Go
through hardships because you never know
when there'll be a good story to tell in
a few years. This turned motivational
real quick. I love it. I love being
motivational to people. It's a blessing.
More questions?
Hi, I'm Pooja. I'm from India. Laura,
good to meet you. I am always, always
fun to meet you, Jay. So and of course
to Leka. Thank you everybody. I love
being here. My question to you is, my
core offer is ghostwriting, right? And
end-to-end LinkedIn management. So in a
way to say there are so many LinkedIn
strategies, experts, whatever you call
yourselves. So in a sea of sameness to
stand out, you spoke about a
differentiating factor yesterday. What
are the questions you ask yourself to
stand out in this sea of sameness where
everybody seems to be offering the same
at varied prices. How do you do that? Is
part one. And part two is, when I have
scaled up to a level that I've reached,
but I'm just stuck here. It's like I
can't move and I don't know why and what
to do next. So how do I go ahead? I see
you on LinkedIn a lot and I was telling
Jay about this. Like Pooja, you're so
different in person. And like I would
love to see more of that because that is
your unfair advantage. How charismatic
and almost like immediately bubbly you
are. I feel like that is something that
you should talk about more on your
LinkedIn and like make it more obvious.
So how can you make real life Pooja into
LinkedIn? Link Linkify her. And I think
a lot of it comes from your actual
stories, like the things that you
shared. That is what I would pay a
ghostwriter a premium for. The way that
you manage things, the way that you
communicate, the way that you are. And
the best way to do that on LinkedIn is
to one, story tell. Two, educate on the
things that your ideal clients don't
really understand. So like I, you're a
mom. You manage your time incredibly
well. You're also ghostwriting for
people. You get like, if I was to see
your process on how do you ghostwrite
for a client versus the other 10 other
processes that I see, oh, use Claude and
then put the 10 top viral posts and then
ghostwrite 10 viral hooks. I want to see
what Pooja does. Like how do you do
that? A client would be so much more
interested in that process versus the
typical AI funnel process that
everybody's following. So I would do
that to differentiate yourself. Like
more stories of you. And also your
individual process. Cuz I don't think I
have seen that yet. So I should focus
more on what I do in terms of how I
write. Yeah. Well, ask me. I'm a
ghostwriter that also built an agency.
The thing that always got me the biggest
fish was literally just sharing my
process. Cuz the clients that I landed
by sharing the carousels weren't the
ones that were interested in how to go
viral. They just wanted to see the
behind the scenes to see that I was able
to do it for them. They weren't going to
copy it cuz they didn't have time. They
wanted to make sure that my process
aligned with theirs. So. So that would
help me go from where I'm stuck to
wherever I need to reach. Yeah, that's
what helped me. I don't know where
you're stuck. Like I said, like price?
Yeah, in the sense I'm stuck at the
price point. I'm not being able to go
higher or I'm not attracting the right
kind of clients. Honestly, I'm not sure.
I mean, I do use storytelling. We do
have challenges that, you know, Jay
started in the community and that's kept
me more focused. I reach out to prospect
every single day. Sometimes even twice a
day. But it's a guide at the back of
your head, but now it's become a habit.
And because it's a habit, it's helping
me get a lot of queries. But for some
reason, I just feel I'm fitting into
this sea of sameness. I'm not being able
to find why me over a Lorraine or
>> Let me give you an answer. Yeah, go. Hi
Pooja. Again, I love meeting Pooja in
person. She's amazing. I will give you
two bits of advice. And this goes for
you as much as it goes for everyone in
this room and everyone watching this as
well. Do things you're proud of. We
don't do that enough. I have to say
this. We don't do things that we're
proud of enough. We do things we think
will work. And everyone can relate to
this. We do things that we think will
work. We're stuck over analyzing the
hooks, the strategies, this and that.
And we write that kind of content
because we're like, we're almost
counting on it giving us more leverage,
more visibility, more this and that.
This is why like when people ask me
like, why are you so positive in your
content? It's because I love what I
write. I love every single piece of
content that I put out. There's not a
single post that I haven't loved
personally that I've put out. I will
write five pieces of content. I will
just publish one because I really feel
like this. And I didn't do it for the
algorithm. I didn't do it because I felt
like, oh, everyone's going to love this.
No, I did it because I truly believe in
it. And because I'm proud of that. And I
know for a fact because I've coached
hundreds of people in person. I coached
thousands of you in the community. You
still struggle with this. Because you're
doing things to be good to the
algorithm. You're not doing things to be
good to yourself. That is number one.
Now, number two. What makes an expert?
What makes an expert? Opinions. Not
information. This is crucial. So in your
case, the way you position the problem
right now is, I don't want to stay stuck
attracting the wrong kind of audience
with the same type of price expectation.
The way you said it is like you feel
some certain way about it. What's your
opinion about it? Why don't you want to
share that price? Why do you want to
share a higher price? Why? Can you
verbalize that? Because I just feel for
the time, effort, and energy I put into
it, I deserve more. So you're saying
because you put time, energy, and effort
into it, because it's really quality
output that you know is going to work
and bring in results for them, that's
why it costs a little bit more.
>> Yeah. Why don't you ever say that in
your content? Literally like that, using
those exact words, word for word.
Verbatim. Because it feels wrong. No.
Exactly. And that is exactly what is
right. Here's [snorts] where we are now.
You see, we're trying to be likable by
everyone. It feels wrong. Why does it
feel wrong? Because we're going to repel
certain people. Not all people, certain
people. But what is your problem? You
just explained it. You're attracting the
wrong people. Meaning the solution is
you have to repel them. You have to
repel that kind of audience. You see?
You're doing the wrong thing by not
attacking the problem in your content.
You're not saying what you should be
saying to attract the right audience.
You're playing the safe thing thinking
you're going to repel a certain bit of
your audience, but that certain of your
audience is exactly the certain bit of
your audience that you should be
repelling. This is what we call
polarizing content. This is what we
literally have experts for. Why are you
here today listening to me, traveling to
meet me in person out of all the other
places you could have been in the world?
Why are you here to meet Laura in person
as well out of all the other experts you
could have met in the world? Why?
Because there's certain things about us
that are attractive to you in terms of
expertise. And let me tell you what that
is, it's opinions. It's not just the
frameworks, it's not just the solutions,
it's our opinions and how we approach
our businesses. That is what makes an
expert. Everyone can share a tip.
Everyone can share advice. Who's the
person behind it? Why do you feel about
this piece of advice this certain way?
Why? Whenever you're sharing your
content, this is like evergreen piece of
advice. Wherever you're sharing content,
no matter where it is, what platform it
is, if you give me a piece of advice,
tell me why I should care. Tell me why
you feel so strongly about this advice.
If you tell me, "Your hook should always
be a one-liner on LinkedIn." Why? Cuz if
you just tell me, "Your hook should be a
one-liner on LinkedIn." Every single
person in this room can repeat that same
piece of advice, but why should I trust
you more than the next person? That is
your problem. You said, "Sea of
sameness." But if everyone shares an
opinion about that piece of advice,
every single bit of those posts is not
the same. You see? Because you attribute
that piece of advice with an opinion now
that gets drawn to a certain person,
certain name, certain level of
expertise. And that is what you fall in
love with with a coach, that opinion,
not the information. And a lot of
experts never share their opinions. They
just share tips and tricks. It's almost
like again, we're scared to repel
people, but that is the purpose of
branding. You want to attract the right
audience and you want to push away, not
in a negative way, by the way, because
that is branding. Why do we brand
ourselves? Why do we brand products? Why
do we package products? Why do we put
certain colors on things? Why do we put
certain fonts on things? Why? Because
you want to attract the right audience,
right? If you want to look premium,
right? If you want to charge a premium.
And if you just put red and green,
you're laughing because you know those
colors don't go together, right? Can you
charge $10,000 for it? Hell no. But if
you put a black background with a gold
sheen font, ooh, you see? Now you're
branding for the right reason. Because
by default, branding means you're
attracting a certain bit of audience,
you're repelling a certain bit of
audience, but what you're saying is
you've never ever once came out there
with your actual words in your content
to repel that type of audience. What you
said today, word for word, when I asked
you, repeat that in a post. Please, I
dare you. I challenge you to write that
post. Send it to me inside our Link Up
community. I will review it personally
and I will tell you, post it this way.
Let me tell you, I know that post is
going to bring you clients. I know it
for a fact. Before we wrap up with this
question cuz I think I relate to you in
many, many ways. I've been through the
exact same phase where I had to battle
with the personal branding overwhelm of
personal brands on LinkedIn. And I was
like, I know I can do something
differently. So, I created this
bulletproof method for our clients that
has been proven to work by people who
were in your exact same position, were
in the same niche, and couldn't get
ahead. I call it the PCC framework,
positioning, content, and conversion.
Yasmine covered the part. So, how do you
stand out in a sea of sameness? You
position yourself as a leader, you give
your polarizing opinions, and you show
your work. That's very important. So,
think about that. How many times a week
can I do a polarizing opinion about
something that no one in the industry is
talking about, but I do? Another one is,
what do your type of client want to
actually read on LinkedIn? Because your
type of client may not want to read
another hook post. They want to know
what's trending for their niche on
LinkedIn right now, and they want you to
know, they want to see that you know
exactly how their market is moving. So,
if Who's your ICP? The C-suites. So, in
the C-suite world, what matters to them?
You know, operating at a high level, how
they can get better hires, how can they
hire A-players, how building up a
personal brand on LinkedIn can attract
them better hires, faster, without them
having to go through endless, endless
hours of hiring recruiters, right? That
is also polarizing. You don't have to
consistently be like, "I hate
everything. This is why I should be
charging more." It can also be a
polarizing opinion on their industry
because that's going to get them reading
you, right? The second part for me is
obviously the content. So, like with
your split So, like educational content,
storytelling content, and then
polarizing content, and then sales sales
content. So, in reality, how many times
have you directly said to your audience,
"I am selling something" over the last
month? Never. This is where the problem
starts. If you don't promote yourself,
no one is going to do it for you, and
that is the harsh truth that no one
wants to accept. No one is going to
promote you better than you promote
yourself. And we've been sold a lie
across social media on LinkedIn that if
you create good content, it will sell.
That is partially true, but it doesn't
work for everyone. Like, you still need
to create content that makes people
aware that you're selling something. You
cannot be hiding under your storytelling
post and expecting a lead to come
through. It is essential for you to
promote yourself loudly. And you can do
what I do, you can do it in sprints. So,
I also get the ick. I feel cringey when
I sell. But guess what happens when I
sell? I make thousands of dollars.
Shocking. But what Guess what happens
when I don't sell anything? I make zero,
right? And this is a harsh truth that I
had to learn. I need to tell people that
I'm selling something, otherwise they're
going to forget. Otherwise, they're
going to go to a competitor that is
open. Otherwise, they're going to DM the
person that is loudly saying, "Hey, I
have this program, I have this service,
and it's ready for you to buy." So, I
think that you probably have done enough
storytelling content, educational
content for us to not give you advice on
that. But what I think you need to focus
on is, how can you write conversion-led
content once a week, right? How can you
desensitize yourself from feeling
cringey and making it part of your
routine, right? That can start from a
lead magnet, basic, you know, simple
lead magnet. You're providing free
value, you're literally doing someone a
favor, and then they're giving you their
email. Then you can market to them on
email. You can do what Yasmine does
incredibly well, is lives, where you can
get to show your amazing, charismatic,
you know, personality, and then people
will convert. Yasmine and I had this
moment 3 years ago when we started doing
LinkedIn lives together. We literally
didn't sell throughout the entire
webinar. Yasmine and I, for one of my
offers, we made $80,000 in one over like
a week of three lives because we were
just showing our personality because
everyone on LinkedIn is so robotic that
none of them actually have anything
funny to say. They don't have
personality, and you do. And that is one
of your own advantages. So, positioning,
content, conversion. Puja, what was the
challenge that I gave you in the
community last week? The challenge was
include your prices inside your post.
And let me tell you, our wins channel
has never been buzzing more. Everyone is
saying, "Oh, this booked me calls. This
got me X many leads. This got me X much
money." You want to know why? Cuz you're
finally telling people what you charge,
what your service is, and it doesn't
feel like selling. You're just literally
saying it. That's I feel like something
that we need to rewire in our brains. We
feel like saying something about our
business ultimately means like cringey
selling, and it's not the case. Just say
it. It's okay. We got more questions
from the audience. Yes, please. Hi, my
name is George. I'm from Serbia, and
since I'm only 19, I'm in the beginning
of my new journey. And what did you wish
that you knew if you were my age and
your beginning of your LinkedIn career
in general? What did I wish I knew at
the very beginning? You know, this is
going to be saucy. Okay, let me tell you
this. You believing in the right things
is going to piss some people off. It
could be like the most generic thing.
It's like, "I love to talk about being
the underdog, coming from a small
country, believing in kindness and
helping people." But that's literally
who I am. I can't change who I am. That
is how I've been raised. That is what I
truly, firmly believe in with every
fiber of my body. But every single time
I've written a post about kindness, it
pisses so many people off. You can
laugh, but it's it's a fact, and you
know this. Like, there's some people who
wouldn't have content ideas, they
wouldn't have anything to write about if
it wasn't for them to write about me.
You know this for a fact. But it's
usually they're writing about me writing
about kindness. And it's like they're
making fun of the fact that I write
about kindness, and I'm like, "What the
hell kind of business model is that?" My
point is, no matter what you put out
there in the world, what I wish I knew
sooner is that no matter what it is,
people are going to have a problem with
it. Like, literally the most generic
thoughts that you have, the most boring,
normal thoughts, people are still going
to find something wrong with it. And
when that happens, and it will happen,
it will happen, best believe it will
happen. When it happens, just let it
run. It's them, it's not you. I wish I
learned this sooner. It used to bother
me at the very beginning. I'll be very
honest. It used to bother me. I used to
read every single comment. I was looking
for comments where people were
disagreeing just because I feel like,
okay, what can I still fix? Like, I was
still looking at it from a like, how can
I get better standpoint? But at a
certain point I understood it's like, I
can't get better for these people. It's
like, I can never get better because
they just have a problem with the way I
think. It's not even what I said, right?
It's just it's you who's the problem.
Accept it, move on. There's a beautiful
button on social media. I believe every
platform has it. It's called the block
button. The second you learn how to use
the block button, it's your your life is
going to be much easier. I'm I'm telling
you this because you have to get
yourself prepared. I can't tell you how
many, how many conversations I've had
about this exact very thing. And my
community knows this cuz every now and
then we get a screenshot from someone
saying, "I just got my first hater." You
guys know this, right? Like, in the
community this happens a lot. I just got
my first hater. Like, how do I approach
this? What do I do? Block and buy. Block
and buy. That's it. So, I'm telling you
this in advance. Take it as friendly,
brotherly advice. There is a lot of
power in proximity. When you associate
yourself with the right people, you
actually gain what I call speed velocity
on LinkedIn, on any life. So, when you
are here in front of 50 people, and me
and Yasmine included, where we have
leverage, when you immediately associate
yourself with something that has an
ideal audience or already has had an
ideal ideal outcome, you can leverage
that to get to the next level faster.
So, find proximity as fast as you can.
Leverage your network, leverage your
connections. I use this concept that I
call the halo effect, where when you are
next to someone, they immediately
associate the good things about them to
you. So, how can you use that faster
weekly in your content to get ahead?
View LinkedIn not just as a social media
platform, but also as just The moment
gamified LinkedIn to just think this is
a game I need to detach from it. I sped
up and I went from 10,000 followers to
100,000 followers in record time because
I detached. I saw it as the game as it
was and I leveraged every single card
that I had on my deck. The card was
broke student. The card was meeting
Yasmin Alik. The card was traveling at
15 and moving away from my hometown.
Every single one of those moments is an
ace card that I could leverage on
LinkedIn and that was like my winning
ace card to win the game. So, think
about that when you write, when you
think about your strategy and just
simply try to detach as much as you can
because it's not real. The people
commenting and hating, they're not real.
But the people that love you are. That
is beautiful advice. Thank you, Laura.
Okay, next up. Hi guys, I'm San from
Munich, Germany and I had a question to
you, Laura, but especially I also would
love to hear your She likes me more. She
traveled 11 hours for me. And for me.
So, I'm running a business for 2 years
now, but especially these past few
months it has been really life-changing
business-wise, which means more
responsibility but less time for my
surroundings and my friends and they
don't really get it. My question to you
is how do you deal with that? I don't go
to holidays. I just work almost 24/7.
That's how it feels like. So, have you
ever experienced Oh yeah, but I had to
make a choice how badly do I want the
thing that I'm pursuing and that
included me having monk mode activated,
which meant that I didn't see my family
for 2 years. I didn't see friends for 2
years. I didn't make new friends for 2
years. But then it enabled me to make
more time to meet people like Yasmin and
then people that were aligned within my
same purpose and they didn't care if I
didn't text them on a Sunday afternoon
to go to the pub or go to a bar because
they knew that I was pursuing the same
thing cuz they also were pursuing the
same thing. When I started I was in
Mexico, there was like no one that
understanding me like you right now. And
then what I did was like I made the
biggest effort to create a community
before I left Mexico. So, when I moved
away to a country where I knew there
were more people in my surroundings that
had a similar vision, I could literally
just hop in. So, the first thing that I
did when I moved to London was go to a
similar pre-little thing event where I
met 10 people that became such assets to
me feeling like I wasn't alone anymore.
But I think the lonely chapter in any
entrepreneur's journey is so powerful
because you learn how to be by yourself.
You learn how to love what you do and
you learn your craft faster because
you're dedicating yourself to it. For
the first few years of my business on
year four, that's crazy. The time that I
spent refining my skill became my own
fair advantage because all of these
people were like getting distracted with
family, friends, holidays, etc. and I
was just focused on the one thing and
now it enables me to be able to come
here on a weekend while I'm like super
busy but I still can make the time. So,
again, it's not meant to be easy and it
can get lonely and it is but that
loneliness also becomes an advantage for
you because when you learn how to be
alone in your own thoughts, no one can
beat you. You become dangerously
independent to the point where you know
how to be alone so you don't need anyone
else. But then when the right people
come along, you feel full and not empty.
So, yeah. I have the most beautiful
piece of advice for you but you haven't
asked me the question.
Let me tell you something that I would
tell every business owner who's
currently building. You can't reach new
heights constantly staring from the
bottom. You're looking up, you want to
reach there but you're constantly at the
bottom. You want to stay in your current
environment with your current friends
hoping they understand you. They don't.
They're not on the same journey with
you. You can still keep them in your
life. They're part of the mountain but
you're at a different level now and I
feel like this is something we don't
talk about enough in business. They
always say like it feels lonely at the
top. I disagree with that entirely. It's
actually very very nice at the top when
you're networking with like-minded
people. It's like it's beautiful. It's
lovely. The climb is the lonely part
because you have to understand in order
for you to grow out of one environment,
you have to grow in to a new
environment. But that process of growing
is in the middle and you're currently
right there and you're kind of feeling
pushed back is like my friends don't
understand me. I can't explain it to
them even if I wanted to. Let me just
tell you that's normal. Just picture
yourself you're climbing in the middle
of a mountain knowing where you're
going. Don't look back. You think hikers
when they start hiking they're like
midway they're like oh yeah, no, right?
They go to the top. But at the top you
meet wonderful people. So, let me just
tell you that. Once you're looking at
new heights, you can't keep looking at
the bottom. And once you reach the top
of the mountain, you can't even hear
what's going on at the bottom. Remember
that. One last thing, I I relate so
much. I had this lonely chapter and I
felt so bad cuz I was stuck in London by
myself at Uni at Exeter actually and I
didn't leave my house and at times I
felt very very lonely and I didn't have
anyone to reach out to. I had actually
well, you were there. I broken up with
my boyfriend and it was like the
loneliest period of my life cuz no one
in my proximity got anything and I had
this grade I don't know if I got it from
my supervisor at university where I was
like so depressed and I went to her and
I was crying cuz of this breakup and I
felt lonely and this business stuff and
I had Uni and it was so complicated. And
she looked at me she was like, "But you
have 50,000 followers. Why do you feel
lonely?" And that broke me cuz I was
like, "How is it possible that I have
such a big audience but I cannot share
this feeling that is so private and
personal to me?" And luckily for me I
had people like Yasmin and also Luke
Matthews in my life who were able to
bring me out of like that. Are you
talking about the 1:00 a.m. call? Oh
yes, many many of them. Many of them,
yeah.
>> And there was like one specific call
where I called We weren't that close
friends but I didn't have anyone to
call. I literally didn't have anyone
that understood that specific situation
where I was like a business owner and
also like a girl trying to like, you
know, build my personal life and
experience that heartbreak for the
second time ever. And I called Yasmin
and I was like, "Hey, like I'm sorry I
don't have anyone to call but like can
you just listen to me for like a bit?"
And he did. But can I tell you the back
context that you've never heard of that
story?
>> No, what? My son was sleeping on me on
my chest and it was 1:00 a.m. I was
awake. I was literally just commenting
on LinkedIn. Of course. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> You know, my phone is vibrating. It's
like 1:00 a.m. and I pick up. I'm like,
"What's up?"
>> Yes. And she's crying her eyes out. I
can hear it. She's like, "I just got to
talk." And it's like those moments on
the journey where it's like
unconditional support for others.
Whether they stay with you or not by the
way cuz some people are just going to be
there for the moment. They're going to
leave. That's fine. That's normal.
That's part of the journey. But I feel
like those moments are what makes the
journey worth it. And it's like right
now you feel like it's almost like one
part of your life is being torn out.
It's almost like you're ripping the page
out of a notebook, right? But if you're
ripping it out, it wasn't supposed to be
there anyhow. It's just going to go to
the trash bin. The best piece of advice
I can give you is to find three people
that are on LinkedIn ideally. That's
your world or like at least in the
business world that are in the journey
and that are willing to give you their
time because you've been useful to them
in some way. Maybe in a friendship way
or like maybe in a networking way.
Yasmin and I were just like LinkedIn
buddies. We're just like supporting each
other but then we scaled that by having
that 1:00 a.m. call and then many other
connections like that. So, find two
people or three and then your journey
will become easier. So, we got more
questions? Yes, please. I believe that
one of the hardest things about personal
brand is that it's easy and it's simple
in theory. Communication, patience,
consistency, all that kind of stuff. But
in actuality, so many of us are coming
to the game with a lack of self-trust.
So, my question to you is one, do you
agree with me that that is one of the
hardest things? And two, what has your
journey to self-trust been? Because
obviously you have gotten over this hump
that many people struggle with. I can
give you a scientific answer because a
good friend of mine, Shadi Zarei, one of
the biggest, you know, researchers,
neuroscientist in the world, she just
published a book called The Big Trust.
And we also have a LinkedIn course
together, LinkedIn learning course. In
her book she explains the difference
between self-confidence and self-trust.
Confidence basically comes from
delusion. This is my understanding. I'll
just keep it short. Trust comes from
action cuz like once you know it works
or was it the other way around? Sorry,
Shadi. If I'm not explaining this
correctly. It's like once you confirm
that it works, then you can trust that
it will work one more time. Until then
it's just like, "Hey, I'm confident."
So, I feel like it's inside the journey
like the answer to your question. It's
on the journey. You can't just be
confident. It's like you grow into it.
And at the very beginning like a lot of
us were talking to each other before a
post goes live. Here's the hook I have
for the post. What do you think about
it? That sucks. No, this was literally
the conversation, you know, you have
that. So, if you can find a supportive
group of friends like similar to the
previous answer like people who can
genuinely like push you to do better and
accept that during the journey some
parts are going to suck. It is what it
is. That's where confidence kicks in.
It's just like unless you know what
doesn't work, you can't count on things
working all the time. Okay, we're we're
going to take a couple more questions
and then we're going to wrap it up. KJ.
Okay, Laura. You wake up tomorrow.
You've lost everything. Money, family,
friends, even yourself.
You aren't allowed to go back into the
same business, SaaS, AI writing,
whatever and you have to start over. You
can't use the same skills. You can't use
the same resources you'd have. Give me
three things you would do immediately to
go get yourself back up to where you are
right now. That's all you.
Three things.
Let me Let me do the funny thing. I'm
telling you this because I was here 5
years ago. So, I'm just I just want to
know. Let me do the funny thing. Sorry,
what was the question?
>> [snorts]
>> You've lost everything. You have to
start over. Three things.
But you can't do the same thing you've
done. And I can't use my skills. I can't
use any of them.
>> use anything. No.
Your LinkedIn nothing. All right.
Um I wouldn't do three things. I would
do one. I would go to my dad.
That is That is a flex.
And I would ask him
what to do [snorts] and I think he never
has given me a wrong answer. So, he
believes in me more than
anyone.
Shout out Rego.
So, I would go to him.
Just one. I love that. Thank you.
Thank you, KJ. Any more questions before
we wrap up? We can take one more. There
we go. Hi, I'm Lena here from Germany.
How you frame it so yeah, I'm wearing a
Fulton t-shirt on me today. So, my
question is I work in B2B. I'm very
happy with B2B but because I'm blessed
to know four different languages and I
see a lack of good specialists on the
Russian market on LinkedIn. I kind of
feel that this is also one of my blue
oceans where I can go and at the what
stage of my business
>> Can I just ask you a counter question?
Do you have the capacity right now to
travel to all those places? Get an
agent. It's almost like booking speaking
gigs. Like it's the easiest thing in the
world. Get a speaking agent, let them
book the gigs for you and negotiate the
gigs for you. They're not going to be
paid by salary, they're just going to be
paid by commission. So for all of those
countries, get a speaking agent that can
literally negotiate the deals for you.
You're just going to lose like one chunk
of the money, pay them for their
involvement and for their effort here,
and you just go travel and expand your
blue ocean. Literally, just get a
speaking agent. I'm dead serious. Thank
you. And if we speak about the
positioning on LinkedIn That's the
beautiful part cuz it's like it's still
the same workshops, it's just different
markets. Correct?
>> Yeah, but the Russian speaking tend to
be connecting to the Russian speaking
content and I don't want to do that.
No, but if you go there, are you going
to give the workshop in a Russian or is
still going to be your usual? You will?
That's fine then. It's like I travel, I
speak several languages, you know this
as well. Like when I go and do my
keynotes, I sometimes don't do it in
English. Is my content not in English?
Oh, everything I do is still in English.
So keep your brand intact, but it's like
when you're going into new markets, just
adapt and during that keynote, during
that workshop, during that training.
That's it. There's nothing about your
positioning that you need to change.
Literally. Again, just get a speaking
agent. They're going to negotiate the
deals for you. So when they ask you
like, are you going to be doing it in
Russian or English? Russian. That's it.
We got one more. Be quick, be quick.
Flavia, come on. When you guys realized
at the early stages that you actually
didn't want to quit, but nothing was
working. I'm asking this because after
almost 12 months, nothing is working and
I do feel like I want to quit, but at
the same time I don't want to wait. So
I'm asking, do you actually
had an epiphany? How do you actually
keep going even though nothing was
working? Going to be honest, I don't
think I I was ever at that point. I
can't answer that question. That was
like That was the most useless answer
ever. I was genuinely never at that
point because I was always outworking
everyone. It's like I wasn't counting on
things to happen. Do you know how much
it takes to be online for eight hours
per day every day and leave thousands of
comments, send hundreds [snorts] of
messages, talk to people, talk to
people, talk to people, talk to people,
talk to people. I'm saying it five times
because I want you to hear how annoying
it is. It's an annoying process. It's a
repetitive process. It's a tiring
process. It took four months for me to
land my first gig through LinkedIn. But
I wasn't going easy those four months.
Like I was literally going harder and
harder and harder starting day one all
the way to month four. The trajectory
was going up. It wasn't like I started
hard at day one and then like towards
month four I kind of fell out because
like nothing was working. Hell no. I
just kept going, kept going, kept going.
So my question to you is, be honest with
yourself. Are you amping up the stakes
or are you kind of losing out on the
motivation after such a long period?
>> No, I'm not losing motivation.
>> But are you also amping up the stakes?
Are you? We had this conversation, so be
honest. I know the answer, you know? The
key, it's like when you're doing things
that don't work, there's usually one of
two problems. It's number one, you're
not reaching enough of an audience,
meaning your positioning is good. You're
not doing it enough because you haven't
been in the right places enough times,
meaning in front of a large number of
people. Or the other part is true,
meaning your positioning is completely
off and you're completely attracting the
wrong audience. It's one of the two. But
you need to outwork yourself and then
outwork everyone else to figure that
out. I can't tell you what that is right
now just based on one question. But one
of those two things needs to happen. You
either need to outwork yourself because
you're currently not doing enough, or
you need to outwork everyone else
because apparently everyone else in your
field is attracting clients and you
can't. It's a hard truth, but you have
to outwork people. Sometimes it takes
time, sometimes it takes guts, sometimes
it just, you know, not sleeping. That's
the reality of the journey, but until
you get that first client, that first
client will give you all the answers cuz
then you can be like, what did I do to
land this client? And then repeat the
process over and over and over again cuz
I guarantee you there is something about
that one result that is crucial and that
is different. Until that happens, I
can't know the answer, you can't know
the answer. Like what needs to happen?
But one of those two things, you either
outwork yourself right now because you
believe your positioning is correct, or
it's completely off and then you got to
outwork everyone else because their
positioning is good. One of those two
things needs to happen. What that is,
I'm going to just give you a challenge.
You got 24 hours to decide which way
you're going to go. Oh my god. No, pick
one. Pick one, Layne. And generally just
go all in cuz it's like have you ever
been in a situation, like a genuine
situation? I've been in these situations
like where money is running tight. Like
you literally see the last bit of your
savings. It's like you know if two more
weeks pass, I will literally have
nothing to eat. If you've ever been in
this situation, you stop asking
questions. You stop questioning
everything. You just do the work, do the
work, do the work. There's no question
because you got to figure it out. Are
you at that point or do you still feel
like I'm still not at that point where
I'm so hungry? No, I'm at the point. All
right. Go all in. As someone that has
been in desperate situations where I've
wanted to quit multiple times over the
last three years, especially over the
last year where I felt like I couldn't
see the lights or the next big win. I
think about the concept of engineering
my own luck quite a lot and I talk about
it often. Now, for you, in your very
niche niche on LinkedIn, there are two
things that I would do if I was
incredibly desperate to win. And one of
them would be, how can I use my current
skill set to touch on a larger TAM,
which is our total addressable market?
Right now your total addressable market
is quite small, right? You are in the
female space with What is it? Egg
freezing, right? So now, let's say that
that's not working, but you are
specialized in that industry. However,
over time you've gained all the skills
while trying to build that offer, which
is writing, which is marketing, which is
psychology, which is course, any other
other skills that can stack on top of
your current offer, right? So then I
could have been at the very start like,
I really like social media marketing. I
want to be a social media marketing
consultant, right? That didn't work
because I was competing with Steven
Bartlett's agency. I was competing with
Amelia Sordell's clout. I was competing
with all of these people that already
had millions and millions and millions
of dollars, had been published in Forbes
Forbes on the 30 and the 30, 40 500. So
what did I do instead? I was like, I
know this skill, I know what I know, and
I know this other new thing that I can
implement into my offer. What was that?
Ghost writing. What was that?
Positioning. What was that? LinkedIn
algorithm stuff. What was that? Anything
else that I picked up along the way
while trying to figure out how to sell
that current offer that failed, I then
stacked it up onto my current offer. So
for you it would be like, okay, I have
this expertise, but how can I then turn
into a larger TAM? So either you can
start your own agency for now, which is
a lot more lucrative than what you have
right now, which then you can use to
then leverage to then start that
business again when you have time. Cleo,
for example, Cleo started four years
ago. We only marketed this year. Why?
Because we didn't have the resources and
anything to position it properly so it
could win. So what we did is we put in
hold while we built other businesses
that allowed us to have that volume in
money so we can reinvest into the
business. So for you it would be like,
okay, this offer is currently failing.
How can I make it a winner? How can I
use another thing, incorporate another
element, maybe a done-for-you for female
hormone specialist, for like marketers
in the female space that want to
understand how to do LinkedIn. I'm not
saying start a LinkedIn agency, but
something like that that you can do with
a current new skill that you have that
has a lot more leverage for you. Because
if I had to start from zero and I had to
make $10,000 by next month, I would do
the simplest thing that would create the
simplest outcome, which is a
service-based thing that can produce an
immediate outcome for a client, which is
a viral post, which is a new client lead
from LinkedIn. Anything that I know I
can do that I've already proven to
myself that I can do, I will do it and
then focus on my next offer when I then
have the time and I don't I'm not
stressed about money. That's what I
would do. Do we wrap up? Here we go.
>> Yes. I feel like this was nice. It's
nice talking to people in person, man.
We write online a lot. A lot of our
thoughts are just online, but when you
meet people in person, it's a different
kind of energy. So personally for me,
thank you all for coming. Thank you for
being here. Not just for the meetup, for
the linkup community, but just here
today as well for making this content
with us cuz you're part of the content,
you're part of the story. And other than
that, I just want to say good luck to
everyone cuz I feel like everyone here,
even though we're together in the same
room, everyone is still on their own
journey. So good luck to you guys and
thank you. Well done, guys. We just
wrapped up our podcast. Bye. Well,
that's it from Yasmin and I. Hopefully
next time we meet is in London live in
front of our 100 people. See you,
London. Thanks for watching. Stay tuned
for the next one. Bye.