In the next 10 minutes, I'm going to
break down the exact five LinkedIn tips
you need to use to stand out on LinkedIn
this year. So, after looking at
thousands of LinkedIn profiles every
single month, I realized that there are
five key elements that make a LinkedIn
profile stand out. So, if you're
curious, then keep on watching this
video. And this is the exact same
checklist that I use to go from 0 to
270,000 LinkedIn followers in under 3
years. The number one LinkedIn tip that
no one talks about really or at least no
one uses well is the feature section.
The feature section has made me so much
money and it's so incredibly underrated.
Here's how to use it. Most people use
feature section to pin their most viral
post that came from LinkedIn. And what
they're doing here is that they are
sacrificing such important real estate
on LinkedIn. So what I mean by this is
when someone goes into your profile,
they're going to see three things. your
headline, your banner, and then the
third thing is going to be your featured
section. You don't want to waste that
with your one viral post that you had 20
like five years ago. There's three ways
that you can use it. You can use three
different parts of the feature section
to promote your business. This is how
people are making money on LinkedIn.
It's not because of their content and
it's not because of just their headline
or the link that they just had in their
profile. It's because of the feature
section. So, here's exactly how it
works. You're going to go and create
three different thumbnails for your
three different offers. And if you don't
have three different offers, you're
going to create one for your offer, one
for your newsletter, and one for
something else. That could be a YouTube
channel, a blog, or anything else where
you can redistribute your attention so
you can actually generate leads. We're
in the business of making money, not
just getting attention. Now, you have
your thumbnails. What you're going to do
is you're going to add the link to them.
Edit your LinkedIn feature section.
Press the plus button. Add the link, add
the thumbnails, and that is literally
it. The second LinkedIn tip that I just
discovered, and I think this is about to
change the way LinkedIn works forever,
is the headline. So, right now, what
you're seeing in your LinkedIn is
everybody saying the exact same thing. I
help X to do Y. Every single person from
entrepreneurs to freelancers and
creators has this exact same headline.
Now, let me tell you why first. Well,
before LinkedIn blew up, everybody was
using this headline template because no
one was using it. But now as LinkedIn
has 1 billion users, everybody seems to
have it. So the way you change it is
simply understanding what does your
business do, who are you helping and who
are you doing it for and in what
platform or in what way. So what is the
ideal transformation that you're going
to provide to your ideal customer.
That's it. Once you have those two
keywords and the transformation, you put
it in your headline and at the end you
add social proof. No one talks about
this either. The third tip is using
social proof every single place you go
on LinkedIn from your headline to your
banner to your feature section and even
in your content. So what does social
proof look like? If you worked with one
client, 10 clients, 100 clients, you can
use that as social proof. So if I was to
write my headline and I was a personal
trainer and maybe I trained Kim
Kardashian, then I will say lose 50 lbs
in 12 weeks like Kim Kardashian did. Now
this is using social proof. You're using
the halo effect and you're directly
indicating to anyone that ever bumps
into your content of exactly what you
do, who you do it for, and how. Simple.
Now, talking about the halo effect, in
your banner, you should be using social
proof at the maximum. So, if you look at
my banner, you'll see four different
logos. They're not just random logos.
They're placed there specifically for a
reason. I've got Forbes, Kajjabi,
Giteex, and Exit University. Now, why
did I choose these logos out of all of
the logos that I could have chosen?
because I've worked with multiple
companies in different platforms and
businesses. Having the University of
Exta in my banner allows me to connect
with the student audience that I'm
trying to build because it shows that
I'm not too far ahead from them, showing
them that I just graduated. So, they can
trust me, they can like me and they can
follow me thinking I could be like her
in the future. Now having Forbes allows
me to connect with the older
demographic, the corporate people, the
people that have full-time businesses,
the people that have Fortune 500
businesses because they can trust Forbes
and therefore they can trust me. Lastly,
I have Kajjabi. So Kajjabi is very well
known in the social media space,
especially in the online business space,
which allows me to then take that
authority of online entrepreneurship
into me immediately. So if anyone sees
one of those three logos, they'll
immediately trust me. So if you have
them, use them. And if you're a beginner
and you don't have any logos, you don't
have any social proof, you don't know
what you're doing. Trust me, I've been
there. What you need to do is work with
people for free and use their
testimonial in your banner until you can
get those logos. Don't over complicate
it. I remember when I was trying to do
this and I was scared that I would never
get Forbes, I would never get Semrush, I
would never get Kajjabi or even Exit cuz
I didn't even know if I could graduate.
So what I did, I just posted my first
testimonial on my banner and then
everything happened. Now, number four,
everybody should know this, but in case
you don't, your profile photo is a
direct communicator of your positioning.
So, if you want to look professional and
attract corporate clients, then you need
to be that. You need to reinforce that
belief that these people can trust you.
We like what we are like. People buy
from what they are like. So, exactly
that. Take it into your profile. Even if
it doesn't look like you, maybe you're
not used to being on a suit, you need to
try that until you position yourself to
the point where it doesn't matter. You
know, people look at Alex Ramos all the
time and they're like, "He has the shirt
and he has the nose thing." Yes, he's
also built multi multi multi-million
dollar businesses. So, until you do
that, you need to play the game of
attention, attraction, and also
positioning. So, you position yourself
as an expert by looking like an expert.
So, please, if you still have your
profile photo from holiday in 2015 in
Spain, change it. Take a photo with your
iPhone with a white background, good
quality, good lighting, and then upload
it onto LinkedIn. Bonus points if you
change the color of the background to
green, purple, blue, whatever it is, so
it looks cleaner. Okay. Now, the fifth
one, there's this thing on LinkedIn
where you can actually add your
newsletter as a link. Now, don't do
that. The reason for this is your
newsletter link should go on your
feature section. You're missing out on
traffic when you put it as your direct
link. And this is my personal opinion
and what I've seen convert best. I'm a
pro conversion, so please trust me on
this. But you're wasting traffic if you
just put the newsletter link on your
LinkedIn profile. What you should do
instead is put it on your feature
section and the link should lead to
something else. So maybe a YouTube link
or maybe overall your landing page for
actually your business. That's best. So
these were my five rapidfire LinkedIn
tips so you can optimize your profile
fast. And if you want me to get into a
little bit more detail and give you the
other unconventional ones, you should go
to this video and watch the full 20inute
master class there where I broke down
exactly what you need to do to grow,
scale, and monetize your LinkedIn. Sila.