I got rejected from nearly every single
job I ever applied for. Spent years
getting a shiny degree, days writing CVs
and cover letters, and endless hours
scrolling and searching for jobs on
LinkedIn. And all of this for the sake
of landing a shiny entry-level $30,000
job that [music] would barely cover my
bills. But that desperation of landing
my dream role led me to the one thing
that changed everything for me in under
24 hours. And that was LinkedIn, the
platform where I spent hours applying
for [music] jobs and never hearing back
turned into the same platform that made
me my first $100,000.
That is three x of what most people make
in their first year, and I did it in
under 10 months while every single job I
ever applied for told me I was
unqualified.
The truth is that the old way of
building a career is dead. The new way
where you can actually guarantee a path
where you have stable income is building
a personal brand. This is the single
most powerful asset that you can build
today as a student, a professional, or a
business owner, and I am living proof of
it. While I was seeking for jobs a few
years ago, I decided to hit post on
LinkedIn. I was scared, I was
embarrassed, and honestly, I was afraid
because it was a desperate attempt to be
seen by recruiters or stand out in
applications. And it was only then where
I realized that I was sleeping on the
biggest opportunity most people are
completely ignoring, LinkedIn itself.
Because within my first few weeks of
actively posting on the platform, I had
serious business owners wanting to work
with me. And yes, of course, the
platform may have a reputation.
Everybody thinks it's cringe, but
business owners themselves will admit
that even though it's cringe, it has
life-changing potential if you know what
you're doing. LinkedIn as a platform
today is completely underused. Even 3
years after I made my first post, I've
realized the exact same thing. It's a
world where instead of waiting for job
offers, they come to you through your
content that you create. Traditionally
though, people use LinkedIn as a job
board. Their profile looks like this one
or like this one. No banner, old photo,
and literally no content posted in
years. The only time people log in is to
update the resume and quickly apply to
roles. And that used to be me. After
all, that's all we've really known the
platform to be for job seeking, but it's
changed a lot to give you the
opportunity you've been applying for.
See, if you really want to get ahead and
land your dream opportunities, most
people don't care about your profile.
They care about your content because
that's what gets you discovered. I soon
realized that after the few poorly
written posts that I posted had gotten
some traction. 50 likes there, 100 likes
there, and even a few viral posts made
this abundantly clear. You don't need to
be an expert or a writer or a creator.
You just need to create. The first part
about building a personal brand so you
never have to apply for a job ever again
is to simply start writing about your
current experiences and skills. Forget
about referencing, forget about being an
expert, and forget about everything
you've ever learned about content.
Because right now, if you are at a
beginner level, you just need to write
about what is happening in your life,
what you'd like to happen, and what you
can potentially educate someone on. My
first LinkedIn post was about me
introducing myself to the platform. As
cringe as it was, it worked because it
was honest. The next few posts were a
few combinations of stories, tips, and
things I was interested in alongside
documenting my journey growing my
following because I soon realized that
that was something that worked, and my
audience wanted to know how. And the
audience that I obtained over time
wanted to know how I was doing X, Y, and
Z things. There was no master strategy,
there was no ulterior motive beyond
having something to do while I was
getting rejected. I had nothing to lose
and everything to gain. And that simple
habit of forcing myself to post every
single day forced me to post, but also
forced others to notice me. Quick, I
literally engineered my own luck by
putting myself in places I literally did
not belong. Talking about things that to
most people I had no qualifications to
talk on about, but I did it anyway.
Weeks later and a few viral posts under
my belt, I'd built an audience of people
who wanted to follow me and people who
wanted to work with me. I built an
audience before I ever built a business.
All of this content creation turned me
into a freelancer. I mean, I had to.
Business owners were literally asking me
for different things, and I knew that
the opportunity was right there. I just
didn't know what it was. The reality
here is that even when you don't think
you need a personal brand, you will need
it at some point, and the best way to
build one is to do it before you need
it. Otherwise, you fall into this trap
where you only post content when you
need to, and it becomes salesy, pushy,
and it doesn't work. So, for the first
30 to 90 days, my content was all about
providing free value as much as possible
on the topics that I was interested on.
I learned, I studied, and I implemented
it, and then I documented everything
that I learned publicly. Figured out
what the best formats on the platform
were, I built a manual swipe file on
Google Docs and Notes app of content
that performed well, and then I saved it
so I could see what I could take from
those posts and implement it into my
own. Now, quick thing. If I'm being
honest, building that swipe file took me
hours. I had to manually screenshot
posts, save them into folders, analyze
what worked, write down the patterns. It
was so tedious, I literally didn't sleep
for weeks. And so, I want to show you
this amazing database from HubSpot that
literally did all of that work for you
so you don't have to go through what I
went through. And honestly, I'm kind of
pissed because I didn't have all of this
when I started, and I wish I did. It's
called 50 Viral Posts Decoded, and it's
exactly what it sounds like. 50
high-performing LinkedIn posts with
actual screenshots, breakdowns of why
they worked, and the specific success
factors behind each one of them. The
hooks, the structures, the storytelling
patterns, the topics, what actually
drives engagement, all of it analyzed
and handed to you in one place. Look,
you can do what I did and spend hours
building your own swipe file from
scratch, or you can download this thing
for free, study what's already working,
and get a head start. This is completely
free, and I've dropped the link in the
description. Download it, use it, study
it because whether you build your own
swipe file manually like I did or you
use something like this, the point is
you need to understand the patterns. The
hooks, the structures, the storytelling,
the conciseness, and even the topics
that at the time were blowing up on the
platform. The patterns were clear, the
topics were simple and adaptable to my
interests, and beyond that, the people
that supported me. Not because I was a
best-selling author or even a famous
entrepreneur, but because I was just
like them. The average 9-to-5er
scrolling LinkedIn resonated with the
difficulty of getting a job and the
desire to do something else. The average
students saw themselves in me when
speaking about how my degree hadn't
taught me much, and the successful
business owners reading my content at
the time saw themselves in me. They saw
me building, working, and thought, "I
want that person in my team." Because
unlike the average job application, my
content wasn't talking about my job
experience, it was showing my
experience. They could literally see
what I could do, how I thought, and what
I could build, and what I'd already done
in such a short space of time. My
LinkedIn profile became the application,
not a sheet of paper reviewed by a
machine. This was my unfair advantage. I
didn't even need to do the call to
actions at the end saying like, "I have
X spots left for Y" or "I'm taking on 10
new clients for this" and like blah,
blah, blah. None of that. From day one,
my business was inbound. In fact, only
until year two of being on the platform,
I'd never really promoted myself like at
all. I'd gone from freelancer to
building an agency that hit six figures
without a single salesy, pushy post all
through educational content. And that is
the real magic behind LinkedIn. The
culture there is about networking and
reaching out to people, and I used that,
and so should you. People don't just buy
from people because their posts are
asking them to buy now. They buy because
they like you and they trust you. So,
during that time while creating content
about copywriting, frameworks, stories,
all I'd actually done was add a few
things to my profile to reduce the
friction between someone seeing my post
then going to my profile and inquiring
to work with me. It was that simple. No
overly complex funnel or a website or a
logo or anything like that. The reality
is that if you are just starting, you
only need five to 10 clients to buy a
$1,000 to $3,000 monthly retainer
package for you to be able to make more
money that in your current job or match
that entry-level job that you've been
begging for. And so, with that logic,
the over complexity of needing a bunch
of systems, calls, et cetera, that is
for the advanced business owner that has
the capacity for 10, 20, 30 plus
clients. But you as a beginner, all you
really need is five of them who then
refer you to your next five. And so, to
make this happen, the content strategy I
developed was dead simple. So simple
that it almost seems obvious, but the
thing about obvious things is that we
ignore them. So, every week I had a
simple structure. Educate, story tell,
educate, story tell, and then promote.
Within that, I had sub pillars for each.
So, for the educate pillar, I was like,
"I'm going to educate, so I'm I'm to
talk about writing, storytelling,
marketing, and building. Then, for the
storytelling pillar, I was like personal
transformations, new milestones hit,
rejections, firing my first clients,
getting my first clients, getting leads,
building a following, working remotely,
and all of these things that you and I
can talk about. Then, to promote, I
either talk about newsletter and like
doing a lead magnet, or I talk about
client success stories, or personal
success stories that I was building in
public so I could speak about it even
more. So, like going to a conference,
being featured in Forbes for the first
time, uh hitting my first $10,000, then
$20,000, then $50,000. Anything that was
a micro achievement, I talked about. And
that was the strategy, nothing else.
Literally, my most viral posts to date
are about rejections, hiring, or
building something. And if you look at
every single one of those buttons,
there's something clear here. They're
all professional topics. I turned the
average post into a professionally
digestible piece of content by linking
one and the other together. Instead of
being like, "Navigating the job market
is difficult." I literally said, "I got
rejected from nearly every single job I
ever applied for, and I felt like a
failure." A simple change in tone and
writing turned a five-like post into a
multi-thousand view post because it was
real, from real experience, not some
article read or an overly fluffy attempt
to look professional. And that is the
thing with the new LinkedIn. Users are
tired of this overly professional
narrative. They've been tired for a
while. So, realizing that, you can look
at the old approach and topics that the
platform is known for, and then spin
them into narrative-led or captivating
pieces that follow a storyline, but
don't overly explain. And that, my
friend, is how you win the LinkedIn
game. Corporate speak on LinkedIn is
that relatable content is in as long as
it's genuinely valuable and not a fake
attempt to be humble. Just think about
how we now consume media. It's not the
research papers that we seek. The
creator who read that paper, implemented
it, and tells us their lived experience.
That is a new wave of corporate content.
When you do this for long enough, you
start creating a resource that people
would pay millions for, and that is
leverage through building an audience.
You collect a group of entrepreneurs,
founders, CEOs, investors, potential
mentors, or even co-founders because
they see you. And this type of leverage
can be seen in the amount of followers
you have, but also in the quality of
connections you built on LinkedIn. It is
so insane that Snoop Dogg or even Steven
Bartlett are one post away from you, not
endless applications and conferences
away. Just one. One good post away.
That's all it take to potentially change
your life. And these examples are real,
by the way. Snoop Dogg literally engages
with my content, and Steven Bartlett has
me on his network. All because I decided
to click post one day four years ago
from my childhood bedroom during the
pandemic because I needed a job. That
same desperate attempt to be seen led me
to not just that, but also getting a
mentor who took me under his wing and
taught me the ropes of business. By now,
I've been in this business content
creation world long enough to tell you
that the most successful people who
built careers that they love,
million-dollar businesses, and massive
followings didn't concern themselves
with being perfect. They concerned
themselves with doing. Speed in
execution outperforms strategy nearly
every single time. The world doesn't
reward those who wait. It rewards those
who do. And so, do. Ask questions, build
something, take your first client
without really knowing what you're
doing, then figure it out along the way.
The worst thing that can happen is that
you fail once, then you learn from it,
and then you know better for the next
time you try again. And this is the real
work experience that builds your dream,
not work experience that builds someone
else's while you're getting paid less
than them. Now, for me, by this point,
when I was implementing this yellow
style strategy, I was getting busy with
real clients. So, I realized that
strategy wasn't going to cut it because
now I'd had built a client base, I had
new commitments, events to go to, and I
was still at a grad school. So, I built
a system that was foolproof and easy to
use. And this was not a fancy, overly
complex thing, but more so a simple
Kanban style board on Trello where I
could literally manage my ideas, content
flow, and days I needed to post. And as
you can see, it was so deadly simple
that a baby could literally use it. I
preloaded it with the same strategy I
had at the start, but it evolved into an
actual system. I could then use it to
track the content instead of staring at
a blank screen every single time I had
to post content. Each day, I'd move the
post around and click when they were
done so I could move them to the next
board and to the next week, and then
make sure that I had ticked every single
post that I needed to do. So, like
educational content, storytelling
content, all of these types of content
that I needed to get in, I just needed
to check them in into my Trello board so
I can then manage it correctly, manage
my clients, and so everything kept on
going and I could keep that momentum
going as well. And so, in essence, this
entire thing took me between one to
three hours every single week, and then
an extra hour or two a day engaging and
commenting and networking. But quite
frankly, that two, three extra hours I
spent was purely because I loved the
platform and I had nothing else to do
but manage clients and do LinkedIn. So,
at one point, I actually started
engaging like five to eight hours a day
for like months on end, and it actually
worked. But I'm not going to make you do
that, but that's what I did. I mean, I
had no friends in real life that shared
my values or new goals and no
professional colleagues to really speak
to. So, LinkedIn became sort of my
community, and it paid off a lot. There
was no need for an overcomplicated
strategy when I actually had so much fun
being on the platform. I just needed
consistency and a basic system, and
within 12 months, I had built a
six-figure business. Now, if you made it
this far into the video, I assume that
you have some questions just like I did
when I started. So, question number one
would be, "I don't have anything to talk
about." And my answer to this is that
you do. You just don't know how to talk
about it. Let's take someone like Woman
here, who is one of my private community
members. He is 18, and out of all of us,
he has the least to talk about. But
instead of worrying about it, he went
and documented his journey as an intern,
then a creator, then getting hired by a
YC company. Every post he made about his
current life compounded over time and
into opportunities. He learned, he
documented, he learned more, he
documented even better, and suddenly,
boom, hundreds of new followers in under
like six months and a new job. And on
top of that, he now has a priceless
asset that will help him throughout his
career. We can also look at people like
Harry. When he started, he also didn't
have that much to talk about. He started
as a recruiter, so all of his content
was about that, but then he started
talking about his interests in gaming,
and then marketing, then LinkedIn
itself. And then, after doing that for a
long enough time, he ended up building a
six-figure agency in under, you know,
12, 18 months where he literally hired
his family. These two people and many
others just needed the right frameworks
and the right people supporting them.
There are multiple ways to monetize your
content, not just one. Most beginners
think that the only way is influencing
deals or a digital product or a
community. And yeah, sure. For me, I
built a freelancing business, then
turned it into an agency where the price
doubled for the same service, then
productized it so I could serve more
people without hiring really. And then
it expanded into programs, coaching, and
masterminds, which then led to
sponsorships from Notion, Gamma, Loom,
etc. It wasn't a single source of income
that built my business. It was multiple.
And this is called the revenue ladder.
In order to climb it, you need to figure
out the one thing you can charge for
first, and then turn it into many.
Today, my LinkedIn personal brand now
generates more revenue than most
traditional businesses with 20
employees, an office space, and massive
overheads. Because I have no office, I
have no employees, I work from anywhere
around the world, and I have a remote
team of contractors who can handle the
things I don't want to do. And it all
started with that one post I desperately
made just to be seen. And right now,
after hearing what I just said, this may
seem easy, but where most people fail is
not when they start, but it's how soon
they stop. I've seen multiple people
start posting, get excited, and then
just quit because it flops, or because
they're not getting hundreds of
opportunities right away. And this is
why, when you post, you need to talk
about something. It needs to be
something that you care about,
otherwise, it becomes another 9-to-5
that you hate. So, ideally, you need to
talk about something that you love. The
opportunities will then come. It shows
up in how you write, and then how
specific sometimes you can be, or how
honest or passionate about these things
you can be. It attracts those who are
tired of generic advice and hungry for
true depth. I posted every single day
for six months before things really took
off. It was a lot of trial and error,
and a few features on LinkedIn Lunatics,
and endless drafts, and overthinking
endlessly. But I didn't let that get to
me. I kept on going, and so should you.
Here's my challenge to you. If you're
watching this video right now and you're
stuck in a job that is draining you, or
you're getting rejected left, right, and
center, then make a decision right now.
Stop applying for jobs. Stop waiting for
someone to pick you, and stop playing by
the old rules of content. Follow this
journey instead. It's unconventional,
but the conventional way isn't working
anymore. So, try this instead. 12 months
from now, you could be a completely
different person. You'll have
opportunities you never imagined, you'll
have income streams you never thought
possible, and you have the freedom you
never experienced in your 9-to-5. But
you have to start, and you have to stay
consistent. Now, if you want the exact
templates, and systems I used to build
my LinkedIn personal brand and turn it
into a seven-figure business, I've
created the most detailed LinkedIn
growth program on the market. In there,
I go live with my community of over
1,000 entrepreneurs and creators like
Harry and Wilman who are building their
own brands and businesses online and on
LinkedIn. I give you every single
framework, every content template, and
even every single monetization strategy
I've ever used. And so, if you're
interested in joining us, then the link
is in the description. Now, remember,
you're not unemployable, you're not
unqualified, you just haven't built your
own opportunity yet. And so, start
building. I believe in you. Now, go
create.