You have 12 to 24 months to capitalize
on the AI gold rush. Listen, the AI
market is projected to hit 1.8 trillion
by 2030. That's 900 times bigger than
the California gold rush of 1849. We're
not just watching a tech trend. We're
witnessing the foundation of tomorrow's
economy being laid out in real time.
It's creating the new rich of the
century. But here's what no one's
telling you. The people who get truly
rich in every single gold rush aren't
the ones following the crowd. They're
the ones building what the crowd depends
on. Rocket fella didn't just drill oil.
He owned the distribution that everyone
relied on. Basos didn't just build a
business. He built the platform everyone
else depends on. And the same thing is
happening right now, but with regular
people. People with no technical
background, people with no prior
technical experience. They're all
creating million-dollar businesses
running with high profit margins from
their living rooms. And I've not only
seen it, I'm one of them. While everyone
was all in on this fear-mongering around
AI, news cycles consistently talking
about mass layoffs and keeping people in
a constant state of panic, the truth for
me was a million-doll opportunity was
sitting right in front of me the entire
time. And it only cost me a $20 a month
membership. And it was chat GPT. Now,
here's the thing. It wasn't about
knowing the best prompts or racing to
use AI for everything in sight. It was
about understanding what researchers
have said over and over again. AI will
not replace people, but people who use
AI will replace those who don't. I've
inadvertedly said this on podcast many
times as well because there is a
playbook being used by the new rich that
is making them and their businesses
futureproof in this AI era. And here's
the thing, the playbook isn't the one
you're seeing everyone talk about. It's
not about prompt engineering. It's not
about automating everything. And it's
not about chasing after the next new
shiny opportunity. That's what everyone
else is doing. That's what makes you
replaceable. The real AI opportunity
that is generating thousands and even
millions for others is you. Think about
it. Your thinking, your experiences, AI
can't do that. And in this video, I'm
going to show you exactly how you can
turn that into real leverage. Because
the AI gold rush is real, but it's not
about AI. It's about brand. It's about
business. It's about who knows how to
distribute. And AI is only the rocket
fuel that adds to it. While everyone
else is panicking about AI replacing
jobs, smart people are using AI to build
brands that make them irreplaceable.
GaryVee didn't just build agencies. He
built Gary Vee. Mr. Beast didn't just
make videos. He built an empire around
his name. And to highlight a more recent
case study for this, Roy Lee, founder of
viral company Culie, just raised 15
million in funding because he focused on
what most tech giants didn't think of,
distribution. Products can be copied,
ads can be copied, but a personal brand
cannot. And that's exactly why the
smartest entrepreneurs right now aren't
chasing AI to replace themselves.
They're using it to build leverage
around their brand, their authority, and
their distribution. And look, AI has
leveled the playing field completely.
But your goal watching this isn't to
play the influencer game. That's a red
ocean of people fighting for attention.
The goal is to become a micro authority.
A personal brand is literally rooted in
that. The game you should be focusing on
is to become a person with influence,
not an influencer. This is exactly how I
managed to outperform AI automation
agencies or AI drop shipping while using
the exact same technology and ended up
bringing in nearly 2 million in revenue
by not trying to be everywhere or
everything to everyone but by fixing one
problem for one person. The reason why
this works is simple. Distribution I
owned and trust I earned and AI just got
me there faster. Now let's get into a
three-step playbook that will help you
do exactly the same. The first step is
to understand what foundational skill
you're going to build mass authority
around on. This is where you become
known for solving one problem better
than anyone else in your space. See,
what people are getting wrong right now
is that they'll go on chat GPT and ask
you to create them content around
business leadership or accounting for
Instagram or Tik Tok and it generates
them broad and generic content that no
one reads or that doesn't even work. And
it sets you up for failure because
you're creating content for overly
saturated platforms. Again, like I said,
a red ocean. And then they just assume
that neither AI or a personal brand
works for them. Here's where people drop
the towel and go back to spending
thousands on ads or another agency.
Here's the fix, though. Instead of
competing in a true red ocean, which to
me is Instagram, Tik Tok, and even
YouTube, I went to a blue ocean,
LinkedIn, with over 1 billion users, but
literally 1 to 3% posting content. And
out of that 1 to 3%, only 0.1% of users
were posting good content. This is the
unspoken competitive advantage no one is
talking about. And this is why I'm
obsessed with LinkedIn. It's the
ultimate place for business owners who
are established to become known, liked,
and trusted because no one there is
posting content to be an influencer.
People there are posting content to have
a full pipeline every single month. And
I cannot stress this enough. Now, by
simply understanding this, you are
already 20% closer to future proofing
yourself in this AIdriven economy. But
let me be clear, it's not just about
where you post. That's just one part.
It's also about what you post. The key
to winning is to find what unique and
relevant things you have to say that are
going to be helpful to someone else.
What authority do you actually have
right now? How many clients have you
worked with? How many people have you
spoken in front of? What results have
you actually been responsible for? You
can literally answer these four
questions and then add them onto Chat
GPT and it will help you dig deeper and
build relevant content that doesn't
flop. Because in these unique answers,
you will create content that exceeds
expectations and gets people returning
to your content every single time. Now,
to keep this video from being incredibly
long, I will be giving you the top line
on how to do this. But I will be
covering this in detail on my free 3-day
live mastermind, which is free to
attend, by the way. There I'll be
breaking down exactly how to turn your
AI fear into an advantage no matter what
you do, sell, or trying to build. So,
check out the link in the description.
Now, to keep things super simple, we're
going to be using AI. I like to use the
content trifecta, which is a concept I
came up a few months ago. And it
essentially outlines the top three
outlier content angles that I found work
across platforms, but especially on
LinkedIn. And I'll be getting into what
each three of them are in a second. But
before we use it, we need to understand
what information we need. So again,
using our good friend Chat GBT, I'll
need you to drop any relevant content
that you already have, whether it is a
pitch, a deck, a transcript, past
content that perform well, or other
relevant information, and drop it onto
Chat GBT. And then you can use this
prompt. Based on this, please give me
three to five specific content pillars
or themes that will help me become an
authority in my niche while still being
professional given my background and
current audience. Make sure we focus on
education, storytelling, and
inspirational content. And as you can
see, if I do exactly this and take
someone else's content from the
internet, it comes up with a good
starting point for us. And honestly,
this is already way more specific than
any of these other prompts that you'll
find on the AI content videos that don't
really work. For example, Cleo here,
which is basically almost like a
ghostriter in your pocket, onboards you
with simple questions to understand your
story, your business, and then builds
your brand DNA that then creates content
for you so you don't have to go back and
forth between prompts. Now, whatever
tool you use, free or paid, to prevent
you from wasting time, you need to
understand the three angles that work in
content. A true reason why my LinkedIn
content outperforms most people's is
because I understood this. You need
total addressable market content, you
need broad content, and you need expert
level content. Now, let me break them
down. Total addressable market content
gets you discovered. Think about it like
the first business book you read. It was
an entry-level book. It was simple, but
it solved a painoint or confirmed our
belief. And this is what total
addressable market content should be
doing for you too. The content that fits
this style incredibly well can fall into
three categories. The first one is
mindset. So the way you think about
success, growth or money, then work
culture, so habits, routines or
productivity hacks. And lastly,
motivation. So the aha moment reminders
that make people feel seen. This right
here is the top of funnel content that
makes people stop scrolling and say,
"Wait, that's me or I really enjoy
this." And that's exactly the feeling
that this content should be creating.
The second part is broad content. And I
say broad, but it's still broad and
niche at the same time. So broad in the
hawk, but niche in its execution. For
example, storytelling content. So let me
give you a good hook idea so you can
understand it better. I quit my job at
21. Then I built a business by 23. The
first part is broad as it's relatable to
many. But then it gets niche when we use
the built-up business line as it targets
the people who are interested in exactly
that. This brings in a specific type of
traffic. And then the third, you need
expert level content which is
specifically about what you and your
business does. This is where you become
undeniable. You're showing the deep dive
stuff that proves that you know your
stuff, case studies, how-to breakdowns,
step-by-step frameworks. And let me let
you in on a little secret. I write
nearly every single one of these posts
using AI. So when you zoom out, this is
their ultimate AI play. The AI gold rush
isn't about prompts. It isn't about who
can automate the fastest. And most
certainly it's you and AI. In my eyes,
AI is the car that gets you to your
destination faster. So let's talk about
where you want to go, which is
ultimately capitalizing on the AI
opportunity and what you've created with
it, which is step number two of my
playbook. monetization and lead
generation. You built an AI powered
personal brand, but now we need to turn
those eyeballs into actual income.
Because here's what most people don't
understand. Having a million followers
means nothing if you can't convert them
into real customers. Like one of my
friends, JK Molina says, likes ain't
cash. And I've seen people with 5,000
followers making 50,000 a month. And by
the way, you can actually get thousands
of leads every single month with one
strategy that has been tried and tested
to work. Lead magnets. Lead magnets have
been proven to generate thousands for
users on LinkedIn. They're basically
free and valuable resources that you
give away in exchange for someone's
contact information. Typically, their
name, their email address, and sometimes
their phone number. Let me show you an
insane case study I recently saw for
this is Shan. He is the owner of one of
the biggest agencies in the world. A big
part of their content strategy on
LinkedIn has been lead magnets. his
organic lead magnet campaign on LinkedIn
attributed to six figures in lead
generation in under a week. Mind you, he
has 42,000 followers, not millions,
42,000.
He's an authority in the space. Every
agency owner knows him. And that's
exactly what the goal of a personal
brand is for business owners. These lead
magnets don't only just collect emails
for you, but they do something that's
even more powerful. It answers the
common objections that a potential buyer
may have when looking at you, your
content, and even your landing page. Do
you get my problem? Do you know how to
solve it? Are you even real? Is this for
me and my hypersp specific niche or
problem? Do you understand my incredibly
complicated situation? And usually the
answer would be yes. When you create a
hypersp specific lead magnet, let's say
it says something like 10 hacks to put
PCOS into remission for women, they not
only want it, they not only download it,
but they now in their head identify you
as someone who understands their problem
and can actually fix it. Think about
lead magnets as a fair trade. I'll give
you something valuable for free, and in
return, you give me permission to stay
in touch with you. Now we've got the
content engine, we've got the lead
generation machine going. Let's talk
about converting these leads, which is
step number three, where the magic
actually happens on email. Your content
serves as the perfect setup. People
trust you. They like you. They listen to
you. The lead magnet serves as this
perfect vehicle. You solved the problem.
They gave you their email. They're aware
of your ability to solve painful
problems for them. And now the inbox is
where you get them to work with you.
It's the ultimate trust accelerator.
See, social media is rented land. The
algorithm decides who sees your content.
But on email, that's property you
actually own. When someone opens your
email, it's just you and them. No
distraction, no competing content, just
pure and undiluted attention. And this
is where AI gives you an unfair
advantage that most people are
completely missing. Writing is not
everyone's forte. I know that. But that
should not stop you from tapping into
the biggest gold mine of cash flow we
have as business owners. Let me explain.
When someone opts in into your lead
magnet, there's two mistakes you should
avoid. Mistake number one is have them
opt in and never hear from you again.
And mistake number two is have them opt
in and then send an email once every
month or once every quarter or once
whenever you remember or when you have
time. This happens way too often. What
you should do instead is one, have a
welcome email plus the lead magnet. Two,
have a welcome email sequence that's
around three to five days. Three, have a
weekly email going out either educating
or storytelling. And then four, have an
offer focused email sequence that you
can use whenever you want. This is just
a top line though, and I'll save the
whole breakdown for another specific
video where I can nail it out on email.
But just know I literally love emails.
Like, I am obsessed with them. They've
changed my life. And this plus AI tools
are truly another winning piece of the
puzzle. All right, those three steps are
the literal fundamentals of emails that
even if you implement this with no more
context, you'd actually see an increase
in conversions. You can also use AI to
write these emails, which I've done
quite often. Even recently, I wrote 20
emails in just 3 days. Most, if not all
of them made us around 5 figures each.
This one made us 12,000. This one made
us 10,000. And this one made us 9,000,
etc. All with the help of AI. This is
what I mean. AI is the vehicle, not the
business model. As you can see, all of
this AI stuff gives you speed. Your
brand gives you the leverage. Likes and
virality are not the wealth creators
anymore. If you truly want to create
wealth, you do this by teaching, showing
proof, and solving tiny problems. That's
the playbook. And AI just speeds it up.
AI doesn't replace you. It amplifies
you. Your thinking, your experiences,
your stories. AI can't replicate that.
But AI can actually help you package it,
distribute it, and scale it faster than
ever before. So, you have a choice.
Spend the next 12 months worrying about
AI taking your job, or spend it building
an AI powered personal brand that makes
you irreplaceable and add six figures to
your pipeline along the way. The window
is open, but it won't last forever. AI
won't make you rich, but ignoring you
will make you poor. You could even end
up looking back in 3 years and say, "I
wish I started now." There are a few
moments like this in our lifetimes where
we wish we were there earlier. This is
one of them. And like I said, the
playing field is now even. Take
advantage of it before it's too late.
Season.