There will be jobs it eliminates.
>> We're looking at a world where we have
levels of unemployment we never seen
before. Not talking about 10% but 99%.
And that's without super intelligence.
>> The day will come when AI will do all of
our all the things that we can do.
>> Many existing jobs will entirely go
away. AI adoption is not slowing down.
It is compounding at a staggering rate.
in this room and so a good bet would be
to be a plumber.
>> There is a lot of noise surrounding this
AI takeover that everyone is talking
about. And whether you're in the
workforce or a founder, you need to
listen to this video. Look, out of all
of the research me and my team have
compiled on this AI wave, there is one
thing I agree with. Time is running out
and you either adapt or you fall behind.
But I'm not here to scare you because I
have the answer you've been looking for.
But before that, I need to show you some
of the notable claims from our research.
Venture capital funding for AI tools hit
a record high, says Crunch Base. Prompt
engineering is the fastest killing wave
we've ever seen, says OpenAI. But the
reality, those AI tools being funded,
70% of them have no active uses after 90
days. The prompt engineering skill set
that everyone is rushing to learn, it's
going to be completely obsolete in 12
months. And those companies that proudly
laid off staff to replace them with AI,
they're quietly rehiring humans because
the tools couldn't deliver while
everyone else is chasing the new shiny
thing. That shiny new thing is eating
their lunch. The services these new AIE
companies are offering at a premium AI
tools are already doing them. Prompt
engineering, chart GPT or claude now
does this for you. Even if you don't
have any technical knowledge, just look
at tools like global and even gamma.
They've completely automated what people
were calling the next best business
model just 6 months ago. Automation
building already being streamlined by
popular tools everyone uses. Sapia,
Trello, and even Notion AI. Everyone has
access to the same workflows. Now, if
you're watching this right now in 2025,
you're not the one in danger. You're not
asleep. You're not blindly building.
You're not chasing shiny new tools with
no plan. You're paying attention, which
already puts you ahead of 99% of people
right now. Look, we've seen this before
in every revolution, industrial,
internet, automation. The pattern
doesn't change. The fast things to get
replaced, though, are the skills at the
edges, the easy stuff. Just look at how
in the industrial revolution, a bunch of
manual work got replaced by machines.
But the workers didn't disappear. They
adapted. Some learned how to operate
these machines. Others learned all the
skills to complement these machines.
Now, here's the lie that everyone is
selling you. AI alone won't make you
rich. The winners of this bull run
aren't the ones creating AI automation
businesses or pumping out prompts left,
right, and center. The winners are the
ones pairing AI with a business. And
that, my friends, brings me to the point
of this video. The AI agencies that just
sell AI won't last. The people who truly
succeed are those who understand the
ultimate weapon, distribution. And in
today's economy, the modern-day
opportunity is attention. Distribution
is built on one thing, brand authority.
It's fundamentally what has allowed me
to build a sevenfigure business by 27.
It's also fundamentally how I grew and
scaled a six-figure agency at
university. And it's even now how I get
equity in multi-million dollar
businesses. Mind you, when I started
only 3 years ago, I had no leverage
before, no followers, no capital, and no
business. But I had one thing, the one
thing that no AI can replicate to a
basic level yet. Trust at scale. And
here's the thing about trust. You can't
hack it. You can't automate it. And you
most definitely can't prompt engineer
your way into it. Trust in today's
attention economy is built one
interaction at a time. one piece of
value at a time. It's the compounding
interest of personal branding. AI can
help you create content faster for your
personal brand, but it can't make people
believe in you. The hype around AI may
not be worth your time, but the hype
around personal branding 100% is.
Building your online authority carries
more weight than any of these fast money
businesses or even AI powered tools.
However, there is a very important
intersection between them that actually
works in your favor. Look, by now you
understand that AI isn't the business.
It's leverage. It can make you faster,
sharper, louder, but it won't make
people listen to you. Having an audience
will. This is the opportunity that
everyone else is ignoring. If you have
distribution, you win the game. Look at
the latest tech founder giant and
founder of Cluly. Distribution is his
mode. raised 15 million in funding
without a fully finished product. Nailed
the attention game and is everywhere and
so is his business. Alexi did the same
thing. Dan Martell did the same thing.
These people don't just have tools, they
have attention and that's what prints
leverage on demand for anything that
they do. A 100 million money models, a
record-breaking launch for a book, not
an AI powered system that makes you
offers on demand. a book that you read.
This record-breaking book that has
nothing to do with AI was a result of
his ability to get attention to generate
trust at scale. Let me put this into
perspective. We're living in an era
where people are building million-doll
AI tools and this guy breaks a record
selling paper with words on it. Why?
Because when you have distribution, when
you have attention, you can sell
anything. You could probably sell
something insane like no strips to
penguins if you had Alex's audience.
That's the power of a personal brand.
Now, I've got a full indepth personal
branding video breaking down how to do
this at scale on LinkedIn, which I'll
link in the comments. And I'll also be
delivering this playbook to you for free
and live during my 3-day online
mastermind for business owners where you
can watch me turn business owners into
domain authorities with a future proof
business and a personal brand. If you
want to join me, I'll leave the free
link for you to join below and also drop
a follow too so you don't miss any of
the next videos that will help you be
prepared for it. Let me share the
ultimate three-step distribution
framework that you can implement today.
Step number one starts with finding your
unfair advantage. This is ultimately the
thing that will make you stand out in a
saturated niche or a market. This could
be down to your background, your
network, your mindset, your story, your
skill set, or even your pain and how you
solved it. These individual experiences
build that differentiator that people
pay thousands for, and you already have
it. Your goal here is to find three
unique standout angles for your content.
So ask yourself, what results do you
already have? What niche knowledge do
you already have? And what lifestyle and
personality angle could you use that
could set you apart? We actually used
this exact same exercise with one of my
friends, Jod. We blew her personal brand
up on LinkedIn in literally 42 hours.
Here are some of the answers we came up
for her so you can see how easy this
exercise can actually be. So for her top
three content pillars, themes or angles
that she could use, we used
entrepreneurship and business building,
then AI and being a chbt expert. And
lastly, my favorite is the fact that
she's a pro athlete. So all of her
discipline is an identity
differentiator. Now step number two is
to have content market fit. Essentially
for this, you need to align with the
demand that the platform that you choose
has. A cheat code for this is to use
LinkedIn of course as it's still an
untapped under supplied market. So to
start on LinkedIn or any other platform
you need to ask yourself what problems
are people currently obsessed with
solving for themselves. Think about it
like this. Is it time? Is it
productivity? Is it making money faster?
Is it getting someone from A to B? So,
for example, let's say that you're a
sales coach that knows how to run many
chat AI automations and puts them
through a blah blah blah complicated
system, right? Your offer is, I turn
your pipeline into actual revenue in 30
days with my systems. Simple. Now, with
this, we've got strong positioning that
builds trust for you on social media and
especially on LinkedIn. So, moving on,
step number three is following my
authority framework for content. I call
it the 4321. The way this works is four
posts every single week, three content
pillars or themes, two ideal audiences.
So, one of them is your ICP and one of
them is your IFP. If you can guess what
IFP is, leave it in the comments and
I'll say yes if you guessed it. And then
the last one is one lead magnet per
week. Literally dead easy and it works.
This is the exact framework I've used to
help agency owners, freelancers, and
consultants become AI proof. Even my
ghostriting agency clients, people whose
literal job was words, became AI proof
when they turned their work into public
authority leveraging the framework I
outlined above. Now look, there's always
going to be someone better at prompting
than you. There's always going to be
someone better at building GPT rappers,
but there's only one you, and that is
the biggest moat, the biggest leverage,
the biggest advantage. And paired with
AI, you won the game. So my friends,
don't sell AI services in 2026. Sell a
transformation and use AI as your own
for advantage. See you in the next one.
Bye.