This billion-dollar AI founder has
mastered branding on LinkedIn and every
other social media [music] platform. And
today, he's going to walk me through his
exact five-step LinkedIn [music]
strategy that he used to turn Gamma into
a startup with over 70 million users in
2 years and becoming one [music] of the
most viral companies in tech. Grant and
I have a combined total [music] of
multi-million views on LinkedIn. We both
turned it into a lead generation machine
[music] as well as a distribution engine
>> for our businesses. So, if you want to
know our exact playbooks, then watch
this video. So, Grant, you built one of
the biggest startups in the world, in my
opinion. Tell us what the playbook to
doing that looks like.
>> Yeah, for us, when it comes to product,
the thing you got to start with is make
sure you have a product that has strong
word of mouth. Before you start spending
money on advertising or marketing, make
sure the product is doing all the heavy
lifting. People use it, telling all
their friends, family, colleagues about
it, and then the rest is way easier. And
then, what else would it be? Word of
mouth?
>> Start building your community early. So,
if you do have strong word of mouth, it
means you have users that love your
product. You got to lean into that. That
means finding ways to, you know, bring
that community together. It could be
virtual, it could be over Slack, it
could be in person in real life.
>> In London? In London, by any means
necessary, but uh build the community.
And then, how do you turn word of mouth
and community into a marketing machine?
That's where, you know, I think
founder-led marketing is where you can
kind of bring it all together. It could
be the founding team, it could be not
just only the founders, but really that
core group that believes so much in the
product, so much in building the
community, and wants to really just
amplify everything you're doing. Okay, I
love all of these, Grant, and I agree,
especially with community because you
literally flew all the way to London to
come meet your users. And I'm going to
get into that in a second, but let's
talk about founder-led marketing. I
looked at your LinkedIn. I'm a LinkedIn
expert. But, I think you are probably
also a LinkedIn expert from what I've
seen because every single one of your
posts goes I'm an accidental expert,
yeah. Accidentally, but it's happening
consistently. How have you managed to go
viral on LinkedIn every single time?
>> Well, if you go back maybe 2 years,
maybe about 2 and 1/2 years when I first
started getting into just trying to be a
creator myself, and you could tell my
posts were not going viral. They were
very much not getting any views beyond
maybe just my friends liking the
content. And what you realize is like a
lot of founders have to get through what
I call cringe valley. You got to like
get through this this low point of just
putting yourself out there. Yeah, and
eventually you find stuff that is at the
intersection of like things you're
uniquely sort of special to your own
story, and things that resonate broadly
with other people, and takes you a while
to figure it out, and eventually you get
there.
>> So, with cringe valley then, what made
you choose LinkedIn, which is, you know,
known as one of the cringiest platforms
to post on?
>> Yeah, for me it was actually doing both
LinkedIn and X in the very beginning.
And, you know, I think every founder can
ask themselves if they do want to become
a creator, you know, what strengths do
you have? For me, writing came more
easily than trying to be on video, and
so I'd start by just writing out all of
my ideas. I'd actually posted both on
LinkedIn and X, and for whatever reason,
LinkedIn content resonated more with the
audience there, and I was able to build
a lot more momentum faster, so I just
doubled down on kind of focusing on that
platform.
>> Okay, so LinkedIn over X for you?
LinkedIn over X for me, and I think you
know, everybody's got to find their own
channel, and it could be different. So,
lean into your strengths. If you see one
channel working, you should just focus
on that.
>> So, you have multiple approaches to
founder-led, I've looked at your
Instagram, etc. On LinkedIn, you sort of
specialize into more so sharing
milestones Yeah. of the company. What is
the thought process behind that?
>> I think what you want to be able to do
is, of course, when you are announcing
stuff for your company, you can be your
company's megaphone, you can amplify
that. But, you don't want that to be the
only content. And so, I do try to spend
a lot of my time thinking about, you
know, how do I reach builders in
general, people that are maybe aspiring
entrepreneurs, and what lessons could I
share? And I think this is where there
is that sort of overlap between if I can
share kind of the journey, build in
public, and tell them like what I'm
learning on the way, then that kind of
kills two birds with one stone. I can
actually amplify Gamma, but I can also
share important lessons that are super
relevant to what we're going through at
the moment.
>> have like three different types of ideal
audiences, so like builders, people that
will relate to your journey, then, you
know, aspiring entrepreneurs that want
to follow it, and then your ICP as well.
Yeah, so for us, our product is used by
anybody that needs to visually
communicate or storytell. So, that's a
lot of people. It could be, you know, if
you're working within a company, you
might be in finance or operations,
you're an analyst, and you're constantly
using decks to share that information
out to other colleagues. And so,
storytellers broadly are people that we
can sort of target. How do we help
people become better storytellers at
work? And so, that ends up becoming a
lot of different sort of sub ICPs that
we can then go after. Okay, cool. So,
you said you write LinkedIn posts every
day, five times a week?
>> It hasn't been every day. I think I
strive to do that because I feel like if
you can get into a good rhythm, you just
have more data points to test. Like,
it's all about being able to test a wide
variety of content, and if you get into
the daily habit, you can also lean into
things that feel very relevant, things
that are coming up in the moment,
whether it's news or trends, and sort of
really build a USP, sort of thoughtful
and kind of engaging in topics that are
popping up.
>> I want to get into your founder-led
LinkedIn playbook. So, you know,
consistency is five times a week, give
or take.
>> Yes.
>> And then, topic-wise, how do you write
content? As a company, we think about
our ICP, so what are the things that we
can sort of build upon? So, what are the
skills broadly? You know, you can talk
about visual communication, and then
break visual communication down into
like what are some of the pillars? So,
storytelling, how do you, you know,
write good copy? You can talk about
visual design. What are the sort of
traits of something that is visually
engaging and consistent? You can talk
about brand consistency. There's a lot
of these things that topically you can
sort of now pull together, and then what
you teach within each one of those
topics, you can start going deeper in
and testing. And then, even for me as a
founder, then I can also zoom out and
say, "Okay, what do I want to teach
other founders or aspiring
entrepreneurs?" It could be one pillar
is maybe target entrepreneurs that are
maybe a little bit later in their
career. So, they're not, you know, the
straight out of college, you know,
dropouts, but people that maybe have
built a career in finance, but are now
thinking about for the first time
building a business. What things do I
wish, you know, I knew starting Gamma
that I can help them fast forward and
kind of skip a few painful years. These
are things I try to just pull back to
our own story and kind of replay that
back so that founders can learn from it.
>> Yeah, this is honestly what I tell
people to do, focus on the education
pillar, which is exactly what you've
outlined, and you know it by heart. And
as a founder, I think that is insane
because most founders don't actually
think about this in the depth that you
just described it. And then, you have
obviously your story-led angle, which
means that you can talk to everyone
while it's following people to Gamma and
your story. And then, you have a third
one, which is my favorite, which is the
announcements and the milestones.
>> Yes. So, for you, how do you decide
which ones to announce? Like when you
have a new product launch or a new
revenue milestone? Do you just go, "I'm
going to tell all of them. I'm going to
talk about all of them," or "I'm going
to reserve some of them"? How do you
think about that?
>> Yeah, I work with my marketing team a
ton to try to map things out. So, we
have a few bigger like launch
announcements every single year, and so
those we can kind of map out on the
calendar, say, "Hey, these months we
have some bigger announcements we want
to make." When things come up like
fundraising or other sort of revenue
milestones that we might want to
announce, we put those onto the calendar
as well. And then throughout, then
you're just sprinkling smaller sort of
announcements. These could be
partnerships that are coming up, these
could be customer wins that you want to
highlight. These are the ways to kind of
fill the gaps for the rest of the
calendar.
>> Yeah, customer wins. How do you know
which ones to share? Well, I mean, you
know, we we can obviously sort of
crowdsource this by just talking to our
go-to-market teams. When we were signing
up a new customer or we're doing a case
study, we can take a lot of that and
say, "Hey, which one of these deserve
more amplification? What can we turn
into like short-form or long-form
content?" So, we work with our
go-to-market team to brainstorm.
>> Okay, so we have the three types of
content that you've created. If you had
to bet on one of them to go viral
tomorrow, which one would you go into?
Yeah, I think it's the founder content
just because the way I sort of frame it
is, I think for me I target the sort of
underserved part of the market, at least
I think is underserved, which is people
that have been aspiring founders or
entrepreneurs, but have not yet been
able to make the leap. They've been
intimidated or scared or just haven't
found the right moment. And so, you as
someone that is a founder, you can kind
of
help them sort of alleviate some of
those fears by sharing how easy or
possible it is, and you can do that by
sharing your own examples, you can do
that by sharing examples of other
founders that maybe had overcome sort of
fear or uncertainty, and there's so
much, you know, sort of goodwill you're
building With viral posts and like the
founder-led storytelling, have you ever
felt cringe?
>> Yeah, I mean, definitely. Especially
when you're talking about yourself. This
one way to reframe it is start by
telling the stories of others. For
instance, one story I tell is around
like Morris Chang, who is one of the
sort of executives at TSMC, which is at
the time just a company that was just
getting started, and he was a much older
founder. And so, someone that you could
arguably say had already seen the peak
of his career and was maybe ready to,
you know, retire. How can he then go on
to build one of the most powerful and uh
valuable companies in the world, and
doing it well beyond his 50s? And so,
most people would have said, you know,
his time is done. I kind of reframed it
to say, "Actually, everything he learned
before that moment in time was necessary
for him to build the company he did."
And I think that just helps people just
understand that it's never too late to
get started.
>> And after you tell the stories of
others, when do you decide to tell your
story?
>> I sprinkle it in. Most cases, it's like,
you know, three or four stories of other
founders, and then I'll kind of pull
back and say, "Okay, this is what's
relevant to me," or "These are the
lessons I've learned." I've tried to do
that also at different milestones. So,
like when we hit, you know, our
five-year mark at instance at Gamma, I
can then reflect, "Hey, in 5 years, what
have I learned that I think is going to
be useful for the next set of founders?"
I like what you're doing here because
you're using the halo effect, and it's
probably helped you grow a lot faster
than it would have. I think it actually
has a few different things. It one, it
actually forces you to become a better
storyteller because you're trying to
learn someone else's story, and then
figuring out what parts of that are
going to be interesting, and how do you
make it resonate broadly? And then two,
you basically can understand like of the
things that were valuable for this
particular person and their career, what
might be relevant in my own story and so
it kind of helps you just to also be
introspective along the way.
>> So you're almost sort of focusing on
being interested rather than being
interesting and then using those
interesting facts for you. Totally,
yeah. Almost like testing out what the
market is resonating with. Testing out
for sure. Yeah, I think a lot of the
best creators obviously do a ton of
research and they can kind of synthesize
this information in a novel way and then
repackage it and then tell it to, you
know, the world and kind of share
broadly. So it forces you to exercise a
muscle that most of us aren't doing very
regularly. So if you were to write a
storytelling post today for LinkedIn,
like how would you even start? What is
the process behind Grant's viral
LinkedIn playbook? Number one rule is
find something that actually interests
you because you're never going to be
able to go into the depth that's
required if it's not even interesting to
you. You know, it's similar to like most
of the best like podcast interviewers or
people that have like great guests on to
the show, it's often because they're
actually curious about that topic or
that person knows and so you start with
a curiosity and then you go super deep
on that and then once you have kind of
that depth, you can then pull out, okay,
what are the themes I think are going to
be most relevant for my audience. When
it comes to themes, you can basically
think about one way to kind of reverse
engineer is like, okay, think about what
the hook is going to be. What is going
to be the thing that draws people in and
of the themes that you kind of
highlighted, what do you think are going
to be the one or two that you can say to
somebody, anybody on the street and they
could actually be intrigued or kind of
learn more about and the sort of
copywriting piece of it is where, you
know, a lot of people don't invest
enough time in understanding like what
is good copy. A lot of people just
assume you can just write a, you know, a
wall of text and it's going to resonate
broadly, but really think about how do
you package something so that someone
can actually lean in and curious. I
think that's going to be, you know, a
super important part. This is so
interesting cuz you've clearly taken the
time to try and learn the art of content
creation. Yeah. When did this happen for
you? Like when did it hit to you that
you needed to understand this not your
marketing team? This goes back to when I
first started. So like 2 and 1/2 years
ago when I first started to get onto
LinkedIn, you know, none of my posts did
anything. Like there's no engagement at
all. And so I realized, okay, let's go
back to the fundamentals. How do I write
something where at least I can get some
more viewership and then ultimately
hopefully more engagement. You know,
there's a few different principles or
like a mindset you can have is, you
know, is this content going to be
something someone would either share
with a friend or bookmark for later
because they want to reference it. These
are the things that will actually create
good engagement and
I think that's the mindset you have. Is
it share-worthy enough? If it isn't,
then go back to the drawing board and
when I started looking at other content
creators and, you know, trying to just
understand their craft a little bit
better, you would see that there's like
very common like a framework that they
would use. These hooks have to be very,
very engaging. You have to capture
someone's attention, be a scroll-stopper
instantly and then you got to then peel
it back to say, okay, how do you package
up the information so it's super
digestible and then something that, you
know, is again shareable. So like the
takeaways have to be so clear that if
you're maybe in that field and you know
a colleague would benefit from this
information, you're going to share it or
bookmark it. That should be the quality
bar that you're aiming for. You seem to
have a lot of awareness as to how
psychology works within content. How
long, like how many hours per day before
or even now do you think you spend in
content and like understanding it? Let's
go back to when you started.
>> Yeah. When I first started, basically I
had so many posts that I would not even
post and this goes back to the cringe
valley thing is like I would write
things, I'd have like 20 different
drafts and they would all be probably in
my mind terrible and I just wouldn't
post. And then I recognized that, okay,
posting is giving you data, right? You
need that data. So the worst thing you
can do is actually not post. The best
thing you can do is just post regularly
and then try your best like after every
week I would go back and say, which of
my posts actually did okay? And if I
were to kind of go back and do a
scorecard, like what do I think I did
well? Sometimes the hook was good,
sometimes the hook wasn't good,
sometimes the sort of angle I was going
for was too generic or sometimes it was
too niche. You're always trying to like
balance those two out. You want to be
able to be specific but authentic and so
you're trying your best to like go back
and actually rate yourself. And then
when you learn, you go back and try to
improve and you just do that over and
over again. Nowadays, I can probably,
you know, have like a few hours session
on like a Monday morning and have enough
content for the week, but I'm constantly
trying to build a backlog. So I will try
to make sure I have like weeks worth of
content at any given point in time and
then always like kind of promote certain
ones at the top and then post those ones
so I can get, you know, kind of a
constant flow of content out there. So
out of 10, if you were to talk directly
to the founders watching this that want
to start building a personal brand on
LinkedIn, but they say that they don't
have time, that it's not important, that
they can just get their assistant to do
it, what would you tell them? I would
build the backlog. So something that I
do is like every day when I do have
ideas, I just put it into my notes and
you just accumulate as much as that as
possible and then you get to a point
where you have enough to be actually go
back and rate, okay, of all the things I
could post on, how much of this do I
think is actually interesting and
valuable? Valuable to the audience I
think is the most important thing. So
grade your content on that and then
accumulate enough of that and just start
posting. You just got to force yourself
to start posting.
>> So just recap, this is Grant's viral CEO
playbook for going viral on LinkedIn. So
start with something that is interesting
to you, then find the curiosity within
the topic so you can also share with
other people. The number two, understand
the themes. So like what is the theme?
Are you going to educate? Are you going
to storytell? Are you going to announce?
The third thing is understand what a
good hook looks like, what good copy
actually looks like and also make sure
that is shareable and people want to
bookmark it, which I think is something
that most people don't actually look at.
Most people look at likes and comments,
but shares and bookmarks are the things
that make posts go viral. It's just what
we've seen many, many times before. I
have a remark that I want to share with
you. Maybe you can use it tomorrow. When
I tried to go viral like you about
announcing something, I used the slay
framework. Have you heard of it? No. So
slay framework is very similar and it
goes with all of your psychological
ideas behind copy and you start with a
story and then lead with a lesson. Then
add actionable advice and then a you. So
if your team were to start posting on
LinkedIn today or even you and you were
tired or you didn't just want to do
announcements anymore or the new
milestones, you can talk about your trip
to London. So like I just flew in London
for 24 hours. We met our 200 of our
users in real life. We saw that all of
them love Gamma, then all of them love
me and all of them love AI. And that's
almost like the lesson like but it has
to be a little bit more tactical before
Now I'm just making fun of it. And then
we can say something else like at the
end to wrap it all up to make it feel
good. We say this the art of building in
public and building community. Yeah. The
companies that don't build communities
are going to be left behind in 2026 and
then I use like PS, who wants to come to
the next Gamma event at Pre-Sale? And
you get them to sign up, you get them
excited, you get them commenting and
that's how we kind of viral engineer
engagement.
>> Nice. Can you explain the S again? Yeah,
so story. Story, okay.
>> So I just flew into London for 24 hours.
Okay, so give them like some sort of
framework. Stories are what lead
content. It's not education, how to do
this, how I did this. It doesn't work.
Yeah. Cuz ChatGPT can do that for you.
Any AI tool can do that for you, but you
can only share what you've done right
now. You can talk about your stretching
routine in the morning.
>> [laughter]
>> Everyone needs a stretching routine,
I'll tell you. I just learned about
Grant's stretching routine. Crazy. I
should start one. Quick one, [music] if
you're enjoying this playbook, then
please hit the subscribe button and
leave a comment below. [music] These
videos take hours to make and organize
and if you subscribe, it also helps the
channel grow and helps me get more
amazing founders like Grant into the hot
seat. So back to the video. A lot of
Gamma's growth has been led organically,
right?
>> Right. How much of it? 100%? Over 50% of
it still.
>> still? Yes. Wow. And how long for? Like
since you started Gamma two years here?
Uh we So we launched our product almost
three years ago now and that's ever
since then it's been heavily organic
adoption.
>> Since 2023? Uh 2023, yep. 2023, so like
it was 100% organic then? Yes. In the
very beginning we spent zero on
advertising, marketing. It was 100% then
over time as our audience and our user
base has grown, we've started investing
more. Okay, cool. So why did you go
organic first? Full honesty, was it
because you didn't have budget?
>> No, I'm actually in 2022 we launched our
public beta which meant like anybody can
actually sign up and use the product
right away and this was pre-AI. We saw a
huge spike in sign-ups, but then we saw
sign-ups sort of plateau out and so we
recognized that our product wasn't good
enough that people would tell their
friends about and so we knew that if we
wanted to grow, we'd either have to
spend a lot of money on advertising or
we should go back and actually
re-engineer our product so that had
stronger word of mouth. So we made the
decision that at some point course we
can throw money top of the funnel, but
we didn't want to do so until the
product could grow on its own. That
without any sort of advertising or
marketing, we could acquire new users
simply by users telling their friends
and using the product and getting out
there organically. That's super
interesting. So like you went back to
drawing board and you made Gamma the
best product on the planet. That was
essentially the decision. The fork in
the road was were we going to start
spending on advertising or go back to
the drawing board?
>> and now when you spend on advertising,
it's like
>> It's all amplified, right? Yeah. And so
it becomes way more efficient. And then
once you have that efficiency, you can
reinvest that money so much faster into
building a better product. You have so
much more optionality in how you build a
product. If you get lured into sales and
marketing too early, you know, your
margins get consumed right away, then
your options go away and then if
anything, you've sort of delayed the
sort of requirement of going back to
building the better product and most
founders just never go back to building
the better product.
>> How did you know how to build a better
product?
>> So our focus was because we're going
after new users, let's make sure the
first 30 seconds of the new users'
experience is magical. It has to be so
good that first 30 seconds at least
earns the next 30 seconds and ideally
it's so good that when they leave the
product, they go and tell their friends
about. So we went back and said, okay,
all hands on deck, every single one of
us is going to figure out how can we
make the first 30 seconds magical. We
gave ourselves four months to do so and
we relaunched the product in March of
2023 and that's when there was the You
relaunched it completely? Yeah, we
relaunched it completely. Wow. I didn't
know that. That's really good. I love I
love Gamma. It's a great experience, so
easy to use. You've gone from all
organic, you rebuilt the product and now
you've gone kind of all in on influencer
marketing.
>> Yeah. I I so what we've recognized, so
before we actually went in doing any
sort of influencer marketing, we were
starting to see a lot of creators
already post organically about Gamma.
So, either they were using it or they
were trying a lot of, you know,
different AI tools, and they saw Gamma
as something that really felt different.
And so, when we started seeing a lot of
that, this sort of coincided with me
trying to become my own creator and
starting to post regularly, I was seeing
a lot of that content starting to do
better and better. And so, we
recognized, okay, well, we should just,
you know, lean more into this. How do we
actually partner with great creators?
How could we really educate them on how
to use Gamma more effectively and use
that as a mechanism for really driving
even more word of mouth. And you have
the main sources, which are LinkedIn and
Instagram? We do LinkedIn, TikTok,
Instagram, X, and YouTube. All platforms
actually have been pretty useful for us.
I think we benefit from being a tool
that's very visual. On the short-form
and long-form video platforms, we can do
pretty well. So, talk to me about the
best LinkedIn, like, not influencers,
but posts Mhm. that seem to get you guys
the most conversions. Have you looked at
the data? The ones that go the most sort
of viral often times are linked to some
sort of big milestone or announcement.
LinkedIn for us serves multiple
different purposes. One, it's a great
way, obviously, for customer
acquisition, but two, it's for us also
an important channel for recruiting
candidates. And so, we see a lot of
people that hear about our company
through some announcement, and then all
of a sudden you'll see a big spike in
people applying to Gamma because they
want to work there. And so, for us, it's
it's obviously beneficial there. And
then third, because we also have our own
sort of API and we're starting now our
sort of B2B motion, we get a lot of
partners that reach out through LinkedIn
as well. So, it ends up becoming
multiple different purposes that
LinkedIn serves, and so it's not just
customer acquisition we care about. We
actually look at all three. So, how many
followers do we gain? How many people
reach out on things like DMs to partner
with us? And then, of course, we can
look at things like sign-ups and what
portion of sign-ups are coming from
LinkedIn. These are all things we can
track back. Do you know what the
percentage is for, you know, customer
acquisition from LinkedIn as a channel?
>> So, across all sort of social platforms,
LinkedIn is probably a little bit over a
quarter of those sign-ups. And so, it's
always been great, but it's also the
quality, right? So, obviously, you get a
lot of business professionals, people
that have higher willingness to pay,
have a real business need versus, of
course, you know, TikTok, you might get
a lot of students. We love having them
on the platform. They're not going to
necessarily be the ones that are
building their businesses, you know, on
day one on Gamma, but for us, you know,
it's a great way to build brand
awareness. So, every channel kind of has
its purpose, and LinkedIn, of course, is
best for business professionals. Who are
your favorite LinkedIn influencers that
you've partnered with? Ruben is one we
partner with. You, of course. There's so
many that I think
>> Ruben, he's great. Ruben's great.
>> like one of the first ones as well, I
think.
>> Yeah, yeah. Especially with a lot of the
AI stuff. And so, yeah, it's been great
to work with him, and he partners with
startups that, you know, he actually
uses the product. And so, for him, he
has a very high bar, and for us, it's
been great to just be with him on this
entire journey from when the product was
still very rudimentary and he could kind
of see where we were going and invest in
us as well.
>> Ruben, for those out there know, he's an
AI guy, and he was leading the Gamma
wave at the start. He was, I think,
probably the one of the first
influencers to talk about Gamma. And you
made it so simple, and I think that's
your ideal type of persona.
>> Totally, yeah. Demystify sort of the AI
world, make it less intimidating for the
average person, and just make it
accessible, right? Like, at the end of
the day, like, everyone wants to be able
to pick up a tool that actually makes
their lives easier, not like super
complicated to sort of onboard, and I
think he does a great job of striking
that balance. And as a founder and
someone that's leading the influencer
marketing, how do you go about finding
the right people to partner with your
brand?
>> You end up consuming a lot of content
yourself, so you see who's putting great
content out there. And then, you're
often times working with a very broad
swath of creators and seeing which ones,
like, is there a good sort of fit
between their audience and the way they
storytell and your product. So, you
know, you're going to have to test and
experiment a ton, but really trying to
reach broadly out into the community and
see who are ultimately is a good fit.
>> Okay. Yeah, so definitely me.
>> Definitely you.
>> And then Ruben. And Ruben, yeah.
>> And then more of your own influencers as
well.
>> Well, I am my own, and then there's so
many others out there, too. And then, is
your company also posting on Gamma's
like top and Gamma employees? Yep, our
employees post. We also have our own
Gamma account that posts, obviously,
from it's the main company account. And
so, I think everybody has a chance to
amplify and be part of the storytelling
that we try to do. Which one do you
think moves the needle the most? You
posting, B2B influencers posting, or
your team posting? We see it as like
portfolio, right? Like, you can't do one
without the other. It should all be sort
of complementary in nature cuz each
person has a different sort of
superpower, a different angle. Like, if
as a founder, of course, you have a
different, you know, way to tell your
story. Someone that is a creator and
like independently just observing what
you're doing and is, you know,
objectively kind of trying to tell your
story, they have a an authentic way to
do that. And of course, your employees,
you want them to help build your brand,
and many of the employee posts end up
becoming great ones for recruiting
purposes. And so, I think you kind of
need all of it. You can't just settle
for like one or or the other. It really
needs to be complementary. It ultimately
ends up being like, the more I post, the
more employees can riff off of what I'm
doing cuz they're I'm giving them fodder
for like their own content. So, without
my content, it'd be harder for them to
even think about, okay, what's the right
angle? But if I give them a ton of stuff
to work with, they can peel off the
stuff that's relevant to them. If
they're an engineer versus a marketer,
they might have a different angle, and
that's great. Like, we want that.
>> So, creating your own ecosystem, so
people can't really say I don't know
what to post about. You're like, "Grants
already doing
>> No excuses, right? Yeah, you create you
create enough out there so that
everybody has You can be their
inspiration. It really is like lead by
example, and you put yourself out there.
You're telling your story. They can find
the right angle that's relevant to them
and like then piggyback off your
content.
>> that you are so in it. Like, you love
talking about content, I can tell.
>> Yeah, yeah, I love it. Yeah. You like
You love talking about content.
>> and I feel like too many founders like
maybe take it for granted or going back
to the cringe part, like, they're like,
"Oh, that's just not me." But I think it
has to be you. Everybody is such a great
opportunity. It's a way for you to build
your brand, and you absolutely have to
be doing it. So, let's say you have
Grants in 2026, but you are just
starting building Gamma, and many, many
of the AI founders are looking at you
for advice. They're like, "What will you
tell them about LinkedIn? Like, how
would you get them started?" It's always
easier to do this with others. So, I
would say find your group. If you're not
able to do yourself, find a group of
other founders that are committed to
doing this alongside you. And at the
very least, you'll have maybe, you know,
four or five other founders that can at
least like and, you know, upvote your
content, which is a good starting point,
and then you can give each other
feedback, right? With anything, whether
it's going to the gym or, you know,
doing any sort of routine that is sort
of not something that you naturally want
to just jump into, finding your group is
going to be really important. And then,
practice the craft, right? Like, study
other You have to almost be a consumer
of the content. So, go out there, do
spend time on LinkedIn, on X, or
whatever platform, and look at stuff
that performs really well. Can you
somehow reverse engineer it? There's a
an exercise some people do, which is, if
you're a copywriter, you actually go and
find like great examples of really good
copy, and you just literally just force
yourself to write it word for word so
that your brain is sort of rewired to
say, okay, this is the right way to
assemble a set of words so that it will
resonate broadly. And I think you could
do the same thing with short-form
content, same thing with LinkedIn
content. Force yourself to find stuff
you think is really good out there and
reverse engineer like write it down
yourself, practice it, and then find
your way to give it your own unique
spin. And then, after they sort of
understand how to write content, what is
a third thing that you think would have
gotten you from 10 to 100,000 followers?
Something I leaned into was just trying
to get like critical feedback from
others. Sometimes I would post something
or like I go on a podcast and someone
would reach out to me and say, "That
really resonated." And I would always
follow up and say, "Could you be
specific? What of the hour-long podcast
did you find actually useful?" And
they'd tell me like the one or two
things they remembered, and I'd go down
and write it down. Basically, I would
tell them, "Hey, I want to make sure the
next time I am on a podcast or I'm I'm
posting on LinkedIn, I can really pull
on the themes you found useful." And so,
asking for critical feedback, trying to
engage with people that are, you know,
willing to give you that feedback,
that's a gift, and I think many people
just also take that for granted.
>> So, step number one, find a group of
friends or founders that will support
you, and then you won't be lonely in
this process even if you're cringe.
Yeah, and have them do it, too, yeah.
All learning together, all doing it
together.
>> guys set yourselves like goals or
challenges like whoever gets to 10,000
followers as fast as possible gets We
didn't, but yeah, that's something
that's worth, yeah. And then, step
number two, be your own consumer. So,
like, how many hours would you say that
you spend on LinkedIn or any other
social I have too many. Yeah, too many?
What was the screen time looking like?
>> It's it's a lot. It's a lot. It's it's
probably not a healthy amount, but you
do it, you bookmark things you like, you
go back and watch that content, and you
do it across like every single platform.
>> So, what I like about this is like
people are consistently looking for ways
to get out of that. Like, "Oh, I don't
have time for this. Can I get my VA to
do it?" But you do it.
>> I do it. It was kind of you, and then
you're better at it, and then everybody
wants to do it. I think if you can
reframe it in your head to say, "I'm
doing this to learn, not doing this to
just binge-watch," I think that's
different, right? Like, if you're doing
this because you're just letting your
brain rot and like you want to go and
escape somewhere, that that's a
different mindset than, "Hey, I'm
consuming this content because I'm
genuinely trying to learn to be better."
And I give myself permission to be on
these platforms to learn, to bookmark,
to share with my other founder friends.
I think that's a different mindset. And
so, it allows to me to be locked into
like even observing any piece of
content, I can really appreciate like
what that creator's trying to do for
their audience, and then I'm thinking
about how can I replicate that for
myself.
>> Yeah, it's not doom scrolling. It's
market analysis. Exactly.
>> That's what I call it.
>> Yeah, yeah. I've been calling that a
dozen since 2007. Okay. And then,
critical feedback from everyone so you
can see actually where you're going
wrong. Ask for the feedback. Yeah, I
think most people just don't even ask
for it, right? Like, they'll just assume
it's not worth their time to look at the
content or give me feedback or, you
know, give me advice. But if you ask for
it, I think you'll be surprised by what
people tell you. I would add a few more
just on top of these based on what I
observed about your brand cuz I I study
it. Cuz I'm like, "Wow, what's he doing
now?" I think the milestones really help
sort of categorize into the category one
now, founder CEO. The next one is, I
would say, the AI wave. So, you are in
AI, and LinkedIn is very AI native.
Everybody loves AI. So, you're also sort
of tapping into that, obviously, because
that's your business, but it also works
for LinkedIn.
>> Yep. And you have the halo effect around
you because you're partnering with all
of these influencers and people are
talking about it and then so as a result
people learn about grants. And so it
just like goes back to the whole thing
and it's like a cycle here. Totally. But
someone watching this today may be
asking themselves I'm not grants, I'm
not we don't have multi-million dollar
businesses now. How did you manage to
talk about the milestones about your
business at the start that weren't
massive like millions and millions of
dollars? Yeah, I'd say in the beginning
it was less so about these big flashy
milestones and more about the sort of
struggles or the things that you're
learning along the way. We tried to
share just stories of fundraising that
didn't go as well as we would have liked
or I told you about like this or sort of
public beta launch where we saw this big
spike in sign-ups but then it's sort of
plateauing out and us realizing we
didn't have a product that was good
enough that had strong word of mouth. So
even when you aren't like, you know, at
the top of the world and like really
feel like you're thriving you can still
share the sort of the journey and like
what you're learning. I think that's
really important to do too and then
hopefully over time as you do become
more successful you can then package up
the entire thing to say hey these were
some of the tougher things that we
overcame along the way and this is like
the light at the end of the tunnel like
what do you get as a reward of all that
and hopefully you can do both, you know,
across the kind of the entire journey.
>> I think your LinkedIn playbook is so
simple anyone could steal it. So are you
okay if I review it for everyone here?
So I think you have three different
types of content. So you have education
based, you have stories and you have the
announcements and milestones. So these
all happen every single week. There's at
least one new announcement, something
you can talk about. And then you talk
about you and then educate on the
product. But on top of that you have
this insane sort of circle around you
where a lot of people are consistently
talking about Gamma to some extent
they're either talking about you,
they're talking about the product,
they're talking about comparing
PowerPoint and Gamma. And so this
actually has accelerated your brands on
LinkedIn which is something a lot of
people don't look at and they're just
thinking about this which is too
granular and it takes time. But here
you've like feed run yourself to
hundreds and thousands of followers by
leveraging all the people. Yeah, I mean
part of this is you need to engineer the
thing that's going around here which is
give people a reason to be talking about
you. Are there sound bites that you can
plant broadly so that people have a
reason to kind of be an echo of your
content and for us, you know, early on
this was things like we talked about
being a tiny team. A tiny team that can
accomplish a lot despite having very
little resources and we when we talked
about that enough eventually the New
York Times picked us up and talk about
us being a tiny team and amplifying
that. And of course then other people
that read that would then go on and post
us as an example of an AI company that
was able to do, you know, accomplish a
lot without huge team. And so these sort
of sound bites are ones where it can be
a self-fulfilling prophecy by even just
talking about and saying hey you're
engineering your own narrative
basically. And a lot of it just goes
back to like even the copy like what are
these sound bites or things that can be
sticky in someone's head and how do you
have that surface? How do you think
about that? It's just going back to just
practicing, you know, content and just
trying to think about your own story
what do you think is going to be
interesting to tell others? I love that.
I'm going to copy that for myself. If
you're a founder, business owner or
solopreneur and you want the exact
playbook that Grant and I just used
[music] I put it all into a document for
you so you can download it for free.
Link is in the description. Now I know
we're running out of time so quick fire
questions. What is the 80/20 for
marketing an AI startup in 2026? What's
an example of one you used there?
So for me it would be distribution is
the 80 and then the content is the 20.
So like if you don't have distribution
the content's not going to get seen.
Yeah, and this is specifically for
content on LinkedIn.
>> Yeah, for content or like you could just
whatever feels most like it could be
building a business in 2026. So like
what is the thing that this year you've
done that has actually made it better
for you to do things? Yeah, I'd say, you
know, for us LinkedIn content has been
place where we've seen the most sort of
rewards. Yeah, and because everything
you can build off that like LinkedIn
inspired content can then, you know, be
leveraged on across all the other
platforms. Hell yeah, we love LinkedIn.
Amazing. This is the marketing playbook.
Now onto me. Yeah. I have an AI startup
called Cleo. It's a LinkedIn writing
tool for now. Right now we're four
months old. If you were in my position
right now, what is the one thing that
you would over index on? So you spoke
about the sticky thing and the
rebuilding the whole product. I like
that.
>> Yeah, I mean I would go back to what
could you do in the product to increase
organic virality or organic word of
mouth so that by using the product
people either want to tell their friends
to use it or by using the product it
spreads to other users. Um and so, you
know, the latter is, you know, companies
like Superhuman where, you know, all of
their emails you'd have the sort of
footnote of hey this is sent by
Superhuman. By using Superhuman that
allows that product to spread pretty
organically. And so are there ways for
you to engineer that within the sort of
workflow of your tool? That's one way.
The other is like what would be so
magical in using your tool where people
couldn't help but tell their friends.
Like if anybody's interested in finding
a writing content tool by using yours
like it's a no-brainer. I'm going to
tell all my friends that they have to be
on this tool tomorrow.
>> So like your onboarding which is like
super seamless. Could be the onboarding
experience. It could be the results that
you get instantly. It could be
basically, you know, as part of the
onboarding maybe you get some sort of
personalized email or personalized
setup. These are all things like there's
many it doesn't need to necessarily be
one. It could be many different things
that create the sort of need to tell
somebody and how can you stack as many
of those up as possible. We think about
Scott Belsky as a saying like your new
users you should have the sort of
cynical view of them which is they're
all selfish, vain and lazy. If you can
create a product that scratches as many
of those as possible you have a chance
of creating something special that again
goes back to being Okay, that's pretty
good. And now a second thing, what about
churn? When you if you've ever
experienced it, how do you fix it?
>> Yeah, with things like churn and
retention often times there isn't going
to be like a silver bullet. It's not
like one thing that all of a sudden
fixes it all. It often times is a
combination of the product maybe is just
lacking in certain areas. It could be
that you're serving the wrong target
user. So, you know, churn can be
inherent if you have even a product
where maybe the usage is very episodic
for instance and they only need it for a
small project and then they're done.
That's like one form of churn but you're
not going to really understand that
unless you understand who the user is.
Like students may only use your product
because they only use it in the school
year. And so I think understanding and
segmenting the churn is going to be
super important. So it's a combination
of what product capabilities maybe are
missing or lacking and then two who is
the user or the use case and, you know,
is churn sort of natural or not natural
in that sort of use case. Do you do that
by surveying them when they exited like
when they unsubscribe?
>> Yeah, you can do a multiple things. One,
you can when they first sign up you can
try to understand who they are, what
they're using your product for and then
if they do churn you can send a survey
to say hey, you know, are there things
we can do to keep you around? If if so,
what are these things? And then over
time you can also just run much more
robust surveys around where people that
are using our product what things do
they actually value and how different is
that from people that churn? Like are
they valuing the same things? It's
likely that the people that value your
product and stick around maybe they see
something about your product that the
churn customers either didn't experience
or isn't relevant to them and so you're
really trying to understand kind of the
overlap there.
>> For the survey do you ever offer them a
gift like people send $10 Starbucks
cards etc. Have you ever done that?
Yeah, we definitely have offered that. I
think it's a great way you should always
probably start with seeing how much you
can get without offering anything and
then offering some sort of smaller
incentive like a $20 gift card to
complete the survey. Try to keep the
survey you know, lightweight so it's not
something that's going to take hours but
you know, 10 minutes of their time for
you know, $20 gift card usually is a
pretty good exchange of value. I like
it. Okay, so well I'm going to steal
your entire marketing playbook and then
go head-to-head with Gamma. Maybe we can
do Gamma for Cleo and then there's like
an integration there for something I
don't know. But yeah, that's pretty much
it for me. Thank you so much for giving
me this. I'm going to implement it and
hopefully it works. That's it and we'll
run it back and hear about the results.
Ladies and gentlemen, Grant big founder
Gamma. Try it now if you want to do it.
Any updates from Gamma that you want to
share? We just launched a new feature
called Gamma Imagine which is an ability
to create visuals and basically be your
own graphic designer. So if you have a
need to create infographics, visuals,
illustrations come check it out. We'd
love your feedback.
>> Love Gamma, love the team [music] and
thanks for being in London. London
marketing with us. London marketing.
>> Hell yeah, high five. Bye guys.