this one LinkedIn hack helped me build a
$100,000 Business Without Even having a
website I'm going to share the hack that
has helped being and my person bring
clients grow the profile get more leads
and convert clients instantly as well as
getting more Authority being featured in
Forbes LinkedIn news Entrepreneur
magazine and other news Publications and
by the way you're going to want to apply
this quickly because LinkedIn has become
one of the fastest growing Platforms in
2024 gar has been talking about this for
years and people are starting to catch
on so if you want to get ahead of 99% of
people here's exactly what you need to
do step number one your banaana your
bana is Prime real estate and you need
to take advantage of it the first thing
it needs to have it needs to be 2,400 *
600 pixels that provides the perfect
size for you to edit it and uploaded
onto LinkedIn you should tell people
what you do and the problem you solve so
this must include a clear call to action
let people know where to buy from you or
where to contact you otherwise they
won't know and lastly the design should
be clear simp simple and straight to the
point don't over complicated and don't
oversaturated with things simple is
better for example if you're a fitness
coach instead of having a banner that
says are you looking for a fitness coach
I offer personalized workout plans meal
prep and onetoone coaching contact me
below that's vague unclear and I don't
really know if that coach is a person
for me instead you could say something
like I help busy entrepreneurs lose fat
and keep it off in 90 days join my
program sign up below see better number
two the feature section is probably the
most underutilized feature in on all of
LinkedIn people either just spin a viral
post that happened a year ago or just
drop a random link and it's costing you
thousands of dollars here's how to fix
it I'd like to divide the feature
section to three different tiers a low
ticket offer a middle ticket offer and a
high ticket offer so what are they in
the low ticket section we would have
something like a newsletter signup link
or a link to a template PDF or something
that's under $100 in the middle option
we would have onet toone Consulting
Services where people can just buy an
hour of your time or something like that
then the last one would be either an
application to apply to your retainer so
if it's like a monthly thing and people
need to apply and you need to like
consult because it's higher to get like
over $11,000 so that's how I like to
position it just because it tells people
exactly what you do where to buy and
what options they have available without
even leaving your LinkedIn profile treat
these thumbnails as a thumbnail of a
YouTube video they need to be clear and
they need to explain what are they
clicking on and entice them to click as
well so for mine I ask a question I give
a solution or I entice them with
curiosity the last thing you need to do
is just add it to your profile use the
link that you want to direct people to
and that's it number three content your
content should be better than anyone's
pay this is the bare minimum LinkedIn is
getting saturated so you need to stand
out so how do you do that you have to
share specific stories your systems how-
to because they build Authority and
trust my favorite types of content I
usually convert clients straight away
just from my content are either how
toose testimonials a lot of social proof
or a storytelling Post Number Four a
profile link on your LinkedIn there's a
hidden option okay it's not that hidden
but it's really hard to find where you
can literally just put exactly where you
want to direct your traffic to all you
need to do is choose what you want to
direct people to so it's is it a funnel
is it a landing page or is it a lead
magnet either way make it easy for
people to buy from you or to give you
their email or just to consult with with
you and now onto my favorite number five
social selling this simple thing helped
me made $10,000 passively no promotion I
never spoke about it on my LinkedIn but
I just did one simple thing and that was
commenting about my product every single
time I would post something and it would
go viral so 100 likes 200 likes 300
likes whatever it was in the comments I
would drop a CTA to where I wanted
people to go what was it it was me using
the comments as an addition to a cool to
action rather than just using it in the
post itself this helps make the post
Shine for it for what it is just the
post with content educational content
inspiring content or entertaining stuff
and then leaving the comment section for
the call to action this increases my
chances of my post doing better because
there's no sale and then in the comments
I get the people that are already
interested in me and and that want to
buy from me so I just drop a call to
action in the comments it was usually
something like you can buy my LinkedIn
Playbook here and I'll just drop the
link people would like it it would it
would be the fast post people would see
because on LinkedIn the author's post
are usually shown at the top so my first
comment would be shown at the top so it
was it acted as an addition not as a
post itself on the post itself I could
be educated giv a lot of value and then
in the comment section they would find
what to buy from me rather than me
telling them to buy from me they just
went and found it last but not least the
headline I see a lot of people making
the mistake that they just add what they
are and leave it as that so I usually
see CEO of X founder of Y and it doesn't
tell me anything it tells me who you are
but it doesn't tell me how you can help
me or what do you do so my favorite
headline formula is a what who how
formula what do you do who do you do it
for and how do you do it stop trying to
blend in with everyone else and start
differentiating yourself with the unique
things that you do and how you can help
people when you're updating your
headline ask yourself what is the
promise I'm making to the ideal p that I
want to come and view my profile because
aside of your profile photo which by the
way you should really update is the only
thing that's shown consistently on the
feed you can always see the profile
photo and the headline and that's
literally it that's everything you need
to do to turn your LinkedIn profile into
a moneymaking landing page let me know
in the comments if you do end up
updating your LinkedIn profile photo or
if you have any other LinkedIn video
ideas for me until then I'll see you bye