This is Cameron. He quit his six-f
figureure tech job to build software
while traveling the world making more
money than any business [music] could
ever pay him. But what will take Cameron
from where he is right now to scaling
faster is content. And this is how his
software will get the distribution he
needs for free while building authority
and getting leads. So today he's going
to sit down with me and we're going to
be going through every single one of
those steps. And my name is Lara Costa.
I built three, [music] six, and seven
figure businesses using content and
LinkedIn. I built my personal brand from
zero to 300,000 followers and I know
exactly what [music] the bottlenecks
income strategy are and how to fix them
today. The key elements we need to cover
in order to build a profitable brand are
one expertise and how we can own it.
Number two, relevant stories and [music]
how we can use them to drive attention.
And number three, traffic generation and
how to manufacture [music] it. My plan
is simple. Ask some questions, get
keywords, and build a strategy and a
full content system for him to use for
the future and for his business. Okay.
So, today we have Cameron here. He is
starting building his personal brand on
LinkedIn and he has a few problems that
we're going to be addressing today. So,
Cameron, do you want to introduce
yourself?
>> Hello, I'm Cameron and I'm a software
engineer turn entrepreneur. I have two
SAS businesses. I started coding at 13
and yeah, now I build SAS and businesses
for a living. I am currently looking at
starting my LinkedIn journey. I'm having
a few issues figuring out what to write
about, how to go about it, and Lara is
the best person at doing this.
>> Yes. So, what do you think is your main
problem when trying to sit down and
write content?
>> Without a doubt, it's figuring out what
to write about.
>> Yeah. And is it because you don't know
what angles work best on the platform or
you just can't even figure out what to
write?
>> I think I have a lot of information to
share, but it's figuring out how I can
say it in a way that's interesting to
other people.
>> Amazing. So, with your LinkedIn
strategy, cuz you've been coding and you
have all of this knowledge, what is the
problem that's stopping you from
creating content consistently and well
on LinkedIn?
>> Right. So I would say Cleo is great for
writing the content, but I think what I
personally struggle right now is what do
I write about? What angle do I write
about and how do I go around it?
>> And if you were to know like so I want
my personal brand to be this like what
do you want to be known for? Cuz we
start with what you want to be known for
and then your positioning and then the
social proof that goes with it. So what
do you want to be known for first? I
want to be known as the tech guy. The
guy who can come into a company and
build a tech team and just really like
pioneer the technical side of a
business.
>> Okay. So within that, what are the main
skills that you think you need to talk
about or show to educate your ideal
client or user or follower about so they
trust you as that person as a tech guy?
What does a tech guy talk about? So, I
think I need to talk about technical
things obviously, but this is where I
struggle because I personally as a tech
guy, I want to get in the details. I
want to nerd out on everybody, but I
know that not everybody's interested in
the real details.
>> Yeah. So, what if we took away all that
over complication like you have you want
to say everything, what would you
actually be talking about right now?
>> I would like to talk about the code.
>> I would like to talk about things like
tech stack.
>> Yep.
>> New latest AI tools. Yep.
>> How we can use them in Cleo. Yeah.
>> So when it comes to coding, like how do
you make this beginner friendly? If you
were for your ideal clients, they don't
know code. So what do they usually come
to you to talk about? Like what
questions?
>> So I think maybe an angle could be more
like the vibe coding side. So me showing
somebody without the experience how to
build different app, build different
tools and start to sell a product. And
then for tech stacks is the same. So
like they just want to know how to
become more productive, how to do that.
>> Yes. Like what tools can they leverage
to get things done faster?
>> Okay. And then the latest AI tools or
trends. Why is that important to you?
>> Well, obviously Cleo is an AI based app,
but I think in general it's a hot topic.
People want to use the latest AI tools.
If they know certain things are
available, it actually every time
there's an advancement in AI, it opens
up a whole new world of opportunity for
businesses. Okay, that's good. We sorted
that out. So, we have enough knowledge
here so we can build a content strategy.
Now, for positioning, what type of
personal brand do you want to build?
There's two types of brands that do
incredibly well on LinkedIn. There's the
storytelling ones like myself, and then
there's education only like Jake's. What
do you want to lean more into? Do you
want to be known for you or for your
skill? I think I would probably lean
towards the story side, but I would also
obviously like to show my knowledge
>> and social proof is the most important.
So, here's how you sort of like
differentiate yourself from every other
tech guy on LinkedIn. So, you've
obviously built Cleo and scale that to
>> 62k.
>> Nice. And then before that, what else?
And who else have you helped do
something of that caliber or something
that people would want to listen to you
for? also built mentions or passive
mentions which is at 20K MR.
>> And what does mentions do?
>> Mentions is a tool which lets businesses
and websites see how they are cited in
LLMs.
>> These two are B2B SAS companies, right?
Okay. B2B
SAS and then anything else?
>> I think really before that my authority
just comes from the companies I've
worked at um mainly just in a 9 toive
job at large corporate American
companies.
>> Okay. Can you say anything about these
companies like four to 500?
>> Yeah, some of they're worth like several
billion dollars.
>> Billion dollar. So the reason why this
is important is that if we can just map
all of this out, people need to know you
for one thing and then they need to
trust you based on that because if
there's no this, they can't really tell
if you're being serious about all of
this. That's where we're going to start
building your content strategy. So we
need to go for high value skills and
then monetizable expertise. So a high
value skill is what you can tell stories
about and what can what you can educate
on. People get this wrong all the time
where they feel like they can only
educate but never storytell. You can
always do both at the same time. Your
high value skill is obviously being in
tech having built businesses from that.
So tell me two stories that we can use
today about you being the tech guy. I
built Cleo to 60k. That's one of them.
Building like building in public in
public. And the next one that would
stand out to me would be you quitting
your job on a whim to go and work with
the Cleo guys, right?
>> Yeah. Quitting 9 to5. And then education
when it comes to high value is how do we
get a stranger to trust me in less than
60 seconds? You knowing what you know
about the market. What do you think
would interest someone like me or Rob or
Jake to work with you? Well, the thing I
see the most is the whole vibe coder
project in order weekend. So, if I can
show people what's possible within one
or two days, maybe they can see well
what's possible with someone with
expertise over a longer period of time.
>> Okay. Anything else?
>> Maybe AI tools which are out there that
they can use like your average person
can use that will help them. So people
will see this and I see this all the
time where you'll highlight, oh you can
talk about this, you can talk about
this, you can talk about this, but
people will be like, okay, but where's
the money or how do I grow? All of
these, if you think about them, they all
lead to a first principle which is
financial. Building in public, you
showing how you built in public leads to
people knowing how they can make more
money. You quitting your 9 to5, you quit
your 9 to5 for a reason to make more
money. So every single thing that we
ever talk about always comes back to the
main principle which is making your
ideal reader the main character. And so
within the first one or two lines of a
post, there always needs to be some
financial incentive or some sort of hint
that this is going to make the user
money. That's what we call unselfish
content and how we make it all about
them. even when you're talking about
yourself. And then the monetizable
skills are, you know, how to build a
SAS, how to buy code in two hours or
less, whatever. Anything else?
>> How to use X AI tool.
>> And then we always say either to save
time, make money, or live a better life.
Cool. All right. So before we get into
actually writing content with Cleo and
AI, we need to understand what your
content themes are going to be. This is
what the part when voice people kind of
like get confused or where they stop
posting content because they use AI and
then they'll be like write me a post for
this but then there's no continuity like
I don't know where this is leading
ideally let's say how many posts a week
do you think you want to write four
>> four or five
>> okay so we're going to be following my 4
3 2 1 framework which aligns well with
you. So four post a week. And so since
you want to build a path of run that's
based on your story but also
storytelling. The split between the four
is going to be one post about education,
one post storytelling, one post doing
both. So edu telling using the slay
framework and then another pose is
educating. This immediately removes
every single constraint of like what do
I write about? You go into a post
knowing that this is going to be an
educational post based on what we talked
about earlier. So then you don't have to
have to decide on the day. You already
know what you're writing. Then the three
is for the three content themes or
content pillars that we're going to be
using. So we already decided that you
want to do education and storytelling.
So those are not the content pillars.
What we're doing is either talking about
total addressable market content. So
something that goes viral because that's
how you're going to increase your
followers. That's how you're going to go
viral. Then we're going to do growth
content. um which is similar to total
addressable market content but this is
going to grow you as a person. So people
getting invested into your brand rather
than just what you're educating on and
then this is like sales content. So for
total addressable market content is
where we talk about something that you
have the unfair advantage to talk about
that not that many people do which is
LinkedIn has these eight keywords that
it loves pushing. One of them is AI. The
other one is productivity. The other one
is remote work. Um the other one is
LinkedIn itself. LinkedIn loves it when
you talk about LinkedIn. So you already
have four. And so when you think about
this, you already have the cheat codes
to create content that actually performs
well without really doing that much
extra work because someone else that
doesn't work remotely, that doesn't know
how to use AI, will have to kind of
figure out how to link everything back
to but you don't because you
automatically already talk about these
things. Then growth content is going to
be stories that again are linked to fast
principles. Your 9 to5, quitting your
job, building a SAS, talking about
money, these things. And then sales
content goes back to how we're actually
monetizing you. Will you be promoting
Cleo in your content?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. And then will you be selling your
consultancy or anything else or just
Cleo only?
>> At this stage, I just want authority.
>> Okay. So, we only want to drive traffic
to your main SAS or your two SAS. And
then the thing here is the two. So
there's two types of personas that you
want to talk to every single time. Most
marketers always focus on one and that
is your ideal client persona. Right?
Everybody talks about this. There's
another one. It's called the IFP, ideal
follower persona. The people that are
18, 19, 20 that can't afford our
product, but they can afford to support
you. These are the people that we want
to get the most because they're going to
push this type of content to your ideal
client. Okay. Now the last thing is my
favorite one. What do you think this is?
One thing a week that I love so much.
One lead magnet
>> magnet a week. So at first like one of
my core principles as people know is
lead magnets. Why do you think we need
lead magnets every single week for a
personal brand?
>> To capture their emails.
>> Yes. The thing with lead magnets on
LinkedIn is that they serve in two
different ways. So when you post a lead
magnet, you get emails. But the second
thing is that these are some of the most
viral formats on LinkedIn because you
automatically get more virality because
people always want free stuff. So if
you're consistently pushing lead
magnets, people get to follow you, they
find you, they know you, and they trust
you, which is like literally what we're
trying to do with all of these these
things. But this is all in one. But most
people don't poison them because they
don't know how. But you know how because
we built some magnets together. Okay,
cool. Now we are you clear on this?
>> I'm clear on this. So let's revisit. So
the four posts. So if you were to
educate on something today, what would
it be?
>> By coding.
>> Okay. B coding. And then so if I said
how to b code assass in 2 minutes. That
does that make sense?
>> Something like that.
>> Cool. Storytelling. Your next
storytelling post would be about
>> quitting my job.
>> Okay. And then how do we make it
interesting to someone else?
>> We
>> use Cleo.
>> Use clear.
>> And we link it back to a problem that
they have. So I quit my 9 to5 to go fly
to Canada. Here's exactly how you can do
it as well. That's the second thing. But
clear can also help us do that. And then
storytelling using the slay. So if you
were to tell a story about something
like B coding, the way that we would do
it is like I started by coding when I
was 15.
Since then, I built two B2B SES that are
nearly six years each. And then here's
how. So that's how we retain that
authenticity but still educate an
audience that is in your IFB and then
your ICP. Okay. And then again, we
educate back and then you can create a
how-to step by step how to build a SAS
product. Cool.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. So, we're going to hop on to
Cleo. This is my Cleo. So, it doesn't
have your information, but ideally what
we would have done is that we will put
everything that we just went through
from the content that you're going to
talk about educating and storytelling in
some context about you and how we just
put it in your knowledge base. Then,
we're going to write like me because
this is my writing style on Cleo. And so
how are we going to write your first
post? The prompt is I want to write five
ideas for my next LinkedIn post. I want
to be known as the tech guy in my
industry. I want to talk about Vive
coding, etc. Give me hug ideas that
match fast principles. Add urgency scars
to your firmware if needed. And then
make this total addressable market
content. On top of this, I'm going to
add a secret cleo swipe file that we
created that has all the knowledge in
here. You can also find it within the
writing frameworks, right? the
>> viral SOP.
>> The viral SOP is somewhere here. So once
we have that, it should give us five
amazing hook ideas that can make you go
viral tomorrow, huh? Yeah. So the first
one, I built two six figure SAS products
using Vive coding. You don't need clean
code to hit six figures. Vive coding is
dead in 6 months. I left my corporate
job to build worse software. Wow,
>> it's an angle.
>> Most engineers will never build a
profitable product. I think this is
good. Okay. So then we actually prompted
to write it. Ideas are good because they
teach you exactly how you need to take
your idea and actually make it a topic
that people are interested in rather
than just a topic that you're interested
in. And obviously then Cleo is going to
write it here. So most engineers will
never build a profitable product. I was
one of them for years. Oh, this is
great. What Cleo is doing here, we are
doing to a few things. So most
engineers, so we're categorizing one of
your ideal audiences that will follow
you and then they they want to know how
to build a profitable product. So
immediately we're giving them the
payoff. And then the second thing is
you're then relating back to you. So
this is entertaining while they're
educating and this defeats the typical
viral LinkedIn slop which is like here's
how to build a productivity app. It's
about them through the lens of you
because everybody wants to build a
profitable product in seconds and then
you know you write the entire post based
on whatever Cleo gives you. Any
question?
>> No. That's good. If you were to leave
now, what do you think would stop you
from being more consistent or feeling
like you're on track?
>> I think would be probably like
validation of my ideas. So, I think what
I would probably do is I'd probably
split out each of the different pillars.
I'd probably come up with ideas for each
of the pillars. But then until I guess
I've I've done the practice and I I've
seen what works and what doesn't, my
first question would be, is this a good
idea?
>> Okay. So, how I would validate the idea
is using Cleo's swipe file because how
we we've built it is we can tell what
people are saving right now. And so, if
you take a validated idea that someone
else has saved, then you put it next to
your post that you wrote, you can sort
of like see what type of content is
doing well on the platform. And that's
exactly how I built my content. It's
like by understanding patterns, not just
regurgitating what other people are
saying. Like, is this formatting working
right now? is this topic and angle like
negative, positive. Oh, this person used
a lot of images. Maybe I should do that
for myself. And it's about testing and
iterating until it works. The topics
that you want to write about are always
going to perform well, but you just need
to find out the right way to promote
them. Does that make sense? Usually, a
fast track is always telling stories and
always using a photo. Let's go back to
let's say me on my LinkedIn strategy.
What I realized is that I was playing
LinkedIn on hard mode because I was
trying to be really cool and not really
use any photos because I was like, I'm
too good for that. But then I realized
like LinkedIn is a social media platform
where you need to retain attention. A
fast way to retain attention fast is by
adding a graphic because what people
don't kind of see is that when you put a
graphic on your post, it takes over the
entire feed. And so that gives you more
time to win someone over and get them to
actually read your posts rather than
just doing texton content. So another
hack and hence why we're here in London
is to get as many photos as possible so
we can almost position you as a tech guy
doing tech guy things and also talking
about tech, right? Because people right
now need this extra validation that
you're not just doing the thing, but you
also are that thing. There's too many
LinkedIn personal branding experts right
now talking about personal branding with
10,000 followers or thousand followers.
But now, how do we get someone that has
a thousand followers but also is worth a
100,000 followers to look the part by
using the right content in the right
cues? Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, do you ever go through and
find a viral post and even though it's
not necessarily in your niche?
>> Yeah.
>> Do you then just copy say the formatting
or try and then relate it to one of your
four pillars?
>> Oh, 100%. So there's someone that I
really admire in the industry and his
name is Jake Ward. What Jake did that
broke LinkedIn two years ago and I
personally say this because I saw it he
wouldn't say it because he won't admit
it. Jake became the best technical
writer on LinkedIn which allowed many
people like myself understand how to
write technically. He [snorts] writes
about SEO. I write about marketing but
then I realized that he was breaking
down such complex topics in such depth
and so I copied it. So let's say this
one, the new SEO game if SEO search is a
real optimization. I don't know how to
do SEO in 2026. So I'll see this and
there's two things I can think. This
doesn't have anything to do with me, so
I can't copy it. Or I can be like, this
worked well. Let me reverse engineer
why. And so I'll take this and I'll be
like, okay, how can I break down
LinkedIn marketing or personal branding
in 2026 and do it exactly how he's doing
it? So what levels can I actually break
down? They don't need to be six like he
has here, seven. It can be three. But if
we just do it in micro steps like he's
broken it down, then I know I can
potentially get a similar result. So you
can do that as well. Whenever I don't
have any information about any client, I
just go and look till the ends of the ad
for any blogs, any content, any YouTube
stuff that I can take and then
immediately just use context. So context
is Jake's post because it's giving us
the the winning format. And then proof
that you've done something similar from
YouTube, blogs, you can either even use
your SOPs, whatever. Then we're going to
add it here. So, write me a post on my
strategy to scale B2B SAS Zaga. Would
you say good?
>> Here's some info. So, this removes all
the friction between finding the idea,
finding what you want to write about,
finding the best hook to talk about, and
then it's just the final draft is done
for you in 2 seconds or less. It's 80%
done. Obviously, you need to go back and
shift things, but that's exactly how
I've been doing it manually this entire
time, and that's how Jake did it
manually this entire time. But now, you
can do it in 2 seconds. Now the last
thing that I want to add before we wrap
up is that the images play a really big
part on this. So whenever people use AI
and even if it's charged etc. Where
people fail in the execution is that
they'll try and copy a viral post but
they won't copy it correctly. They won't
emulate it. You need to emulate from the
structure the hook the formatting uh
even the CTA but also the image that
you're using. So obviously you and I
can't make this right now right? But
what can we do in less than an hour
today or like whatever time allocation
we have to write a post. We can go on
Canva. We can try and make something
similar. We can add a photo of us
working. So we can just add that. And
then maybe your SEO strategy is on the
screen. So we always want to give
context. One person that does this very
well is Richard Moore. He has this
strategy where he doesn't really use
infographics, but he always use candid
photos of himself which positions him as
an authority always because he's always
speaking. He's always in a suit. So he's
sort of like telling people who he is
without that. So for you it would be
like you looking like a B2B SAS nerd and
in your laptop because that's exactly
what your ideal client and someone
looking for you wants to see. You being
yourself. That's pretty much it. We walk
through actually understand how to build
your positioning, what strategy is
better for you, how to build it, the
type of post that you need to write and
then actually writing the final post in
seconds. Do you have any questions? How
do I remain authentic and make sure that
it always sound like me?
>> So when we built your content pillars at
the start and even your strategy, we
focused a lot on your story and what you
specifically educate on and your social
proof, right? That is the main thing
that will keep you authentic and what is
going to pull people to you. So when
we're using AI, when we're emulating
other people's content, when we're using
people's swipe files, your content won't
always sound like them as long as you
prompt it, right? So even the outputs
that we had for AI content earlier, they
sound like you because we gave a context
about you. And that's how we kind of
like beat that from being just generic
AI fluff that Chad GPT writes. This is
what makes tools like Cleo so different.
And also the tool is basically built on
you. So when you are on boarded onto the
platform, you already know this, but for
people watching this, we know the about
you, your story, etc. Which means that
every single time we create content, it
will always be backed on your story in
your beliefs rather than just copy and
pasting the viral format. What we've
trained Cleo to do is follow formats,
but not the content, just the context
ideally. So that's how you stay
authentic and not a typical viral fluff
person on LinkedIn. Cool. Let's go. Come
first as viral post tomorrow. High five.