So, I deleted every single social media
platform besides one. And it ended up
turning $0 into a sixf figureure
business [music] in under 12 months. No
Instagram, no Facebook, no Tik Tok.
Everybody thinks that in order to build
a successful personal brand, you need to
be posting on every single platform. But
I made my first million dollars without
having thousands of followers on
Instagram, on Tik Tok, or even on
YouTube. And I also didn't even need to
post multiple times every single day
either. While common social media advice
will lead you to believe you need to
post on every single channel if you want
to build authority, get more sales, and
make more money this year, there [music]
is one platform that beats all of them.
The platform is LinkedIn. And this is
the biggest cheat code to building a
profitable online presence. Because
right now, we are still incredibly early
into the platform's true potential.
Attention is completely underpriced on
LinkedIn. Even three years later, after
I made my first post, if I lost
everything, I'd rebuild it all using
LinkedIn. I've got 300,000 followers on
the platform, built three six and seven
figure businesses through it, and just
recently, my new business acquired over
a,000 new clients in under 3 months
because of it. So, when it comes to
LinkedIn, I don't just know the theory.
[music] I know the best strategy to
build and grow your personal brand today
without burning [music] out while doing
it. Now, just like in any other
platform, there are three different
shapes of growth that determine one
success. The first is what I call steady
growth. This is consistent and somewhat
predictable growth where you gain
followers at a steady rate over time.
It's reliable, but it's slow. The second
graph is exponential growth. This is the
hockey stick everybody talks about. You
start slow, then something clicks and
you explode. This is exactly what
happened to me when I found my content
market fit for LinkedIn. And the third
one is what I call the identity crisis
growth pattern. You grow, then you pivot
your niche, then you lose momentum, then
you get stuck, and then you try and grow
again in a different direction. And this
takes the longest because you're
essentially starting over every single
time you change direction. In all three
graphs though, there are specific
moments where fast growth becomes
predictable. These are what I call the
inflection points. And hitting these
inflection points isn't about posting
more. And it's not about doing things by
brute force either, especially when
you're trying to become a thought leader
or a respected authority or a business
owner who sells and not just create
content. This happens when you decide to
focus on one thing rather than many and
make it your purpose to make it work in
your niche. And in this video, I'm going
to be showing you the four steps it
takes to achieve this. Now, above all
LinkedIn growth tactics, you want to pay
attention to this specific one because
after running this playbook myself and
for thousands of clients and students,
helping them grow and scale their
personal brands and online businesses,
it's proven to work. But before I reveal
those four steps, you need to understand
the economics of attention. This is what
is called attention arbitrage. Every
social media platform has a supply and
demand curve for attention. For example,
Instagram has a massive supply. Millions
of creators posting consistently, but
LinkedIn has a massive demand. 1 billion
users consuming content, but almost none
of them supply any of it. When demand is
high and supply is low, prices go up. In
this case, the price is how much
attention you get for your effort. On
LinkedIn, the price is massively in your
favor. Right now on LinkedIn, attention
is massively underpriced. You can reach
10,000 qualified ideal clients with a
single post that takes you 20 minutes to
write. But if you try doing this on
Instagram or Facebook without spending
thousands on ads, you probably get
nowhere. In all graphs above though, the
moment things hit an inflection point,
you start maximizing your performance,
giving you exponential returns on every
minute you invest on the platform. One
post becomes 10 clients. One client
becomes a $50,000 revenue stream. And
that's the power of attention arbitrage.
And if you want to start winning on
LinkedIn, you need to nail the four
steps to get ahead. All steps that I'm
about to show you are incredibly easy to
nail if you do them right. And I'm going
to show you exactly how to do it as a
beginner or an intermediate trying to
start today. So step number one is
authority positioning. Everyone talks
about LinkedIn profile optimization, but
rarely anyone really explains its
importance. But now more than ever,
based on recent LinkedIn algorithm
shifts, this is crucial. Profiles today
that feel optimized actually miss the
spot. They're not niched or relevant
enough, meaning that the algorithm
doesn't know where to place you or who
to show you to. But there are people
that have actually nailed this for us.
So you can actually see how it works.
People like Justin Walsh or mega niche
down creators like Daniel here. Their
headlines, their banners, and their
content across the board outline their
specific niche that they serve and how
they actually help. The most followed
personal brands on LinkedIn aren't
trying to be everything for everyone.
They stay in one lane. This essentially
makes it easier for an audience to
conceptualize who you are and what you
do faster than if you're posting seven
times a week and all posts are about
different things and angles. This is a
trap you need to escape immediately.
Because here's what most people don't
understand about positioning. The human
brain can only hold up about seven
pieces of information at any given time.
When someone lands on your profile,
they're also making a split-second
decision about whether you're worth
their attention or not. If your headline
says marketing expert and your banner
talks about productivity and your posts
are about everything from crypto to
cooking to business, all you're doing
here is not being relatable or
authentic. You're just overwhelming your
new audience that's trying to actually
find you and buy from you. They can't
categorize you, so they ignore you and
go to your competitors. But then on the
other hand, when someone like Justin
Welsh shows up, it is crystal clear that
solopreneurship is his thing. That's it.
One lane executed flawlessly.
Essentially, what I'm trying to say here
is that our brains categorize everything
into mental folders. The clearer you
are, the easier is for people to
remember you and what you do and how you
help and how to refer you, etc., etc.
This is how you avoid the what do you do
by the way question after posting for
months, which happens way more than you
think. And just before you tell me, oh
wait, Lara, but aren't the big creators
the niche of one and big creators don't
actually do that and they are the niche.
Well, are they really? Steven Bartlett
is always talking about
entrepreneurship. Justin Welsh is always
talking about soloreneurship. And even
if you follow me on LinkedIn, you follow
me to understand how to make your
content work. And yes, our content for
big creators might be broader, but we
are still in one lane and so should you.
And listen, don't just take this from
me. Recent content and articles across
LinkedIn employees and their own
engineering department outline this
exact same thing. These posts and
articles are highlighting the increasing
importance of domain expertise rather
than broad and vague variety. Now in
practice, this is what you should be
doing right now. Fix your headline, fix
your banner and your featured section.
All of these should be related to your
niche, your skill and your outcome. Your
headline needs to be more than CEO or
founder of or freelancer doing X thing.
Instead, be painfully obvious about the
problem that you fix and how you do it.
Let me explain. So, I'm showing my
screen right now and I'm going to show
you the best headlines and banners I've
seen recently. So, firstly, we have
Daniel. I've shouted him out in the
channel before. He's one of my favorites
because he's so specific and painfully
obvious about what he does, who he does
it for, and also his social proof is
insane. So, let's read it. Million-doll
email marketing prompts, tactics, and
strategies for seven and eight figure
founders. So, immediately he
disqualifies everyone else that he
doesn't want to work with. He's saying
what he does, million-doll email
marketing, that's it. And then after he
states the problem that he fixes and who
he does it for and how, he then shows
some social proof to like add to his
prestige and positioning. So people read
that and then have something to be like,
"Oh, okay. This is legit." And this is
exactly how you escape this sea of sness
that everyone seems to be in on LinkedIn
because everybody has a similar job.
Like you're either CEO, you're a
marketer, you're a consultant, you're a
agency owner, you're like a founder,
whatever. And just by saying that, it's
not going to be enough. So, you need to
be showing proof. And Daniel killed it
right here. And then on his banner, it's
very obvious, very clean as well, very
easy to understand. So, learn from him
and follow him because he is the best.
And I absolutely love Daniel. All right.
Now, and also his social proof is
insane. So, let's read it. Million
dollar email market, 571 video ads for
B2B companies and counting. So, this is
brilliant because immediately he tells
you exactly how much work he's done,
what the work is, and who he does it
for, but in a more casual way that is
not overwhelming, that it doesn't look
templatized, and it's actually quite
approachable rather than the typical
templatized. I do this for this person
doing it's just like the template is is
gone. Stop it. Like, this is very new
and I recommend it. Also, we need to pay
attention to the banner. The banner here
is key. He's showing social proof. So,
he's showing all of the companies that
he's worked with and even a fivestar
review, which makes people that come to
his profile more likely to actually
proceed to book a call with him or at
least continue browsing his profile
because he's borrowing authority from
all of these companies. He's stating
that he's done the work before and he's
not just starting and a freelancer. And
by saying B2B companies, he's also
categorizing himself in like a specific
niche. So the people that are companies
on LinkedIn, B2B companies, this is this
is the best um they come to him in
instead of anyone that's just doing
broad social media video marketing
agencies, right? So this is a unique
selling point for him that he's
utilizing incredibly well and also the
rest high production B2B video ads
without the agency marker. So again,
making it clear what he does, who he
does it for, and what is his unique
selling point. Amazing stuff. Connor,
don't know him. Seems like a great guy.
Third, I want to show Kate. This is
slightly different to what I outlined,
but it still follows the same
principles. So, growth advisor ex Maro,
founder at Growth Makes, speaker and
creator PLG activation UX. And what
she's essentially doing here is that
she's borrowing credibility from Maro.
And I assume that her new business has
something to do with what she's done for
them. So then, whoever knows Maro, the
company, will be likely to also want
what she sells. And therefore that's why
she's stating it in her headline because
it is easier to categorize her as a
growth advisor for a company like Mo
which is like a software. So then her
ideal customer knowing Maro they would
want to work with her for everything
that has to do with growth in a company
like that. So it is making it easier for
her less words very straight to the
point. And then on top of that, she's
saying that she's also a founder of her
own company and also a speaker and
creator, increasing her chances of being
categorized for many different things,
but still within the same niche. Okay.
And then number four, Michael Faster, AI
customer service agency for your B2C
business. Again, super clear what he
does, who he does it for, and how. And
also stating again co-founder YC,
Cambridge, etc. So again, borrowing
credibility, positioning himself as one
of the best because if he studied at
Cambridge, if he's a co-founder, if he
got into YC, those things indicate a
specific type of persona and the type of
person that he'd also be willing to work
for work with and the type of person
that he's likely to attract because of
all of these accolades. So it is
important for you to think about it like
this. It doesn't need to follow a
specific template. You just need to
follow the results, the specificity, and
how quickly can you get to the point.
So, I've shown you four different types
of ways of doing it. Please just pick
one and run with it until you feel like
you need to change it. Okay? All of this
advice also goes for your banner, your
feature section, and this is where you
get to show proof that you can do what
you are claiming that you can do in a
frictionless way for people to buy from
you. Now, with this, I've just made it
incredibly clear and easy for you to get
going today. Like today. Once this is
done though, in order to then build your
personal brand on LinkedIn, we need step
number two, which is using content as a
trust accelerator. The tactical way to
build this fast is to do it
strategically. And a proven method for
this is what I called the 4321 LinkedIn
content playbook. Its aim is to remove
all friction points from your writing
and get you from idea to posted content
instantly. Here's how it works. The four
is the number of posts you need to post
per week in order to hit that scape
velocity moment. The three is for the
three different content types you need
to post to obtain it fast. The two is
for the two types of audiences we need
to be talking to at all times. And the
one is for the one key thing that gets
you sales off the back of your personal
brand. But I'll get into that at the end
of the video. And trust me, you want to
keep on watching for this. All right.
Now, content frequency is out of the
way. You know that you need to post four
times a week with three types of content
themes and talk to two different types
of audiences. That's crystal clear. Now,
let's talk about what matters. What to
post about. You want to focus on the
content that will get you visibility
fast. And today on LinkedIn, you can
achieve it by educating, storytelling,
and using content that meets a large
TAM, a total addressable market. So, if
you're an agency owner, for example, the
content breakdown would look something
like this. Monday, you educate on the
newest content strategy to get more
leads using cold outreach and using it
as a step by step. Then on Wednesday,
you storytell on how you work remotely
while being an agency owner scaling to,
let's say, $10,000 a month. Then on
Thursday, we're going to be doing total
addressable market content. So here you
want to talk about current news and talk
about it in your own way, such as like
Open AI launching a new update and how
agencies can use it to reduce hiring
costs. And now lastly, for the fourth,
on Sunday, you can pick either of the
three and choose which one you have.
something else to write about on that
week. It could be a story of a recent
event you went to. It could be an
educational post on a system that
recently worked for a client or another
update on how X company just did
something cool and how you can adapt it
to your own niche and how they did
something that your clients may also
want to be doing. For example, off the
top of my head, Claude just launched a
crazy new update for growth marketers
and how they manage marketing at Claude.
So, they released that sheet. If you
take that sheet that just came out
literally yesterday and you talk about
it in your own terms and how your team
is planning to implement it, then you
are able to maximize and capitalize on
this new trend. You're also being one of
the first people to talk about it in
your niche and for your niche. And as a
result, you become an authority. You
become trusted and you are consistently
tapping into what's going on in the
culture in your niche, which is
incredibly important. Sahil Bloom
actually hopped on that trend this
morning and it blew up. So this is proof
that it works. You just need to be fast
and you need to understand how to make
any news relevant to your audience in
your own words and how to link it back
to your business or your expertise and
how to make it give you more authority.
That's it. And to make this even easier
for you to start doing, here are some
examples of posts that meet each of
these criteria so you can literally see
how they look like in practice. So you
can potentially try and emulate them
too. Nailing content in this way is
essentially the way to win the content
game on LinkedIn in 2026. And by the
way, if you think you might struggle
with ideiation and writing, I built a
tool to help you solve this as well.
It's called Cleo, which acts as a
writing partner for you. You can ask
Cleo to write you an educational post, a
storytelling post, or even a total
addressable market post based on your
brand and your business, and it will
automatically write it for you using the
exact patterns and frameworks used by
the best creators on the platform. We've
got over a thousand users on it and they
are loving it. And if you want to give
it a go, the link is in the description
for you to try it. All right. Now, like
I mentioned, there are two audiences you
want to target. your ideal client
persona and your ideal follower persona.
Most people only think about their ideal
client, but you need to think of
followers too because they can refer you
to your ideal clients in the future. The
goal here is for you to understand why
storytelling and broad education content
is needed to succeed. The reality is
that not all users of the platform will
be your clients. This is a fact.
However, creating content that targets a
broader demographic will get you closer
each time. So, instead of focusing on
specific content targeted to a specific
type of client, let's say, here's how to
build an email list of qualified
prospects, it can actually say, "My
business gets 10 leads every single
week, and I don't even need to do any
outbound. Here's exactly how I do it."
What's happening here is that these
posts are still niche in the topic, i.e.
business building and sales, but it's
not too niched down where you're saying,
"If you're a B2B business owner making
over 10 million a year, here's how to do
X." That right there segments your
audience way too much and completely
alienates those who may be able to work
with you in the future or may have
someone to refer you to, but because
you're being too niche, they may think,
"Oh, they don't work with this person
and they don't work with that person and
they don't do this thing." But you do.
But because you're trying to be so
specific, you're kind of like ruining
your own growth, thinking that you're
actually helping it. This is not the
case. People again, they segment things
in their head. So make it easier for
them to place you in a box that's big
enough for them to conceptualize what
you do so they can refer you to people.
They can follow you. They can still keep
up with you even if they're not buying
right now. In short, the entry point to
your content needs to be accessible
enough so a firsttime founder can learn
from it. A marketing manager can share
it with their CEO and a freelancer can
apply the principles at their scale.
This is why storytelling and broader
educational content works. It keeps you
in your niche without locking people
out. Because if you're watching this,
your goal truly is to have content that
attracts clients and builds an audience
that brings clients to you every single
day. Now, let's talk about the greatest
growth hack of all. Listen, up until
this point, I've given you the strategy,
content playbook, and ways to position
yourself. But this will fail if you
don't do this one thing, which is step
number three, engagement. Because here's
what most people get wrong. They think
posting is the hard part. It's not. The
hard part is what happens after you hit
publish. See, [music] there's this
common thing called posting and ghosting
where you drop your content and then
disappear. And this is where LinkedIn
differs from most platforms. You can't
just post and let the algorithm do its
thing. Essentially, LinkedIn works on a
network basis where your network must
see the post and engage with it in order
for it to be distributed further. So, if
you can't be there to engage, don't post
at all during that day. Otherwise, to
me, you are wasting a perfectly written
post and sending it into the ether
without a strategy for it to be seen.
Comments on LinkedIn are the ultimate
growth hack. You literally get to
somewhat manipulate how much reach your
post gets. All top LinkedIn native
creators spend at least an hour
engaging. So they engage 20 minutes
before their post goes live with their
feed, their industry peers, and even
they go and reply to comments on their
own post from the day before. Then once
the post is live, you want to aim to
reply to every comment within the first
30 minutes. All of this in ways
activates your post. You're literally
increasing the number of comments per
minute the more you engage. This in
psychological terms is the law of
reciprocity at scale. But here's where
it gets interesting. There's actually a
formula for this. One of my good
friends, Yasmin Alec, coined it the 1 +
three rule. Never comment on one post
just once. And then number two is leave
three more replies to other people's
comments. And as a result, you get 4x
more profile views every single day. And
if you think about it, it actually makes
sense. Every time you engage with
someone else's comments, their network
sees you. And that's the real game. And
this is not just about the person
commenting. It is about the person with
the network that you currently don't
have, but you want to have. So when
you're commenting, you're not just
talking to one person. You're talking to
their entire LinkedIn network. And the
numbers prove this works. Top creators
like myself are doing over a thousand
comments per week. Not posts, comments.
Okay? And the entire reason for this is
simple. While your posts might reach
your audience once, your comments put
you in front of new audiences all day
long. That's how you turn engagement
into a client acquisition machine. I've
acquired clients from comments. I've
gotten more likes in comments than some
posts. And that is the thing with
visibility. It can be acquired in
multiple ways within the same channel.
You just need to be strategic about it.
You don't need to post everywhere. You
just need to know how to post and then
how to maximize your posting efficiency
by doing all these micro steps that I'm
showing you. Now, if this is confusing,
let me show you how I do it. All right.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to
go to my LinkedIn feed. Although, it's
kind of late, so no new post yet, but
ideally, I'd be doing this at around
12:00 p.m. UK time. So, scrolling
through my LinkedIn feed, I'm going to
try and find a post that I actually want
to engage with that is relevant to my
network as well to maximize the
similarities between networks and I'm
going to comment. So, I like this post
by Toby. Toby is a great entrepreneur.
He's a killer in the industry. So, we
have a lot of similarities because we're
in the same industry as well. So, this
post is relevant to my audience, is
relevant for me, and it potentially has
the right network that I'd like to tap
into. So, I'm going to write a comment
basically. So, let me just read this.
Cool. So that's my main comment. Uh I'm
not really going to try and overdo it
because it's a story. So then I'm going
to kind of like look for people like my
friend Jolon here. So this is just very
me. Don't copy the king unless you do
say it. And then I'll scroll for like
another 2 minutes and then find
something relevant. Right now the
comments here are a bit too AIish. But
if there was like a a conversation I'd
try and tap in. Like this for example.
This is a cool one. So, I'll probably
refly this one as well.
This is how I do it to a high level.
Although, if I was just starting from
Sarah, I'd probably be a little bit more
tactical with the post I choose. So,
I'll be looking for educational posts
that I can tap into. So, let's say
something about writing specifically and
then I can comment on the framework or
like my point of view, etc. So then I
can also tap into that audience. But
essentially, this is how it's done. I
think people over complicate commenting
and they overthink it and they they try
to use AI. Be human, be genuine, and
then try and give as much value as you
can, or at least try to drop in a joke.
It doesn't hurt. No one really cares if
the comment was bad, and it's fine.
Like, it really is a win-win situation.
So, don't play a losing game and start
commenting more. And by the way, this
exact commenting strategy made me
$10,000 passively, literally. And it's
also recently gotten me to speak at
different conferences because I
commented on the my own posts about it
and how I wanted to speak at X
University and give an ex talk at X
place and travel to LA and New York.
Then people saw it and they reached out
to me with this opportunity. I made
$10,000 from my comments underneath my
post dropping a link to a digital
product I had up on Gum Road and it made
money passively like literally. And the
speaking conference invite that I'm
talking about came from me literally
asking what conferences do you want me
to speak at in this year in 2026. All of
this just from comments and not posts.
And that is why I'm literally honing in
on the importance of this because it is
an untapped opportunity and people are
doing it wrong. Don't use AI comments.
Try and do it yourself. Just schedule in
30 minutes of your day and you'll be
good to go. I promise to you if you do
it for 30 days, 60 days or even 90 days,
you will see an increase in your
engagement. uh you'll be the algorithm
claims that you know it shadowbounds you
and you'll actually see what consistent
LinkedIn growth actually looks like. All
right, now rant this over but look
everything I've shown you up until this
point is worthless if you can't convert
your attention into revenue. And here's
where most people fail. They try to sell
directly from their LinkedIn posts. And
that's not how it works. LinkedIn is a
relationship platform. People buy from
people they know, like, and trust. So,
your content's job isn't to sell, it's
to build a relationship. And so, in
order to monetize your personal brand,
here's the system I use. I call it the
revenue bridge, which is the last step
here. The bridge starts with your
content, then moves onto your profile,
and then leads to a lead magnet where
you then convert them into email
subscribers, and then lead to sales.
Your content attracts the right people.
Your optimized profile converts them
into followers and then your lead magnet
captures their email and your email list
is where you actually make most of your
sales. 70 to 80% of my own revenue comes
from email, not LinkedIn directly.
LinkedIn is the top of the funnel. Email
is where the money is made. So, if I had
to make money today from my personal
brand, I'd create insanely good content
with the 4321 strategy I just showed
you, then do the one lead magnet post a
week, which is the one missing part from
the blueprint I showed you above, and
then have a permanent lead magnet that
leaves on your profile for anyone to
download at any given time. And for
those wondering what my lead magnets
have looked like in the past, here are
the top three performing lead magnets
I've done over the last year on screen
right now for you to see how easy and
simple they actually are. Some of them
took a few days to build and some of
them just a few hours and many under 30
minutes. It doesn't need to be this
hyperdesign thing that lives on a pitch
deck with Canva things etc. It's like
super high tech. It doesn't need to be
like that. As long as it's solving one
key problem for one key person
incredibly well, that's it. The
conversion to clients comes from the
emails you then send to that list, not
just from the lead magnet itself. And
then when you build a decentsized email
list, email them weekly and offer them
something whenever you need to launch or
when you have something to sell or a new
opening for your agency or or a new spot
for your coaching or something else.
That slightly elongated strategy
converts clients better than when you
just post content and pray for
conversion. All right, but as many of
you know, I could go on about email for
literally forever, but if you want me to
make an indepth video on the strategies
we specifically used for email, then
drop a comment below so I can finally
nerd out about email on YouTube and show
you my best performing emails so you can
copy them as well. Now, my friends, that
was the full four-step playbook I'd use
all over again if I was a creator, a
founder, or a business owner. So, the
TLDDR is step number one was authority
positioning. So, you need to fix your
profile to be painfully obvious about
the problems you solve for one person.
Step number two was following the 4321
content strategy I made. Using your new
positioning, make sure your content
matches exactly that without burning you
out and building your content to a level
where it is undeniably good. Step number
three is strategic engagement. So spend
an hour daily engaging before and after
you post. Use the oneplus 3 rule to
maximize your visibility and turn
comments into a client acquisition
machine. Then step number four is the
revenue bridge I just talked about.
convert attention to revenue through
content, then profile, then a lead
magnet to email, and then sales.
Remember, 70 to 80% of my revenue comes
from email, not LinkedIn directly. And
as you can see, this is in theory. It's
what has taken me from zero to 300,000
followers and built me multiple
businesses and a cult-like following.
Before we finish, what I need you to
understand, if you made it this far into
the video, is that we are living through
an insane time in LinkedIn history right
now. [music] While everyone else is
chasing Tik Tok trends and Instagram
algorithms, there is a platform with 1
billion users where most of those users
aren't creating any content. There is a
platform where attention is massively
underpriced, where you can build a
sevenf figureure business with four
posts per week. But this window won't
stay open forever. I've been in this
game long enough to see opportunities
come and go. I saw it early with
YouTube. I saw it with Instagram and now
I'm seeing it right now with LinkedIn.
The people who act fast will build
generational wealth. And the people who
wait until the best time and the
algorithm hack and whatever the
algorithm changes to their advantage
will be wondering what if. So my friend,
I have a question for you. What is it
going to be? Are you going to be
spreading yourself very thin, posting on
every single platform, trying to post 10
times a day and not getting anywhere? or
are you going to focus, go deep, and
then dominate the one platform that
actually matters for business? [music]
The choice is yours, but choose fast.
And if you want to learn the ultimate
monetization strategy I used and how to
figure out what to sell and how to
position an offer, then watch this video
right here where I break it down step by
step. See you.