Over the last two years, I've posted
over 2,000 pieces of viral content
across social media. Consistently have
gone viral on LinkedIn, have done the
same on YouTube, Instagram, and even
Twitter. And just this week, I've gained
over 10,000 followers and millions of
views while sending weekly emails to my
newsletter that consistently get opened.
All of this while running and building
three profitable businesses. See, social
media content is a cheat code for all of
your businesses to succeed. Content is
no longer optional anymore. It's the
cost of entry. And if you have a
business, you need to get serious about
content as well. Because even if you
hate it, your customers are on these
platforms right now deciding who to
trust and buy from. Your next client is
already online. The only question is,
will they find you or your competitors
first? And look, I don't just say this.
I know this. I've crossed seven figures
in revenue. I've gotten millions of
impressions and thousands of clients.
[music] And while everybody's talking
about content and building your personal
brand, no one is really telling you why
this even is the case. But even Google
has this rule that backs his entire
theory for personal branding and content
up. And they called it their 7114 rule
where people need to see you seven times
through 11 different touch points across
four different platforms before they
trust you enough to buy. And as someone
that's gone from just LinkedIn to
posting consistently on YouTube,
Instagram, Twitter, and even newsletter,
I'm about to lay out the exact strategy
I've used to nail all of this. I want to
be clear though, this isn't going to be
a copype system or tactic or the perfect
repurposing system that you can use to
blow up today. Because right here with
this thought is where most people go
wrong with repurposing. And it's not
really their fault. I mean, there's
literally apps telling you that you can
turn one video into 10 viral clips in
seconds. And there's endless YouTube
videos showing you how to turn a
newsletter into a YouTube script and
then into 20 pieces of viral content.
And sure, this can work, but it doesn't
really work for everyone. What I'm about
to show you is the intentional strategy
I've used to build a wellpositioned
brand across all social media platforms
that then allows me to get clients
international speaking opportunities
while giving me just enough microniche
fame to walk around London and get
recognized once a month. The way I like
to think about all of this is in terms
of intention and mastery. Now, my number
one rule for content was to master one
platform and dominate all of them later.
Here's my secret. You need to dominate
one platform first, then earn the right
to go omni channel. See, most people
struggle to go omni channel, be visible
across platforms, and be successful
because they've not mastered their
positioning on one. They don't know what
content resonates. They don't know what
topics land better, and they don't know
what ideas they should be talking about
every single time on their content. And
this is why even the brightest
entrepreneurs fail. It's a lack of
focus. So the key before repurposing is
to dominate one platform. To do this
well, you need to use what I call my
niche down, niche up, and then go broad
strategy. Let's say that you want to
talk about business, but that honestly
is way too broad. So when you go into
the business or even entrepreneurship
space, your total addressable market is
high and so is your pool of competition.
You'll never be able to truly test your
content and your ability to create
because your competition is way too
high. So instead, if you want to make
things easier for you and start
dominating something, you need to find
where you're a specialist in business.
This could be email marketing, this
could be high ticket sales, or it could
be even just freelancing. [music] That's
your micro niche. Less competition and
more space for specificity. Then once
you have that one thing, you can lay out
a content strategy of weekly posts that
help you to test different hypothesis
you might have about content. So for
example across different platforms we
have different types of content right
educational entertaining storytelling
and we also have different formats like
we have videos we have carousels we have
images we have infographics but then you
first need to test every single angle
and combination to then find your
outlier content. Let me give you an
example. Let's say you're someone called
John and he is in high ticket sales. On
Monday he posted a carousel on the best
scripts to use. Then on Wednesday, he
posted a video of him using the best
scripts to use. Then on Friday, he
posted a story on how one sales script
took him from zero to $20,000 a month.
Now, after a week of testing, John
noticed that his story post performed
better than most. So then he can use
that to then follow the same format and
double down using similar angles. And
then with that one single outlier story
post, he can then use that to turn into
five different angles with a similar
storytelling backing to use across that
month. Now John can also try the same
context or way of writing that
potentially resonated and turn it again
into a carousel then an infographic and
see how this performs for him. And now
after a few weeks John now has a content
machine not just based on ideas and
hooks but on validation of formats
angles and resonance. [music]
And so after around 30 days John would
have something around 12 tested and
validated pieces of content. He's got
validated formats that work for him.
validated ideas and has done the testing
required to then repurpose onto other
platforms. And the most exciting part is
that within this process of the 30 days
that he's been testing new content, he
then starts to become a micro authority
in his niche. When I started writing on
LinkedIn, I did the exact same thing.
Then I niched up and then I went broad
with productivity hacks, etc. Once I
found validation and people started
trusting me with other advice. Now,
something that you may not notice is
that people that you follow or aspire to
be like in this space, whether they're
business owners or entrepreneurs like
Alice Hermosi, Cody Sanchez, Imangaji,
they all did the exact same thing. They
started with one platform first. They
focused on their micro niche to dominate
and then they went broad. So trust me
when I say this, this works when you
master one platform first because then
the rest becomes easier. So now when it
comes to redistribution, it's not just
about reposting your content that
perform well across platforms and it
just begins to become a seamless
process. Here's what I mean. One
validated or even viral post can be
turned into a YouTube script outline, a
newsletter outline, a Twitter thread, a
single tweet, a short form Instagram
script, a part of a YouTube video, a
line for a podcast that you can use and
then cut it into a short clip. You can
also use your viral content to use as
answers on a podcast and then cut it
into a short form clip that you can then
post onto social media. Now, I know this
might sound overwhelming, but I actually
found the key [music] and the best tool
to use when you're trying to do all of
this at once. But as a last reminder,
you need to have dominated at least one
platform first because the key to
repurposing is truly understanding that
your message is resonating across one
single platform because then that is a
test that we are using to then share
across all the social media platforms.
Now to do this, I didn't use Chad GBT or
Claude and the reason for this is
simple. See those tools are great if you
just want quick answers or a random
idea. But if you're a content creator or
a business owner who actually cares
about your brand, your tone and your
voice, your office, and everything else
like your positioning, the post written
just by using Chad GBT or Claude fall
apart quite fast. These tools start
hallucinating or forget what performed
well for you in the past. They do not
actually know the landscape of the
platform that you're trying to grow on.
And they also don't know your audience
or what your best content has been in
the past. So you end up copy pasting
from LinkedIn, YouTube, email into 10
different chats, repeating the same
context over and over and over and then
hoping that one of the outputs will
sound like you eventually. So I
personally needed something that
actually understood my world, the
content world. So the entire way I've
been using it before I move on to the
rest of the explainer video on how do I
repurpose a lot of content is that with
Poppy I've just been able to build a
different ecosystem with my favorite
YouTube videos that I've created
personally my favorite YouTube videos
that I've watched before a space for my
office that I can copy paste from all
the places and everything is in the
exact same board where I can visually
see them at all time instead of having
to repeat myself every single time I
start a new chat on Chad GBT or on
Claude. And then with Poppy, my favorite
part is that because it has different
chats and you know boxes, you can see it
almost like in a myro style board. I
have YouTube videos, I have LinkedIn
post, I have Twitter threads, I have you
know my newsletters, I have past scripts
and my favorite YouTubers etc. And then
it all then connects into a main chart
where it's almost like a brain that
knows exactly how I speak, how I
actually want to sound like, and what I
want to do, what's performed well for
me, what's performed well for others
based on what I said to it. which then
allows me to create way better content
without needing to repeat myself at all
times, having pre-validated versions of
content that I like, that I've watched,
that I want to sound like, and then use
it to my advantage, helping me write
better and faster YouTube scripts,
Instagram posts, newsletters, and so on.
So, let me show you exactly how I use it
in practice. This is one of my older
Poppy boards. I built this when I was
going all in on YouTube earlier on this
year. then I quite obviously but then we
don't talk about that and then also
newsletters at the same time up here
what you can see is a chat connected to
all my previous YouTube videos so you
can actually understand my tone of voice
my flow the frameworks that I use what I
usually offer what I usually talk about
again an entire breakdown of exactly
everything that I've ever talked about
in my YouTube content so I don't need to
repeat myself which is important cuz
like I want to do stuff fast. Then on
top of that in another box I connected
my top performing podcasts, my top
performing YouTube videos, my best
emails etc. and even webinar angles that
I liked. And then by connecting a few
other things like my favorite YouTube
videos, a YouTube video that I really
really enjoyed the flow of, a YouTube
video that I really like the structure
of, another YouTube video that the
thumbnail was amazing or the title was
really catchy. So I have a combination
of all of these things that understand
my tone of voice, understand my
language, and understand what I aspire
to sound and look like and feel like
with my scripting. And then from this
mini process using the AI chat, etc.,
and given it different prompts, I've
actually been able to script YouTube
videos that have gotten tens of
thousands of views. And it was all
pulled from the ideas I'd already tested
on podcasts, etc. [music]
And so by using this mega visual board,
I know that the output that its AI is
giving me is actually quite accurate and
it's giving me the ideas that are
actually going to work because it's
using data that I'm literally telling it
to use and I'm seeing it use it
specifically and that's what's made
scripting a lot better for me and faster
because I know that it's using the
things that I needed to use instead of
me having to copy paste many many things
in different chats and it never working
like I said at the start. Now, to make
this super practical for you, I'm going
to open up a fresh simplified board so
you can see me use its powers live and
you don't have to waste your time. So,
let's get into it. All right, so I've
got my laptop out. I've got Poppy pulled
out and I'm going to show you how I turn
one LinkedIn post into a YouTube script,
then an email newsletter, then use it
for different Twitter posts, even
YouTube ads or Instagram ads, Instagram
posts, or whatever I wanted to do. So,
the first thing that we're going to do,
and this is the most important thing to
get the best tone of voice and ideas
that you already have and use them on
Poppy AI. This prompt I actually saw in
a different YouTube video by Ben Beta,
which completely changed my life. So,
I'm going to leave his video linked
below so you can also watch it as well.
So, this is the prompt. Based on all my
previous inputs and what you know about
me, my business, and my ideas, please
create a 20 to 60page PDF that can be
used to promote, market, and represent
my brand and values. The content should
draw from my business education and
experience, my current offers, and the
problems I solve. The topics that are
top of funnel and highly engaging for a
broad audience to increase virality.
This document should also serve as a
comprehensive asset, something that a
ghost writer could use as a foundation
to create posts, marketing material,
[music] and other brand content.
What I love about this prompt is that
you can then use it for everything else,
which I'll show in a different video.
But now, JAGBT is currently creating the
perfect SOP. So, you can use onto any AI
just like Poppy, and it actually will
write like you and it will sound like
you. So then whatever outputs you then
create, they will sound like you. Okay.
So then what I'm going to do is I'm
going to copy this. I'm going to go back
to Poppy. I'm going to pull out this
text button right here. I'm going to put
this here. And then and then I'm going
to title it SOP so we know exactly what
this is when we're referencing it. Now,
the second thing that you're going to do
is go onto the platform that you're
trying to master right now that you have
some either validation or even some
early virality that you can start
repurposing from. So, I personally went
to my LinkedIn. I looked at this post
that I wrote earlier in the month that
then became one of my most recent viral
LinkedIn videos on YouTube. Then, I'm
going to show you exactly how I scripted
that. So, I'm going to copy and paste
this post. I'm going to put it onto
Poppy. So once both are loaded, I'm just
going to connect it like this. I love
how visual this tool is. It almost
mimics my boards and charg. [music]
Oh, and by the way, I forgot to mention
when using Poppy, you can connect
different things like I'm doing right
here on the screen. LinkedIn posts,
YouTube videos, email scripts, Tik Tok
videos, and so on. Here's exactly how
I've used it previously to script all
the short and long form videos. And yes,
I'm a big fan of Callaway and
Immanangaji's videos. Don't judge me. I
am an internet kit after all. If you
like how this looks and want to make one
for yourself as well, then there's a
link in the description below for you to
try Poppy and get a discount. Now,
moving on. So, first I'm going to
validate that it understands the
information that I'm giving it, which is
the most important thing, and this is
why most people get AI wrong because
they don't test it first. So, based on
these two assets, tell me how I write
and my tone of voice. So, I'm just
testing to see if the information is
accurate and it's understanding it.
So, I've just quickly checked it and it
understands how I write, how I sound,
what my preferred frameworks are, the
topic that is at hand. So, what I'm
going to do now is please ba based on
the LinkedIn post, write me a 10 to 20
minutes long YouTube script using the
exact same title I used. So, I'm going
to go back and reference that. So, the
So, I'm just going to use that. We
already have a validated hook, so why
not reuse it somewhere else? And then
the key here is to be as specific as
possible again. So I'm going to add my
own preferences. So please make sure
that the video is educational,
that it has high retention tactics and
analogies with in it don't generate
outside
the content providers.
and add a mid roll subscribe CTI.
Now you can see Poppy has generated an
incredibly accurate and scripted
stepbystep video and even counting the
time that it will take you to say each
line. So here's my draft of this YouTube
video that I'm repurposing from a simple
LinkedIn post into a 10 to 20 minute
long YouTube video. And like I said, I
actually really did this using Poppy
last time. So, I'm going to leave the
video so you can check it out here so
you can see how it turned out at the
end. This was mostly 80% of the work
done for me. I then added my 20% that AI
doesn't know because it doesn't know my
own preferences or even examples that it
doesn't have access to. But this
literally saved me about 5 hours of
scripting and even ideating. So, then
we're going to move on to newsletter.
Please write me a
thousand word
long newsletter promoting the YouTube
video that we just created and posted.
Give me different headline variations
for highest open rates and use a story
lesson. Actionable advice
and PS method to make the email
engaging.
All right. So this prompt that I just
gave it is using my sleigh framework. So
sleigh is story lesson actionable piece
of advice and a U. This is proven and
tested to work for me and my clients
across different niches. So you can use
it as well. The entire point of writing
emails this way is that every single
email newsletter I ever write is in my
tone of voice starts with a story to
increase retention and make it seem like
I'm not selling anything or trying to
push anything. Then lead with a lesson
and actionable advice. So the users that
maybe already watched the video, that
don't need to watch it, that maybe are
already my clients also still get value
from my emails. And then I asked it to
include a CTA so then I can redirect
people into the YouTube video. So it
starts creating this content flywheel
that most people dream about having.
This is where it starts. All right. So
now we've gone from LinkedIn post to
YouTube script to then long form email
written already for you. Poppy has given
us about nine different headlines. I
think I ended up using this one. I'll
show the screenshot here. Now, I'm going
to be completely honest here. I don't
love how this has been written because
it doesn't have enough information of me
yet because this was a brand new
Marboard. If we use my old one, you'll
see like literally a entire storage of
all of my thoughts. But I don't want you
to see that. So, what I would do if I
what I did when I started from zero was
I copy pasted the final output of Poppy.
Then I chose what I liked. So let's say
let's do this.
So as you can see here, I've taken this
as inspiration and then just added my
two cents. So it's literally the same
thing just in my own words. So then
that's that done, which is usually the
hardest part for me, coming up with a
hook.
All right, so I just spent the last five
minutes editing the first draft. As you
can see, I made some minor changes and I
deleted big chunks of text that just
read too long or are irrelevant or
unnecessary because they are in the long
form video script. The purpose of this
email is to educate my audience, get
them excited about this new topic and
then get them to click on the long form
while still enjoying the text version of
it, which is this email. So what I did
was I technically just reformatted the
email so it reads better so it's
basically using visual formatting so
people can skim it and then I've added
some key lessons like this one. Here are
the three key rules that you should
follow in 2026. Here what it said here
was something like here's what you need
to do right now which I just wanted to
add more specificity. I kept the bullet
points exactly as they were. I kept
these and then I just added my own CTA
because the one that I came up with
wasn't really my in my tone of voice or
how I usually do things. And then I
again I just reformatted it. I left the
links as well. Then I added my own PS
because I only I I do them my own way
and I don't think I could ever replicate
them. But essentially this took me 5 to
10 minutes. Ideally for most people it
takes them 30 to an hour to do this. So
that's our newsletter done. ready to
send. Now, moving on to short form
videos like Instagram or Tik Tok. I'm
going to insert this prompt of the
puppy. Please turn this into a 60 to 90
second short form video script. And then
it's done amazingly well. I'm so
surprised. I just made the bullet
prediction of my career. After studying
for 30 days straight, I believe that 90%
of current creators will become
irrelevant in the next few months. And
here's why. Then it gives me the exact
topics I should be using. Um, it's added
even some visual cues for me to use,
which I've actually done in my short
form video on LinkedIn. And then I love
that it's done this. Uh, it's even added
a soft CTA. So, I broke down the exact
three rule system in my last video, link
in bio, adap or fade, your move. It's
added this power line at the end, which
makes it easy for someone to want to
rewatch again and feel good after
watching this video, which is something
most content creators don't mention. The
most important part about your short
phone videos is the hook and then the
last line that you use because then that
keeps them going or then it makes them
happy that they watch that video for the
last 60 seconds which then makes them
more likely to even share it, like it,
uh, follow you or subscribe to your
channel or whatever your platform is,
which is amazing. By the way, if you're
like me and don't know how to do short
form videos, you can add your favorite
short form videos onto Poppy and connect
the same board so you can get the
inspiration from those videos and give
you scripts in a similar tone and style.
Now, we're going to move on to Twitter.
So, I've asked it turn this into three
platitude short tweets. So, 90% of
LinkedIn creators will become irrelevant
in the next few months. The platform is
shifting to the expert content. Humble
brags are out. Depth is depth is in.
Adapt or fade. Nice. LinkedIn used to be
a networking event where everybody tried
to be the loudest. Now it's becoming a
university or electrical only experts
get a microphone. One client stopped
humble bragging started sharing insights
results 100% more reach. All right. So I
am actually going to use this and I'm
going to post it and then see how it
performs. So, I really like what it's
come up with, but I know that this is
not optimized for what my audience
personally likes. And this is because I
know what works because I'm on the
platform all day. So, what I'm going to
do is I'm going to copy paste the first
one and I'm going to edit it a little
bit to try and make it more my style and
what makes more sense for what the
Twitter algorithm is currently in demand
for.
Now, this is how most creators that use
AI actually use AI to write. As you can
see, this is a completely different idea
or tweet, but I've used the same context
to turn it into my own idea, which is
why most people that are using AI still
sound authentic because it still is
their own voice, their own idea, just
using AI to ideulate faster and then
turn something that would have taken
them 20 minutes again into something
that takes two seconds to change and
then post. Based on the first input,
write me
10 bullet points I can use for a podcast
answer. Okay. Now, lastly, and this is
actually quite important for me and it's
helped a lot with my speaking career, I
go to two podcasts a month at least. And
what I need to always have handy is
pre-thought answers that I can give so I
can sound eloquent, so I can, you know,
structure my thoughts well and so the
podcast makes sense and I don't have
long drawn out answers that bore
everyone. So when I write so much, I
already have thought about the answers,
but I need to have something in my notes
app that I can read beforehand so I can
be prepared for when the question arises
and I can give my best answer. So then I
can use that podcast to turn it into
short form content that performs well
because usually most podcast content
can't actually be clipped because the
person speaking isn't speaking in clips.
So this is how I've been able to master
it by using AI using my old content and
then turn it into bullet points that I
can read beforehand and I can use.
Actually this answer you'll see me use a
lot. Um, after 30 days of deep re
research on LinkedIn, I believe that 90%
of current creators will become
irrelevant within months. I say this a
lot. Um, I also go and say, "Oh, I've
analyzed over 3,000 posts this year.
Here's what I found," etc. So, this is a
cheat code for anyone that goes on
podcasts. And so, yeah, this is exactly
how I use Poppy AI every single week to
turn one post into different formats,
newsletters, Instagram posts, etc., and
save me a lot of time. I'm leaving the
link to Poppy AI in the description
below. I've literally just shotcuted
your content creation system across
multiple platforms. This took me years
to understand and I just gave you the
blueprint in under 10 minutes. So, if
you want to thank me, please, please,
please subscribe to this YouTube channel
so I can keep on delivering these secret
hacks to you every single week. Please.
Now, this was just the content part, but
here's the thing. Every platform has its
own unique mechanism for it to work. On
LinkedIn, just posting isn't enough. You
need to be in the comments engaging with
other people's content, building
relationships. The algorithm rewards
genuine engagement and professional
conversations. On Instagram, it's about
the visual story and consistency. You
need to show up on stories. You need to
engage with your audience through DMs.
You need to create content that stops
the scroll every single time. And then
on YouTube, it's all about watch time
and retention. The first 15 seconds of
your video need to be at the ultimate
and highest quality and then keep them
watching. And then on Twitter or X, it's
all about distribution. The more you
reply that, the better your content is,
the more the base that you actually
start. People with higher following
ratios will start finding you and engage
with you and then that will push you
into Twitter's algorithm. And then with
email, well, there's none of this back
and forth where you don't need to be
engaging or anything like that. And
that's why I love email so much. And I
could make an entire video on the best
engagement strategies for each that I've
noticed work best right now for maximum
results in the future. But the point is
when people say just post more content,
they're missing the entire [music]
point. It's not about posting more. It's
about nailing one platform first and
then dominating the rest. This is the
blueprint that I followed and it's
worked incredibly well. It's not made me
the most viral across platforms, but
it's made me the key person of influence
across all of them because honestly, you
don't need thousands of followers to
outperform your competition. You need
100 true fans. They will find your next
100 and then the next. And that, my
friend, is more valuable than a 100,000
random followers who scroll past your
content every single day. or even people
that don't remember you, your name, and
most importantly, your offer. So, here's
a tactical step by step that I want you
to follow right now. Pick your platform,
pick your micro niche, and start
testing. Stop trying to be everywhere
and start being the most useful in one
platform first. Now, ladies and
gentlemen, if that was useful, please
hit the subscribe button. I shared the
behind the scenes of exactly how I do
this every single week. And as a token
of my appreciation, I've left some free
resources that you can start using to
start writing and mastering one
platform. And remember, your competition
is posting more content, but you're
posting better content. See you in the
next video. Bye.