I decided to lock myself in a room until
my new business hit six figures. The
question is, would this even be
possible? Well, let's start from the
beginning. At 15, I immigrated to the UK
with no family, no connections, nothing.
All [music] of this for one big bet.
Make it happen. All my family savings
went into [music] this big dream. And
for years, I've sacrificed everything.
My freedom, my friendships, spending
time with family pulled thousands of
allnighters. Fast forward an entire
decade and many failed businesses. My
new business made $30,000 [music] in 3
days. Then we hit $60,000 in monthly
recurring revenue 53 days later. But my
friends, success is extremely fragile.
And before I explain everything, you
need to understand what happened in this
corner of my apartment. Over the last 4
months, I've barely left this spot in
London. To tell you the truth, there is
nothing glamorous to an apartment that
hasn't been left in weeks. But see, I've
been building a tech startup that might
change everything. A startup that can go
from $0 and no users to six figures in
less than 3 months without [music]
spending a single penny on ads. We've
literally done that all organically. But
to achieve that, I gave up my life.
Lapped up attached to my [music] hip
early mornings and late nights. I
worried every single one of my friends.
My [music] mentors were telling me not
to do this. And I even broke my own
rules in the process of focusing on one
business only at one time. But the truth
is, in 2025, I realized I [music] wanted
more. something that didn't just rely on
me or my face [music] to be profitable.
And so mid-March of 2025, I got a
message from my good friend Jake with an
offer I couldn't refuse. And here's
where the real journey started. We were
on a mission to build the one thing we
wish that we had when we started as
creators and entrepreneurs. Back then, 3
years ago, making $10,000 a month was a
dream, like an actual fantasy. But even
when I thought that that was just a
[music] longdistant dream that I may
achieve when I hit 30, I showed up
anyway. Average content, no master plan,
just consistency and a simple swipe file
filled with all of my favorite creators.
I was obsessed with Hux. Iworked like
crazy. I engaged on every single post I
could find just for the single chance of
being seen. And slowly things actually
started to work. I got my first inbound
leads. I went viral for the first time
and I made my first online dollar. But
beyond all of the money and all of these
aspirations, I started meeting people,
real people, which then became friends.
People who were at the exact level as
me, trying to figure out how to grow and
succeed. These people were beginners
just like me, trying to figure out
everything. How to grow, how to scale,
how to build an actual business. And all
of us together we helped each other grow
and succeed along the way. And in that
period of time we built our own swipe
files filled with content we loved. We
studied what worked in the platforms
like Instagram, LinkedIn, Twitter etc.
We posted religiously and obsessed over
LinkedIn and how to grow faster than
anyone. This single platform that was
seen as the place where people just
posted jobs and applied had become the
single most profitable place to acquire
clients for our boring businesses. We
went from zero dollars to multiple six
[music] figures and then millions. But
in 2025, I hit a block. After building a
few businesses that [music] became six
figure and seven figure businesses, I
wanted to build something else.
something with the potential to not just
helped thousands of people but help
hundreds of thousands. And to do that,
the right vehicle was right in front of
me. During my come-up and in those years
where I [music] went from zero to 10,000
followers to 10,000 to 100,000 and now
even 300,000 followers, I'd met the one
key person that was going to change
everything for me and that was Jake
Wood. He had started to build a tool
that collected viral content. It
collected posts just like we did
manually in 2023. Then he used AI to
turn that into original content with
proven ideas and formats that we had
collected over the years manually
[music] through our work. And I knew
about this tool, but he hadn't taken it
to market until somewhere around March
2025 when I got the call from Jake. He
wanted to launch this thing to the
public. And as soon as he said that, I
was all in because I didn't just know
about this tool, I was the first user.
And to this day, I can say with
certainty that without it, I wouldn't be
here in front of you being able to tell
you this story. I'd be far behind. It
was my cheat code to skyrocketing my
following from 50,000 to 150,000
followers in under a year. Jake also
grew his own following from 30,000
followers to 170,000 followers with it
too. Millions of views, thousands of
likes, hundreds of clients acquired
inbound. But there was a problem. The
tool wasn't making any money. Our
friends used it, friends of friends
tried it and people ended up getting
their hands on it as we spoke about it a
lot. But Jake wasn't making any money
from it. That wasn't the point at
[music] the start. The tool back then
was completely free. We were just meant
to use it internally. And this is when
the penny actually dropped for Jake and
also me. We had a good product, but we
needed to sell it. But here's the
problem. Right until this point, all I
had ever done was marketing. The
software game was completely new to me.
I didn't even know it. It was B2B SAS,
AI, and all of these things. I had no
idea about all of these new words like
MVP, MSP, MR, and new problems like
churn, bottlenecks, etc. All of these
things had made me realize that if we
wanted to win this game, we needed to
[music] lock in. The reality with this
entire new play that we were going to
make was that no one was going to come
save us. No one was going to give us a
handout. And [music] if we wanted this
business to succeed, we had to build it
ourselves. So we did exactly that. Jake
built a co-founding team with me
included. We found a great developer.
And after months of trying to organize
ourselves and free some time to build
this business completely bootstrapped.
After all of that, we finally started
brainstorming the first MVP. We started
building it and everything felt like it
was going to succeed. started creating
hype for the official launch of this
version that people would be able to
actually buy. It came to the point where
we set the date for launch publicly.
Everyone that we knew that followed us
knew that this date was the date where
the product was [music] meant to be
going live. And this was it, my first
tech business. I was so excited until a
few weeks later when we were set to
[music] launch, our developer quit. It
put us all the way back to square one.
[music] The pressure that this put on me
was intense. I was in charge of the
marketing, [music]
but I couldn't market a product that I
hadn't seen. Time was ticking. [music]
Hours felt like days. Days felt like
hours. Launch day was around the corner.
But [music] luckily, a few days later
after we found out that our CTO had
quit, Jake found the perfect developer.
His name is Cam, by the way, and he is
amazing. He was the perfect fit. almost
made it seem like our CTO quitting was
almost like a sign. Jake knew him
because they grew up together. We shared
similar values. He had the perfect skill
set. And most importantly, he was all
in. So much so that he literally quit
his job to start working with us. He put
everything that he had on hold. He flew
all the way to Canada where the boys
were and locked in with them all while I
was here in London building the
marketing and everything else that we
needed to get this product ready to
launch. We had the mock idea of what the
product would actually look like. We had
the work that our old developer had
done. And in this process, we ran into
so many bottlenecks. AI hall had loin
sometimes. So we needed to figure out a
way to stop that. We had to prioritize
some features more than others so we
could have the product ready on time.
And before we knew it, launch day had
finally arrived. And so my question then
was, was the product even ready to be
sold to the public? Was I truly able to
punch my weight for this product that
had nothing to do with me or my brand?
This was the ultimate marketer's test
for me to see what I was actually worth.
So I sent our first email to our email
list. We are live and people bought it
from one single email, acquired our
first 10 customers within seconds. And
those 10 users turned into 20, then 50,
then 100. And the user count kept on
growing. But somewhere along the sleep
deprivation and caffeine, I thought we
could do better. And so there we were on
Zoom at 3:00 a.m. Me, Jake, our other
co-founders, Rob and Cam, doing
something no one had ever really done on
the platform. A live launch of a product
we finished hours before with no
preparation, no idea, no slides, no
anything, and literally no marketing for
it. We ripped it off the cuff. It was it
was just me and Jake sharing the first
version of Cleo, and [music] people
loved it. Things here could have gone
wrong, completely wrong. People could
have not shown up. The internet could
have broken. The tool could have
crashed. I could have potentially just
not known what to say. But we bet on
ourselves so hard anyway. Beyond every
single potential problem, every
self-doubt, all of the imposter
syndrome, we bet on ourselves anyway.
So, by the 42hour mark, we had made
$21,000,
a record in our books, in many books.
insane work. But instead of celebrating
like a normal person going out having
dinner, I was sleepd deprived in Bosnia
while the guys were in Colombia, we knew
that no matter how little we had slept,
the real work started there because now
it wasn't about new acquisition, [music]
it was about retention of customers. The
entire Cleo launch was actually a beta
launch, which meant that we weren't open
to everyone. We just opened 500 spots
for Cleo as we were truly just testing
if the MVP actually worked because just
in case you forgot, we finished building
the product hours before the launch. So,
we needed to get feedback from users to
understand what was needed for a good
final product. The tool for the first
500 users cost $49 a month, that's it,
and locked in for a lifetime. People
were keen to try it, but the feedback
was brutal. For the next 60 days, we got
to work. Hours in customer calls,
thousands of lines in code written. And
so then 60 days later, we opened another
500 spots, our final 500 spots. And to
be honest, I had my doubts. It was 60
days later after we had built all of
this FOMO and hype and excitement, and I
didn't know if we were going to be able
to do it again. So, we went ahead and
did it anyway. We opened the next 500
spots and I'll never forget what
happened next because after all of that
self-doubt, I hadn't slept. I was about
to hop on a flight. I was sleepd
deprived on my way to a conference. We
had made $61,000 in monthly revenue in
less than a week. People were sharing
it, talking about it, using it in their
workflows. We were literally getting
invited into podcast, starter story,
Greg Eisenbergs, Indie Hackers, all
these things. I even got to go on James
Smith's podcast which was a childhood
dream of mine because I've seen him
growing up and so was one of our
co-founders Rob went on Greg's which is
ultimately the AI B2B SAS king and the
best part of all of this for the first
time in my entire life I wasn't the
product the product was the product Cleo
was Cleo in a matter of months with
outperforms our competitors with VC
funding and decades of experience on us
we did it ourselves four people team.
That's it. We didn't even have a landing
page for all of this. All we had was a
team of four with no idea and pure
delusion, a polar.so checkout link that
looked like We had an email list
which proved to be the most amazing
thing. And we had a deadline. Shipping
before we were ready [music] turned out
to be the best thing we could have done
for the product, for ourselves, for our
personal brands, and for the users. To
be honest, we could have waited until
everything was perfect, but where's the
fun in all of that? To be honest, for
the purpose of this video, I could just
say everything here was perfectly
planned to a tea. We knew exactly what
was going to go wrong. We knew exactly
how to do it. We knew exactly how to do
this and that and how to achieve this
thing and how to overcome this obstacle.
But nearly everything went wrong. And I
think that this is where true
entrepreneurialism is tested. How many
punches in the face can [music] one take
before they decide to quit? We took
every single one of them. And now,
ladies and gentlemen, this is where our
story really starts. This is just the
beginning for us. We're now obsessing
over growth, retention, new marketing
tactics, hiring, making even more
mistakes. We need to build an undeniable
product that is a no-brainer for anyone
and most importantly maintain it. a
no-brainer, retaining our current users.
And now the million-dollar question in
this journey of building a $1 million
ARR business is, can we do it? Well, I
guess you'll have to follow the journey
and see.
There are no limits in this game of
internet business. The only limit is the
one that you give yourself. Let me
remind you of this. If a bunch of kids
like us were able to do this with no
experience, what could you do with all
of the experience that you have, with
all of the resources and even just the
fact that you have the internet? That is
the question that I want to leave you
with. You have to be willing to outwork
anyone else. The sky is truly the limit.
Now, if you want to join me for the next
live launch, I'll drop the link in the
description below so you can watch us do
this whole thing live and see it come
alive for the first time publicly. I
hope you guys join us in this journey. I
love you guys and I'll see you soon.