This is Tyler Dank. He's built one of
the fastest growing creator platforms,
Beehive, to more than 30 million in
revenue [music] in its fourth year, and
he's sharing his entire playbook on
LinkedIn. Tyler has all the ingredients
for massive content [music] success. He
posts nearly every single day, writes
incredibly well, and has a series of
viral posts that prove that he's on the
right track. And today, he's got a
massive opportunity to go from 58,000
[music]
followers to over 100,000 followers
before 2026 ends. All he needs is the
right strategy so he can position
himself as the authority in his niche,
post high performing content
consistently and start winning on
[music] LinkedIn. And I'm Lara Costa. I
built multiple six and seven figureure
businesses through content and growing
my personal brand on LinkedIn to 300,000
followers while scaling [music] those
businesses. So, I understand exactly how
to help Tyler. Now, [music] I spent 3
days analyzing every aspect of Tyler's
content strategy and figured out that he
needs a databacked winning format engine
that he can repeat on demand. He also
needs a signature style post series to
put Sporal posting to rest. My plan is
simple. Take Tyler's proven winning
patterns, systematize them into
repeatable frameworks, [music] and build
him as the most influential founder on
the platform. So Tyler, welcome to the
channel. Today we are going to see
exactly how we can get you from 50K to
100K in record time. Now why do you want
to dominate on LinkedIn?
>> Yeah, for me I think it's a few
different things. I think the content
that I create falls into a few different
buckets. One is founderled content and
so building trust with my audience as I
build beehive. Two is just becoming a
subject matter expert in
entrepreneurship and email in the
creator economy. And three is there is
no three. or so some combination between
one and two tail. At the end of the day,
I am one of the co-founder and CEO of
Beehive. And my ultimate goal is to
build Beehive into a massively
successful company. So I would view
LinkedIn as a top offunnel channel to
win customers and loyalty with my
audience.
>> And how many followers do you have on X?
>> About 40,000.
>> So yeah, 40,000 and then 50. You
actually have more followers on LinkedIn
than X. That's crazy. But you have more
engagement on X.
>> I don't know. It's hard to say. I I get
more engagement per post on LinkedIn. I
think every time I post on LinkedIn, I
guess we'll say this in a minute, I
typically get at least 50 likes or so. I
don't know if likes are the right
measurement. And I also don't know if
you're laughing because that's not very
much, but uh
>> yeah, I don't know. Um
>> so I actually analyzed over 200 of your
posts from the last 365 days. Okay. And
I actually noticed a few things and I'm
going to break them down to you. So
right now I would categorize you as a
level four for creator. This means that
you have the credibility. Okay, so we
have the C, you have the positioning,
and you have social proof, which is
essentially everything you need to get
to level five, which is like the final
boss stage. So, there's five levels of
LinkedIn creators. Level one is complete
beginner, so you're at zero and you're
trying to get your first thousand. Level
two is you're like an intermediate.
You're trying to get your first 10,000
followers, but you're still kind of like
struggling with content ideas, testing
out, you don't even have a business.
Then once you nail that and you've
created content for a few times, you get
to level three where it's like you're
posting consistently, you know your
niche a little bit and now you're seeing
some traction. But now level four,
exactly where you are is you have the
traction, you have the credibility as
well, but now we need the consistency,
which is what we miss with you when it
comes to content. Because what I
analyzed is you have really good high
performers. So like I actually put 20
that are within 2,000 and beyond 100
like mark but then the rest were quite
sporadic. So there were either product
features updates etc. And so I noticed a
pattern between your 20 top performer
ones that we can actually use to magnify
that. Okay. So all your top performers
look like this. Can you see anything
that you think is consistent between all
of these posts?
>> Uh they all have an image.
>> Yeah. What else? Anything else? Um, they
all crushed it.
>> Yes.
>> Um, what what am I missing here? So, I
guess the two categories that jump out
to me are milestone based. So, the MR
ones that's an accomplishment. I think
LinkedIn enjoys and celebrates other
founders or or business owners that have
hit different milestones and
achievements. And then the other one
that jumps so two others jump out the
personal story. So, right as I have
posted over the past few years while
building the business, I have built a
persona of like a founder content
creator I suppose. And so the selfie
with like me talking about burnout, it's
career adjacent with talking about
burnout and work and life um but also
personal. And I think the bottom one
around email is dead is like really
flexing an expertise in understanding
the industry and becoming more of a
thought leader in that space.
>> Yeah, exactly. So what I deducted from
this is like you have a heavy use of
numbers and proof which is important for
LinkedIn to position you as an
authority. than the personality post
like this one about burnout. It just
it's a total addressable market thing.
So anyone whether they are an email guy,
whether they're interested in email or
not, they can relate to you and then
that could be a funnel for them to
finding you then finding out what you do
and then being like, "Oh, he's talking
about email. Let me listen to him
because I already like him." And then
the last thing, the last two things is
when you work about remote work or
layoffs, it also kind of works because
again, it's to total addressable market
content. And this is such important part
of LinkedIn content. Like content on
LinkedIn is essentially like a funnel.
You need total addressable market
content so people can find you. Then
growth content and niche content which
you have done incredibly well. And the
last one that I really like from you is
you hijack narratives and you have
contrarian takes. So you are known in
the industry for having an enemy quite
loudly and so using that on LinkedIn
actually works incredibly well for you.
Just not overdoing it. Okay. Now, the
best part about where you are right now
is that we already have literal
templates that we can rinse and repeat
just based on different topics. And so
today, my only job is to show you how
you can continue that every single week
without you thinking, okay, what am I
going to post about today, right? So,
what we're going to focus on next is
data level back to winning format
engines, repetitive signature style
posts, so we can do less sporadic
posting and then broad personality
posts. And then what we're going to stop
doing is generic figure uh updates and
office and hiring post without
structure. So everything that you've
spoken about on your LinkedIn, you can
actually templatize and create a high
performing post with the same exact
topic. We just need a little bit more
structure. So where people get stuck is
that once they post a viral format, they
don't repeat it enough. And what I think
about brand and series is that you need
to be repetitive in your messaging. So
how do we repeat this consistently?
Obviously, not every single week you're
going to be hitting a milestone. How can
we make every single thing you do a
milestone like post? So, we're going to
go and use the clear swipe file here.
I'm going to add this to my swipe file.
And then what this is going to do is
going to allow me to templatize your
post that you already wrote in your own
person style. So, like what are the top
things that you've done over the last
two weeks? So, you were in London.
You're in London right now for what for
the Google event?
>> Yeah. So, we hosted an event with Google
and then we also had dinners with a
bunch of users and creators in the UK.
So yeah, brought a bunch of the team out
here this week.
>> Okay. What else
>> about London specifically or just in
general?
>> So you dropped the product.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So we just launched a new
product yesterday as well. It's a new
media library and so you can actually
edit assets directly in Beehive. Now we
also launched Giddy Images and some
other asset like aggregators of sorts.
So a steady drip of new features. And
>> and you did your launch as well, your
Apple like launch, the video that you
did for um you launched something else
like it was a massive product update
where it was like very steep jobs like
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. So that was a few months
ago, but yeah, we did a winter release
event in November where we launched 10
features including digital products
where we just launched a few minutes
ago.
>> So we have those two posts and we have
all of these new things that we can talk
about. So, what I'm going to do is I'm
going to go into Cleo, use this as a
swipe, and let's say, please look at
exactly how this post was written, and
give me 10 ideas for my next post based
on this exact template. So, let's say we
want to talk about uh flying to London
to speak in front of how many people do
you think?
>> We had about 300 people there yesterday.
It's unfortunate you couldn't make it,
but I saw again. I was there after very
people and you spoke about
>> the importance of owning your audience
and owning the distribution and then I
also gave a overview of how I scaled my
newsletter to 100,000 readers.
>> Also launched 10 new features for
beehive including digital products which
help users
>> launch and sell anything from ebooks,
templates, guides and sessions.
>> Very cool. So from here we have the just
the basis. So ideally every single week
instead of trying to start post and
thinking about what what to write. You
just literally give clear the updates on
what you're actually doing cuz you're a
founder creator. You're not you don't
necessarily need to be capped at
educator and you need to break down. You
just need to learn how to talk about
what you're doing vingible attention way
where people want to listen to it rather
than just updating. So obviously this is
based on my own knowledge base because
I'm using my own cleo but for you when
you have it you have it already set it
will say about it will talk about you.
So it would say behub just hit over 20
million active users but most creators
are still struggling. So that's one
idea. Then your business just hit 1
million revenue. So immediately we have
different ideas on how you can
templatize the exact post I went borrow
and talk about different things. So here
we're talking about product course etc.
Your personal brand how much money
you're making all of these things. So
let's say for your email list we can say
my email list just crossed over 100,000
subscribers. So we have that. It's
writing it exactly like how you wrote
it. you know, we have one new post ready
to go. So, if you're able to do this
three times a week, we will be able to
gain between a thousand to 10,000
followers every single week just based
on three posts rather than having to
sporadically post product updates. We
are kind of like centralizing the
content as to authority and
personalization so it can grow faster.
And so, we're just going to wait and see
what
>> we'll let we'll let Cleo cook right
here.
>> Yeah. Any questions so far?
>> No, this is great.
>> Quick one. If you are enjoying this
breakdown with Tyler and [music] I,
please subscribe to the channel. I bet
him that I could grow to 100,000
followers on YouTube before he hit
100,000 followers on LinkedIn. And I'd
love to beat him. And it also helps me
get more guests into the channel and
even more of you so I can break down
your brand and how [music] to win as
well. Let's get back into the video. So,
let's go back a little bit. Where do you
think you would struggle to actually
have this as a mechanism for your puzzle
brand? Yeah, I think where I struggle
the most is if you go back to the board
of all of my different posts. I think
the one that would perform reliably the
best is the email is dead format. Yeah.
Not just the format, but the fact that
it is actually me being positioned as a
thought leader and trying to educate the
market. It also has a bit of like a
contrarian take to it. So, I think it
couples both contrarian take and
educating people about email and its
importance. Yeah. But I also think that
those are the most time consuming posts
to write personally. Um so I think
that's where Cleo could be extremely
helpful.
>> So what other contrarian views do you
have? Like obviously yes everybody
thinks email is dead. Anything else that
you've seen in the market that people
think about email?
>> Yeah, I mean I think the fact that
remote work is superior than in-person
work to build a company is fairly
contrarian and something that I believe
as well.
>> Well, you don't believe in remote work?
>> No, I do believe in remote work. I think
remote companies are much better than
companies that are in person.
>> Oh yeah, 100%. You used to work in an
office as well, right?
>> Yeah, way back when.
>> So, we can do that as well. So, I'm
going to say that as well. Did you just
click to write this?
>> I did.
>> Yeah, I could tell. I love And it did so
well.
>> It is one of my best performing posts
for sure.
>> Yeah, I remember. All right, cool. So,
we have the fast post and obviously my
email list just crossed over 100,000
subscribers, but most creators are still
ignoring email entirely. This is
literally based on the post that we just
saw from you. And so that is going to
literally cut the hours spent writing
into less than two minutes. All you need
to do is kind of like proofread it, add
some relevant insights that you know the
AI wouldn't know and you post it.
>> So to reiterate, take my best performing
post that consistently have some sort of
format, feed it to Cleo, update Cleo
with other milestones or things that
would be relevant to create a new post
and it basically keeps the format and
rewrites the post with additional new
content.
>> Yeah. So the key is find a format that
works cuz you've already done the
testing and iteration because you were
like level one, level two, level three
creator. Then at level four, you have
all these knowledge of the content
that's already performed well. So why
not use that at scale? The main problem
that creators have and founders and
entrepreneurs on LinkedIn is that they
go viral once and then that's it.
They're like, "Oh, I can't use that
format again." The reality is that once
you find the winning format, you rinse
and repeat it until it stops working and
then you find another one. And in that
time, you would have found another one
through testing and iterating. So that's
what I would do if I was you. just use
what works and then repeat it. Because
what happens with content and users and
every single person that consumes social
media is that they love repetition. They
love familiarity. And so the key for you
to get to 100K is that familiarity and
trust. Like they want to be like, "Oh, I
know Tyler. He's the guy that's always
talking about email. He's running and
building his own business." And he's
also kind of cool.
>> Pineapple just go. Super cool. All
right. Cool. Now, let's do that again
with the pose that you told us.
>> Yeah. Should we do the other contrary
and take with this format, which would
be that remote work is better than
in-person work.
>> So, how many employees do you have?
>> 110
>> remote employees.
>> Yes.
>> From all around the world.
>> Yeah, I'd say like 15 different
countries.
>> And any other data you would be able to
give us like maybe
>> like maybe time zones.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know the answer to that though.
>> How about how productive your team is?
>> Yeah, productive as Actually, I
think the credibility would be like we
ship product faster than anyone else in
the industry and so the product velocity
I think is the output from our
productivity.
>> So the key with Creo is to just give it
a few more things to embed into the
content otherwise it'll sound generic.
We need to add more personal insights so
you can write us a nearly perfect end
post. You don't have to spend an hour
editing it. Instead you spend a few
minutes. So notable failures when it
comes to remote work would be like
hybrid working office building. Yep.
>> So I would add that here's a reality and
that's it. So it's based on this viral
post that you wrote but even better and
that's it. And I think what worked well
for you is the use of specific numbers
as well. Yeah.
>> So when you go and write this again is
using it here. So 110 employees across
different 15 countries etc. And then
what we need to bear in mind is that the
image also allowed people to
contextualize faster what you're talking
about. So if we can replicate this image
we can actually do it today with Cleo.
But um Cleo now has an image generator
so we can generate with the eye and we
can add some references. I'm going to
upload the graphic that you created and
it'll take a few minutes but it'll
create a visual similar to that but
about exactly what we're speaking about.
So by this point we had already created
your templatized version of how you can
create content that's viral, high
performing and it's on topic and also
showed you how easy it is to truly talk
about anything with a system. Okay. The
second thing is low friction repetitive
signature style post. So I highlighted
here the ones that you also highlighted
at the start which is the ones that are
showing proof. So like the graphs and
also the ones that have your beautiful
face in it.
>> Selfies work.
>> So the number one task that I would give
you is one take more selfies and two be
more personal. The reason why this work
and I think you should repeat it again
is you need to talk about typical
founder problems because you're leaning
into that persona. You're like a founder
that's struggling like any other founder
but you're still winning. But we want to
talk about the what happens when you're
building such a large business like you
have. So we talk about burnout, we talk
about remote work, we talk about
productivity hacks that actually work
for you and how you travel a lot and you
still manage to be productive and
anything else that you think comes to
mind. So realistically, I know you
talked on maybe many podcasts or
interviews. So things that actually
stand out to you, just write them down
after so we can actually build that
rapport with your audience because they
actually do care. The proof is there. So
why not repeat it? So, I'm going to go
look for this post and see how we can
systematize it as well. Yeah.
>> Yeah. No, I think that was my best
performing post that I've ever had. So,
I agree.
>> And you wrote it with Cleo Clean. That
was And I chose a photo.
It's
>> Oh, look.
>> Yeah, it looks great.
>> Sick. This is what your call is as well.
>> Yeah. One that looks sick. I actually
don't think the format of like failing
since is like the best for this one. Or
at least we could probably do like COVID
or something else, but like the year
format doesn't make sense. But yeah, I
think that that looks actually really
cool.
>> I think it's Yeah, after that what you
can do is then go and add more feedback
so then it can create you something. But
like as a fast draft I can Yeah, that
was really good.
>> Now we just found your repeatable
framework for personality posts. So what
we're going to do is again add it to our
swipe file and then I want ideas just
like this but about panda struggles that
address a total addressable market. So
let's keep it broad but within the
founder entrepreneur niche. So let's say
uh remote work problems
>> maybe like working alone like long hours
by myself.
>> Being alone.
>> It's true. I sit in my office 14 hours a
day.
>> A day. Uh how you quit coffee?
>> Sure did.
>> For a month.
>> No, for a year.
>> For a year. Why?
>> I feel like I feel like that's a great
post in itself of just like giving up
coffee cuz everyone feels very
opinionated about that.
>> Yeah. So you feel better now?
>> Feeling well at this very moment. No,
>> but typically yes.
>> Stand over today. Uh okay. So we have
three and then every single thing that
you experience can be turned into this
gray post just based on the format that
we have today. And that's the beauty of
templates. That's the entire reason why
we build clear off the back of templates
and systems because we know that once
something works, it can be repeated
multiple times. So one idea, I worked
14our days for 18 months straight. for
you would be more than that.
>> Yeah. More so I wish
>> then my body forced me to stop. And this
is literally reciting kind of like
exactly what you did here.
>> Y
>> and then we're keeping it equally as
short.
>> We go down to the coffee one. That one
looks like a banger potentially.
>> I quit coffee for a year. The decision I
made as a founder. Okay, cool. So we're
going to take that in and then the next
thing I think by now the point is going
to be nearly perfect because it's just
like so short and obvious. And then we
just need a good photo of you with
>> not drinking coffee. Yeah. With maybe
some new new tonic.
>> New tonic.
>> Yeah, of course. Yeah, it does have
caffeine for you. But yeah, so basically
good educational content that follows a
format and then good uh storytelling
founder content that tells your story
and makes you someone that people want
to root for. The core of LinkedIn and
what I've noticed after being on
LinkedIn for 3 years is that if you
don't build an audience that loves you
at any point when the topic stops
working, they'll go to someone else and
you have all the credentials and you
know the charisma etc. and all the
credibility for someone to root for you.
LinkedIn loves an underdog and you are
not an underdog, but the idea of an
underdog and rooting for you is still
present. I
>> I think it's important actually that to
turn yourself into an underdog as well
because I guess we have had some success
as a company, but we're still going up
against dozens of much larger
competitors in the space. Some have been
acquired for billions of dollars. Many
of them have many more users than we do.
Yeah.
>> Um so I do think and I think that's also
kind of the benefit of the founder
marketing. A lot of these people have
been following me since we had $2,000 in
revenue and now we have 2 million in
revenue a month. And so that story arc
and journey um and remaining humble
throughout that experience and really
showing personality I think helps a lot.
>> That can be a pose in itself as well. So
how often to talk about these things? Do
you do you get scared of talking about
the same topic multiple times or no like
this story style? No, but I don't think
I've created the muscle of I said
something that is valuable to other
people but has become second nature to
me because I'm so deep into it to think
for a second like I can turn this into
content that other people would find
value from.
>> I think even what you said right now can
be turned into a story like I'm going
against every single top competitor that
has lots of funding and has been in the
industry for years but in less than four
we've been able to meet 80% of them.
Here's exactly how we did it.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> That's another post. So as you can see
literally from ideas to conversations
anything can be turned into a post as
long as we have a repeatable format and
then that's it. This is where people
fail or win is knowing the difference
between an idea and how to execute it.
But now we have the execution and yeah I
think this could be a bang of for you.
So
>> yeah that looks great. I think people I
think when I I've written a few
newsletters about health as a founder
which I think is another thing kind of
like burnout where like mental health
and even like physical health of like
how I take care of myself while being
quote unquote locked in and working so
much and one of the most controversial
things that people respond to is getting
up on coffee. So I think it's kind of
like a great
>> Why do people love coffee so much?
>> I have no idea but I guarantee you that
post would pop off on like
>> Okay, let's do it. Let's do it. We just
created a viral post for Tyler and
you'll post it tomorrow. I'll send it to
you.
>> Yeah, we're going to wait till next week
because we better engagement on the end
of the week, right?
>> Weekdays. Yeah, that's true. That is
true. What I would do after I'm going to
try and make this a little bit shorter
so the story kind of like just banks
quickly like uh one and done. With
storytelling, there's two ways. So you
either make the story incredibly long,
but it has to have every single open
loop so people keep on reading. Or we
just keep it short, concise, and to the
point so people stop, they like the
hook, they like the photo, and then they
want to read what's inside, which is
exactly what you did for your burnout
post here. Yeah, that's why we're so
short. Okay, so we've covered how to get
from level four to level five by using
repeatable templates, by using uh
storytelling, and by using numbers and
revenue. How many times are you posting
on LinkedIn today?
>> I try to once a day during the week. So,
five times a week.
>> So, if we're going to post, let's say we
want to have four key posts every single
week. So the other three, they can be
your typical post that you're updating
things on, but we're going to want to
follow the templates. So let's say you
want to talk about your feature update
for the digital products. So we want to
have a good hook that's less than eight
words that also has specific outcome. So
instead of saying we just shipped a new
feature on behive, we can say this new
feature will make you a top 1% creator.
Or like if you want to make money as a
creator fast, here's exactly how to do
it in less than 20 minutes.
>> Yeah. instead of just like the updates.
The body of the post needs to have
action steps and a call to engage. So,
this is what's going to make your post
go from 100 likes to 800 plus likes
every single time. So, the call to
engage is at the end of every single
post, you encourage your audience to
comment on it. So, by the way, who here
is a Beehive user? Or by the way, who
here wants to learn exactly how to build
their news in less than 10 days? So,
we're kind of like giving people more
chances to comment rather than them just
being like, "Oh, that's a good post. I'm
going to like it." Comments, reposts,
and saves are tactically and technically
the things that actually push your post
onto the algorithm. So, we always want
to push people to comment more.
>> How are the clever ways that you've seen
cuz obviously when you do drop X in the
comments and I will send you Y, it's
kind of like a lead magnet thing, but
that also gets overplayed a lot on
LinkedIn. So, like what are the other
clever ways that you've been able to
encourage comments on LinkedIn? So we
use the 3+ one 3+ one comment strategy.
So we have two posts. We have your post
here and we have posts on the feed,
right? So what you want to do is within
your post, you want to drop three
different comments yourself about
different things. So let's say this is
about London and Beehive, right? So then
you want to drop a BTS pick of like a
selfie. It's like, hey, I just saw this
person speak. I love this. And then it's
like a two liner post with a photo. Then
this one is would be like like a tip.
So, education and then either another
education or a BTS, whatever you have
the resources for. So, sometimes I don't
have anything to say, so I just drop a
bunch of like behind the scenes
pictures. So, like in my post on Monday,
I'll be talking about personal branding,
but then my BTS post will be about, hey,
I just filmed a YouTube video with Tyler
Denk. Then, by the way, tip to write
better emails would be use Beehive. And
then the other one would be here's how
many coffees I drank while Tyler drank
syrup.
>> Exactly. Perfect. And then these allow
people to have a soft conversation
within the post, making the post go from
100 to a thousand without having to work
harder. Okay, so that's one. And then
you're going to be doing the same for
every single post you see on the feed
for the next 30 minutes. So you post
fast, you comment all of these things,
you reply to every single comment as
well. And then on the feed, you want to
do the same. So you want to drop at
least one or two comments that give some
insight. So you're like maybe you see my
post on puzzle branding and then you're
like yeah building my puzzle brand has
been the cheat code to actually growing
my found business or whatever you think
or maybe you're like no building a
personal brand doesn't work this way.
>> And how important is it for you to reply
to the comments that you're receiving on
your post.
>> It's super important especially within
the first 30 minutes. So a hack that
people don't really realize or they know
about it but they don't want to believe
it because it's a lot a lot more work is
that people believe that you cannot
control the algorithm which I agree but
the only small chance that you get to
controlling the algorithm is within the
first 30 minutes of a post because like
any algorithm the more comments you get
faster the faster it gets pushed onto
all the people's networks. So here's how
we are algorithm hacking without really
doing anything else. What are the other
algorithm hacks that you recommend or or
what are both algorithm hacks and things
that you should never do on LinkedIn to
hurt your reach?
>> Okay, so one thing that let me dispel
some myths first. So a common algorithm
myth that people think is that you
cannot post a link because it decrease
your reach. The only reason why it would
decrease your reach is that if people
are not clicking on that link. So you
need to make the link that you're
sharing attractive. So instead of saying
join my newsletter here, you would say
join over 100,000 people learning about
email newsletters and founder companies
here right now.
>> Is it overrated to say link in comments
and move your link to the first comment
versus having the link directly in the
post?
>> If I had to drive traffic as fast as
possible, I would always have it on my
post because on the comments you're just
depending whether people are going to
actually go into the comments actually
or not. And before it was easier because
LinkedIn had pinned comments. You could
actually pin the first comment but today
you can't. you're relying on like
whether the comment ranks high or not.
So, if you want to drive traffic fast,
then put it in your post. But if you
don't really care and you just want to
have it there to like build some sort of
like momentum or like awareness, then do
drop it in the comments. It just
depends. If I was you and I was trying
to drive people to behive to subscribe,
I would do that once a week within a
post and then drop it on the comments
for the other six post of the week.
>> Gotcha.
>> Any other algorithm hacks that you found
that I found? H. So, it's not an
algorithm hack, but it's definitely
obvious. It's I call it the
tiktophication of LinkedIn where
basically people respond better to
images, not videos, images. When you
post videos, they perform kind of well,
but they would perform better on YouTube
or Instagram or even Tik Tok because
it's a videoled platform. On LinkedIn,
we just want to use images. So, let's
say you want to drive traffic to your
next behive update on YouTube. What I
would do instead of posting the the
video, I would actually just post a
photo of you behind the scenes filming
the video that you posted on YouTube
instead because that gives people more
context faster than having to wait for
you to say something on the video.
>> What type of images do you think perform
the best? Are there certain type of
infographics, selfies, behind the
scenes, or does it depend?
>> Images
ranking. Yeah, let's talk about this.
There are three different types that I
see perform. There is like personal
photos, there are infographics, and
there are screenshots. For personal
photos, if you're doing storytelling, an
infographic won't perform well if the
post is about you. Then if it's an
educational post, then these two work
incredibly well. And for you, cuz you do
a lot of product updates, business
updates, etc. Screenshots of your MR or
like how much beehive is growing would
actually work. Yeah, it it has to be
context dependent and people need to
understand the pattern. Today in the
attention economy that we have, people
have become aware of what things match
the context. So think about okay, how
can I give as much context to what I'm
talking about as fast as possible. So
people actually click on read more. If
you're like we just raised 100 million
for behave, then you can like show the
news article. But if it's like, oh, I'm
burnt out and tired, just show a photo
of you.
>> Yeah. Would you ever recommend posting
without an image?
>> Actually, one of your top performing
posts was actually text only. So it
depends on how strong the hook is. If
the hook is good, so you're talking
about, you know, productivity is dead.
Here's what I actually think. Then that
is a controversial enough topic that you
don't need an image for, but I'll always
sort of like back it with an image just
in case because sometimes we think that
the hook is really strong, but in
reality it's not and we just think we're
good at writing.
>> Agreed.
>> Any other questions?
>> No more questions for me.
>> So I guess from your point of view, like
what do you prefer? What's easier for
you? Educating heavy or storytelling?
>> Storytelling.
>> Yeah. So, I think that if we just do one
educational post a week, which is going
to take the majority of your time
writing, and then the other like five or
six story storyled, then that would make
it easier for you to stay consistent
rather than having to think, no, no, I
need to do three educational posts. Just
let's remove the friction and just do it
once a week. So you can be a top
performer, very insightful, but it
doesn't make you feel like, "Oh, I have
to write more." Because right now, like
you have all the tools in your tool
stack to write incredible stories
because people care about you. And
within those stories, you can still
educate on email. And this is the thing
that people miss. When you're telling a
story, you can also talk about the
journey of being a founder. So like, I
built a $30 million business in less
than four years. And it was all because
I focused on email. You know, if you're
starting an email list this year, here's
exactly what I would do. He drops three
different points and then you talk about
this how I became a founder or something
like that.
>> Are the creators that you think are
crushing it the most on LinkedIn doing
more story or more educational or does
it depend on the type of career?
>> It just depends. The market will
allocate what they what it thinks you do
best. So when I started, I truly just
wanted to be an educator cuz that's what
I saw perform well. But once I started
talking about my story, I realized that
the market just loved it when I talked
about my journey. For you, the market
loves it when you do both. And so you
can be an a combination of an educator
and a storyteller but pushing towards
storytelling while educating. So I have
a a framework that I use all the time.
It's called slay. Have you heard of it?
>> I have not heard of this actually.
>> The slay framework is to start with a
story, lead with a lesson and then have
actionable advice and you end with a
use. So it pass with everything that we
spoke about before. And actually Cleo is
built on one of these frameworks. So
most of the post that Cleo writes always
kind of like follow this criteria. So
the story would be like I spent six days
in London and spoke to a hundred of our
customers. They all had one thing to
say. Email changed their business.
Something like that. And then you can
say like they monetize faster. They
build credibility. And then you could
say like 80% of them uh quit their 9 to5
or something that is relevant than that.
And then you can say this is the power
email.
>> We love email
>> email. When are you building yours?
Building yours. Okay.
>> It's a banger post.
>> Yeah. Literally copy paste put on to
clear and then that's it. Obviously it
needs to be a little bit longer but
that's the entire draft of it. So that's
how I think about post when it comes to
telling my story so it can get attention
but also telling someone else's story
through my lens. This how you master the
art of the humble brag on LinkedIn.
>> Is that a art that you've mastered?
>> I think so. Incredible.
>> You as well.
>> I think so.
>> You as well. But it's like humble bag.
So it's like I'm not You're not saying,
"Oh, I'm rich. Look at me." It's like I
>> I've never said those words. You said
those words a lot.
>> I've never said those words.
>> Yeah. So exactly why? Like cuz you don't
portray yourself as a rich person. You
portray yourself as someone that's
building world at scale.
>> But if I wanted to do it humbly, I'd say
I just recorded with Lara. She said I
was rich.
>> Yeah. We've got it on camera as well.
>> There we go.
>> Well, that's it. Tyler, thank you so
much for coming on. Thank you for
helping me with my LinkedIn strategy.
>> My pleasure. 100K by the end of the
year.
>> That's the goal. And if you don't
already follow me, sorry to leave you
hanging there. There we go. Uh if you
don't already follow me, help me get up
to 100K and shoot me a follow on
LinkedIn.
>> Tyler, if you want to grow your email
newsletter and know everything about it,
I love Beehive so much. And yeah,
>> thanks for having me.
>> Let's go. Bye guys.