In the next 20 minutes, I'm going to
show you exactly how I built a
million-doll creator business using
LinkedIn. I'll be covering every single
thing I did to start, build, and grow my
business, so you can just copy me. But
if you can't watch this video from start
to end, then you might not make it.
Look, over the past few years, I've gone
from running a sixfigure agency,
launching an e-learning business,
co-founding a B2B SAS businesses, and
also angel investing into founder
businesses. And if I had to start all
over again, here's the exact stepby-step
framework from zero to 1 million I'd
use. Now, I'm going to cover how to know
exactly what to sell, how to start with
zero dollars or any investments, how to
multiply your income streams, how to
build your personal brand to 10x and
dominate your market, and lastly, how to
leverage your scale into a wealth
multiplier. The first thing is to know
exactly what to sell. One thing about me
is that I don't believe in market
saturation only in opportunity because
when a market looks saturated all it
means is that there is demand. The real
question is can you position yourself as
someone that people will choose anyways?
To nail [music] this you need to
understand your market value. What
tangible thing do you bring to the table
or to the market that someone actually
wants or needs? A good model I recently
created is the SMPV. So the S stands for
scale. So what are you good at? Then the
M stands for market. Who actually needs
this thing? Then the P stands for
problem. So what pain are they stuck
with? And then V stands for value. So
what tangible outcome do you create by
solving the problem, right? So let me
give you an example. Let's say that
you're a creator, right? And you want to
become an entrepreneur. So how do you do
that? We identify the skill first. So
the skill for the creator can be
something like they like writing and
storytelling. So this is the skill. So
now the market that this person that is
a creator and loves storytelling can tap
it in is into freelancers and maybe
coaches or even entrepreneurs who are
struggling to create content that
actually brings people into their funnel
that attracts attention that makes some
sort of impact because not everybody
likes writing but this person does right
the V for this person that's just
starting the value that they can provide
is like they document their journey so
then for the P because this person
probably doesn't know exactly what
problem they're solving yet. They're
going to document exactly how they're
fixing the problem for themselves. So,
they're also getting ignored. They're
not getting any leads. But then when
they fix this problem, then they can
come onto the V, which is the value. And
the value will come in the solutions
that they find to their problems. And
that's pretty much it. If you're a
creator that wants to be an
entrepreneur. Now, let's take another
example because this one is too easy.
And this also is my story. So, the
reason why this is the first example is
because this was me. I started with my
skill which was writing and
storytelling. I identified it because I
noticed that I just had a knack for
writing. I enjoyed writing on LinkedIn.
And also anytime I would write on
LinkedIn about writing or storytelling,
people would react the best. So I was
like, okay, there's some money in here.
Now for the market, I started
identifying, well, who are the people
who need the most help right now? Who is
the easiest target demographic and the
lowest hanging fruit? I noticed that it
was freelancers, coaches, [music]
entrepreneurs who didn't know how to
write content, but I did. So, I was two
steps ahead. I wasn't 10 steps ahead. I
was just two or one. And then I noticed
I found their problem because I had that
problem as well, which was I wasn't
getting any engagement. I wasn't getting
any leads. I wasn't getting any
followers. But then while I documented
my journey on LinkedIn, this brought me
the value. So, that was my value ad, the
fact that I solved this problem. And so,
that was it. Over time, LinkedIn
delivered me my first few leads and then
I never had to send a cold outreach
message ever again. Now, another example
just for simplicity and also just to
help anyone that may not be a writer and
be like, "Oh my god, Lar, I'm not a
writer." Yes. Okay. And no, let's say
you have an interest for AI, anything.
Maybe it's automations with AI, maybe
it's RGBT, maybe it's Claude, maybe any
anything by coding, whatever. So, how
we're going to lay this out for the
SMPV.
So, the skill is obviously the curiosity
that you have for AI. So maybe it's like
lovable, maybe it's charg
automation, anything AI agents. So then
you've realized that your skill is
understanding how to fix a simple
problem like automations with AI agents
and creating content with it using
claude, right? So that is a thing. So AI
agents plus cord content. So the market
for you would be small agencies and
coaches or solopreneurs. So that is the
market. Why am I saying this is the
market? Because most people that are
within these people, small agencies,
coaches or solopreneurs need help with
automations and they want to use AI. So
they are also open to this. You can also
pick someone else. Now the problem that
you're fixing is the same problem that
you probably fixed for yourself. You
were trying to fix something. That's why
you got into AI and automations. you
then learned, okay, I can actually do
this quite quickly. How about if I then
start selling this to agencies,
solarreneurs, and entrepreneurs [music]
so I can save them time, right? Because
most people don't want to hire anymore
or they want to help their team become
more efficient, right? So the problem
that you're fixing is like the time
issue and potentially saving them money,
right? Now for the value is you're going
to offer your service. You're also going
to offer free content about this and
you're going to show exactly how to fix,
how to implement, and then how to hire
you. So these are three ways in which
you are providing value to the market.
So you're providing it in a free way, in
a paid way, and also in like a premium
way where like you'd probably reveal
most of the steps in your LinkedIn
content like five tips, but you won't
actually say the implementation. So this
is exactly how anyone can find their
market value as fast as possible. Once
you understand this and use this model,
you will be able to get into the next
step. But if you still have questions, I
actually created a chat GPT prompt that
will help you identify your scale, the
market, the problem, and the value you
have and will actually build it out for
you. And it can even give you an offer.
So I'm going to leave that in the
description so we don't get distracted.
But it's incredibly good, and I wish I
had it when I started. So I hope you use
it. That's how you figure out what to
sell to who and how. You don't do it by
copying what's trending or by waiting
for the perfect offer. But you do it by
connecting your unique skills to a
market with a real problem and a clear
value proposition. Now, this is clear.
The next thing is how to start with
zero. Because when the time comes and
you have capital to invest in
businesses, you won't blow it away like
I've seen it happen multiple times. When
you're starting from zero, you don't
need ads, a website, or a funnel. You
don't even need a logo. What you need is
proof. Proof that someone will pay you
for solving their problem. And the
fastest way to get proof is by starting
with a service. That's literally how I
started my business. I didn't go for VC
funding to start a business. I didn't
even know what that even was. I only
just learned what YC Combinator was
earlier this year. And honestly,
ignorance is bliss. When you don't have
money, you pay with your time. And for
me, starting a service-based business
was exactly that. That's exactly how I
paid with my time because I had no
money. All right. Now, let me show you
exactly how you think about it as a
service. So, let's say we have three
types of people. One, two, three. One of
them is a video editor. The next one is
a writer. And the next one is a fitness
coach. Right? So they're done for you
service which is like a service based
business. For the video editor it would
be a short form agency. For the writer
it would be a email agency and then for
the fitness person it would be a PT
training program for 12 weeks or even in
person. So now we have solid examples
that you can actually use and hopefully
you can implement into your own business
and if not maybe you can get some
inspiration. So the idea here is that
you have identified the thing that you
do well and how you can do it for
someone else. Right now in terms of
getting your first few clients, all you
need to do is open LinkedIn, search for
your ideal client, then send a
personalized message or maybe not.
Depends on the volume. I would usually
opt for sending a personalized one,
especially if I'm just starting on
LinkedIn. So there is nuance here. So
just pick and choose what suits you
best. then provide value for free for
them solving one single problem that
they may have and then do this 20 times
a day for as long as it takes until
someone replies. So the sniper approach
I actually used to get from zero
connections to 500 connections not even
followers connections was doing exactly
that. So what I did in order to get this
500 connections as soon as humanly
possible I did a few things. So the
first one was obviously making my
LinkedIn look nice. So building my
personal brand which we'll cover in a
minute. The second thing is every single
personalized DM that I sent, I would
give them a compliment or I would give
them value. I wouldn't just be like,
"Oh, great to connect." Or like, "Oh, I
see you're connected with X." Like, that
is just so overused. Now, it screams AI.
Before it just screams rookie. Now,
let's say I found someone like one of my
co-founders, Jake. I'd say something
like, "Hey, I really loved your recent
SEO breakdown. I actually published it
in a separate blog if you want the
backlink." Or something that is related
to them. So he'll be like, "Oh my god,
thank you so much. This is very helpful.
I actually am building something else
and I really want back links for
whatever purposes." So I've done him a
favor. Now he's more willing to either
engage with my content, refer me to
people if he thinks that I am worthy of
referrals or even building a good
networking relationship. And so either
way, I win, you know, but this requires
time, attention, and personalization,
which is why most people quit and don't
do this. But honestly, it's worth it.
But now if I wanted to connect with
someone like Jordan who would have been
an ideal client during my agency days,
what I would have done is I would have
looked at his profile, would have
identified what was missing from his
LinkedIn strategy that would allow him
to win on LinkedIn or get him more
leads, more growth, more impressions,
whatever the metric that I want to go
for is. And then I would either send a
message very short being like, "Hey
Jordan, I just dropped you a 10-minute
loom sort of like giving you free X, Y,
and Z thing. Here's a link. Hope you
enjoy it. by and then in the loom I
would actually run him through exactly
what strategy I would implement for him
so he could actually start growing his
LinkedIn. I would even draft his first
five posts. I would give him the
strategy. I would tell him how to hire
the specific people that he needs to
grow his LinkedIn faster, the exact
templates, the exact photos, maybe some
swipe files that he can use for
reference, maybe even a charge bot that
I created just specifically for him,
whatever. something that screams
personalization. And then with that, I
would most likely at least land a call
with him to talk about the agency and
what I do, you know, and this type of
tactic is also called the Trojan horse
effect when you go in with a really
massive hit and then you really leave
people with no option than to hopping on
a call with you because you blew them
out of the park. I've done this and
people have done this for me. One of
them was one of my editors for YouTube
who is now a six-figure agency owner. So
it works. You just need to try enough
times. So if you do this 20 times a day
for as long as it takes until someone
replies, then you get three people on a
call to agree with you to some sort of
like service exchange. So you do it for
free for them for a while because at
this point you're starting from zero. So
you don't have any testimonials, so you
need them. Then you get them to give you
feedback and testimonials on your
service and obviously on the quality of
it. You use the feedback to iterate on
the service and make it better. And then
you use the testimonials to promote
yourself even more. So you use these to
repeat that again. So you have the
testimonials and you have the feedback.
So with the feedback, you're going to
iterate on your service and then charge
a premium price now. And then you use
the testimonials to then market this to
all the people. Okay, this literally is
a win-win. I am such a big fan of free
work because you cannot lose. You can
only win. There is only upside for you
in this. You get free real feedback from
people that would actually pay for the
service. Most of the time, these people
could also become your first paid
clients if you do a good enough job. And
at the end, you can actually have a
product that you would be pleased to
charge for. So, at the end of this, if
you charge people between $500 and
$2,000, you'll be good to go and on your
way to making your first $10,000. The
key here is your consistency of
outreach. And the more you do it, the
better you get at it. It's literally the
law of averages. I learned this from my
door to door sales. The more you do it,
the higher the chances of someone saying
yes to you. And the more you do it again
and again and again, the chances of
someone saying yes to you are higher. So
it really is a game of numbers. Let's do
the math. So if we get three clients at
$500, then you'll be at 1.5K a month,
right? And then if you get three clients
at 2,000, if you're charging more so for
our premium service and you're like
already a legend, then that's 6,000s a
month. Now, for the people that might be
like me in the past and unsure about
charging, I get it. It's hard to charge
for something that you did for free or
that is new to you. So, a very powerful
tip that I got from my mentor in 2023
when I was also scared of charging and
raising my prices, he said to me, "Only
raise your prices between $300 to $500
every time you get a new client. This
way, the jumps won't feel scary." And
they didn't. And using this is exactly
how I went from zero to charging 2,000
to even charging 5,000 at the peak of
the agency world. And then for the
cohorts between a,000 to 5,000 to
15,000. So number three, how to multiply
your income streams. Here's a problem
every service provider faces eventually.
There's only 24 hours in a day and if
you keep on selling your time, you will
eventually hit a ceiling. And the most
common answer for this is to hire. Now,
I could say that too, and I could be
like, "Yes, hire, create SOPs, go on
Fiverr, Upwork, etc." But I personally
didn't hire. I tried. I scaled my agency
with AI for the most of it. I tried
hiring writers to scale it even more,
but I simply just couldn't. I hired VAs
to assist me with minimal tasks for
clients and so on. But for me, the
easiest, lowest friction path that made
sense for me was to multiply my scale
into products, not hire more people.
See, by now with the done for you
service, you've been solving problems
one to one. Now, you're going to solve
them one to many. Here's exactly how it
works. You turn your service into a
repeatable framework. If you're a video
editor, for example, document your
editing process and then turn it into a
course or templates. If you're a writer,
you then package your email strategies
into a playbook. And if you're a fitness
coach, then you take your one-to-one
coaching and then you turn it into a
12-week group program people can
actually download online. Now, the
multiplier effect, how it works in
practice, I've seen it happen and I saw
it recently with one of my exclients.
They have the agency and they were
making 4 million. They realized that
they didn't need more clients now
because they've hit their ideal ceiling
of how many people they probably want to
have. I don't really know what they can
do to still increase their profit
margins is to have a cohort or a program
where is one too many. So this means
that they can start instead of charging
5,000 for one month for one client,
they're charging maybe 3,000 or 5,000
for 6 weeks for one person and then
they're doing it to multiple people and
then they're delivering the same thing
to multiple people for less time. So
they're buying their time back
essentially. So doing things one to many
isn't just for content creators or
people that are in the personal branding
space. It's for everyone. Agency owners,
consultants, coaches, fitness trainers,
teachers, AI AI professionals,
engineers, anyone can do this. And it's
honestly the smartest thing you can do
because you're doing less work for more
money. So instead of charging 1,000 to
work onetoone, you can charge 1,000 per
seat for a four-week program to 10
people, right? With just 10 people,
that's $10,000 in one program. With 25
people, you're already hitting $25,000
in one month without doing more work.
Just because I have time, I'm going to
lay out exactly how I turned my agency
services into a program that actually
worked. Then I'm going to show you how I
built it, where I hosted, and then how I
marketed it. Okay, so first things
first, the program. So the program is
built out of your SOPs and your systems
and all of your coaching calls. So if
you've had coaching calls, if you have
transcript from clients, if you have
their results, then you can understand
what problems they usually have, where
are the bottlenecks, how to get them
their results, right? And then once you
standardize that process, you can turn
it into a course that then can be turned
into the cohort's curriculum. So every
single problem you've ever solved for a
client, it's a part of your new
curriculum that you're going to build
and educate people on. To make this the
most comprehensive thing as possible,
let's say you're an executive coach. You
coach people onetoone. You help them do
X, Y, and Zed. You help them get sudden
transformation. You maybe you take them
from $50,000 a month to $100,000 a month
to even a million dollars a month. But
you've only done this one to one. Now,
to do this one to many, you're going to
take exactly what you do with your
onetoone clients, but you're going to
turn it into a 12week program that
people can take every single week,
right? And then you're going to take
like week one, how to hire, week two,
how to create SOPs, week three, how to
fire, week four, how to look at your
accounts, whatever it is, like all of
these things, right? Every single thing
that you do with clients onetoone then
can be systematized and optimized for an
hourong lesson and then after that do
the sequence and then that's 12 weeks.
That's literally it. And that is
essentially the curriculum of your
12-week program done because you are
giving people the problem and then
you're giving them the solution because
most people don't even know where the
problem is and maybe they know one but
they don't know the 12, right? Or they
don't know the six or whatever how long
you choose to make your program. So
that's how you build the program. And
then because most cohorts or programs
have the live element, you can actually
add a Q&A session at the end of each
call or if you film the curriculum
content like a course and you have it
and you host it and you give it to
people and then you also give them a
weekly call with you, then you'll also
be able to get more feedback live on
demand. So you can then iterate on the
next version of this exact same product,
which is again why I love cohost because
you get live feedback, you're also
getting paid, you're having a lot of
fun, and you're doing technically less
work. Now, where to host it? There are
multiple places you can host things like
this. It's become incredibly easy to
actually have your coaching or your
services like your one to many services
on the month. I personally use Pablo.
Then you could also use Sako, you could
use Slack, you could use school, you
could use hot. So, whatever fits your
brand works and whatever feels more
intuitive to you. I think most of them
have free trials, so you can test them
all out, but it just depends on your
crowd as well. You want to try and
optimize for whatever feels more
intuitive for your customer. If I took
B2B person onto Discord, I think they'll
probably crash out. Probably keep them
on Slack. But if I had to take one of my
creator friends onto Discord, that'll be
fine because they probably are used to
using it. But now, if you put me on a
platform like school, I'd crash out. So
now the marketing for these cohorts or
programs or coaching whatever we want to
call it there's multiple different ways
mentorships. Now the marketing of these
this could be an entire different video
so I'm going to leave it there but the
single best way to market anything
[music] online. So the first thing is
build an engaged email list so you can
sell to people. I've said this before
but around 70 to 80% of my total revenue
from this year has come from emails. So
it has been a massive advantage to build
one rather than prioritizing being in
this content hamster wheel uh and being
a slave to the algorithm. I am a slave
to email and I own my audience and I can
sell directly to them anytime I want. So
100%. Then the next thing to marketing
these things is use case studies. People
want to resonate with the product. They
want to see it. They want to envision
themselves in it and using it and they
want to see how you solved a problem for
someone that looks exactly like them.
the amount of times that people have
bought my product because I said one
single thing that made it click. So you
need to understand exactly what problems
are you actually fixing and how. Right?
So then you rinse and repeat this with
launches. You run them as many times as
you can handle and each one can generate
between 100k to 300k. And that's how you
stack revenue without stacking hours.
This is exactly how I went from a
six-figure service business to multiple
six-fig launches. And this is exactly
how we've gotten people like Thea inside
of one of my cohorts to go from zero to
50K launches in four to five days using
my exact systems, frameworks, and
strategies. And now we've even added
email sequences that people can use. So
if you're interested, I don't know when
we're going to open the next one, but if
you want to join the weight list for
that, then I'll leave the link in the
description so you can join. Now, for my
perfectionists at the back, your first
cohort, your first program doesn't need
to be perfect. It just needs to deliver
what your customers need. Your process
is the product. That's it. You can
iterate in the future. My first cohort
was a mess. I didn't know what I was
doing. I had to have my friends
involved. The website wasn't ready on
time. I didn't know how to market it. I
actually only had one sale in the first
24 hours and I thought it was a failure.
Strip didn't work. I literally made up
the entire curriculum, but it ended up
giving me the best results in the
planet. So, honestly, you're not being a
perfectionist. You're just
procrastinating. It's like perfectionism
is procrastination in disguise. My best
piece of advice, build your curriculum,
start marketing it, build a weight list
and then ship the product within four to
six weeks. It just needs to deliver what
customers need. Your process is a
product. Now, yes, I know what you're
thinking, Lara, how do I market that
though? Or like, hey, I don't have 1
million followers and I won't be able to
sell anything. Or maybe you're even
thinking, hey, I am scared to sell to my
audience. And I get it. I had all of
these exact same thoughts when I started
to. But actually, when you start
promoting your offer online, you
actually gain so much more trust and
traffic. And I don't just say this, I
have seen it play out time and time and
time again. The first time I ran a
launch after never ever ever promoting
my services, I had the most leads and
inquiries for my agency and consulting.
Like, I'd never had so much pipeline in
my life. And this was off the back of a
very intense launch where I was spamming
people about my services, my business,
what I was offering, etc. Now, let me
really tell you why this works. It's all
about psychology. People can only buy
what they are aware of. Most of your
audience isn't sitting there thinking, I
need their service right now. They might
not even realize that they have a
problem you solve or that you know how
to solve it. And that's why building a
personal brand is so powerful because it
creates awareness, trust, and demand
that compounds over time. You also get
to market anything you want for free. No
ads, no spend, just good content,
especially if you do it on LinkedIn.
Duh. Shocking that I mentioned LinkedIn.
So, here's how you build a personal
brand. So, first you need to pick a
platform. So, either where you have the
most followers or where your ideal
clients are. And the second thing is you
need a content system. So something that
you actually know works that is
validated for you and your niche and
that you can stay consistent with
because otherwise if you start creating
content let's say you start a 60 to 90
day posting challenge right and you post
90 days but then day 91 you quit because
you are overwhelmed you're burnt out and
you don't know what to talk about right
so the platform let's say you're going
to choose LinkedIn and the content
system well you're going to use this
thing that I call the 4321 [music]
method I invented this myself after
talking to so many of my clients and
realizing there is a common denominator
and that is the belief that you need to
have an extraordinary amount of quantity
in order to make it big on LinkedIn. So
the reason why I love LinkedIn so much
is because it is not a platform where
you have to push quantity. Quality is
what's important. Now let me break it
down. So the four it stands for four
posts every single week. So, not five,
not six, not 7, not 12, four. That is
the sweet spot with content, right?
Because four is just enough to build a
presence over time that compounds
without burning yourself out. And it's
not so little like 3, two, or one that
it makes you not have enough data to
then validate and then reiterate in the
future. Okay? So, that's four posts a
week. Now, the three is for the three
types of content that you're going to be
using. So, you're going to be
storytelling, you're going to be
educating, and you're going to be
selling. Right? After analyzing
thousands of LinkedIn posts and
thousands of accounts over the last 3
years, I've realized that the best
creators do two things very well. They
either educate or or they storytell,
right? And then they sell off the back
of it. Now, the 0.1% of entrepreneurs
and creators on LinkedIn and overall on
social media, they educate and storytell
at the same time. They do both
simultaneously, which allows them to
gain more brand equity over time, right?
So, what you're going to be doing is
you're going to be storytelling maybe
two times a week and then maybe
educating once and then selling once. Or
you can do it the other way around. You
could be storytelling once. You could be
educating twice and then you could be
selling once, right? So, whatever ratio
fits your narrative. I would usually be
storytelling twice and then educating
once and then selling once. Or when I'm
not selling, I'll be educating twice and
then storytelling twice. And then if I
really felt like I had nothing to talk
about that I'd be educating three times
a week and then I'd be selling once or
storytelling once just depend. The two
is for the two types of people you want
to be reaching online. Right? So we have
one thing that a lot of people will
understand and know and that is the ICP.
So your ideal client persona, right? Or
your ideal client profile or whatever
you want to do it. So this is who people
usually write their content to. Now the
problem is that I don't think that is
enough. The next thing you want to be
focusing on is your IFP. Your ideal
follower persona. A lot of people don't
take this into consideration, but I
think it's incredibly important to
understand this. Your ideal follower is
not someone that's going to buy from
you, at least not immediately. It's
someone that can buy from you in the
long term, but while you're building
that IFP, they're going to redirect your
ICP to you. It becomes almost like a
cycle, right? An ideal follower then
becomes an ideal customer. An ideal
customer then becomes an ideal follower,
and so on and so forth. And the reason
why most people fail at growing their
personal brands is because they do not
take the second one into consideration.
People are so obsessed with the idea of
ICP that they forget that in order to to
get the most ideal customers online, you
need to be reaching wider audience.
That's why people think about it in
funnels like top, bottom, and middle of
funnel. The bigger your funnel, the
bigger your top of funnel, the more
people you can get into the bottom of
your funnel, right? It is not and that's
why people creating content like 10
times a week about you know ghost
writing for doctors or ghost writing for
dentists and then the content is so
niche that it never reaches a wider
audience of people who could actually be
their ideal clients because they're
focusing on the one thing too much.
Right? And it's not about becoming a
niche. It's more so about niching down
to twice a week and then niching up two
days of the week. Right? That's why we
have the three and the four and the
three. the four pieces of content, then
the three types of like the three
content pillars and then the two ICPS
and then the one. So now the one is
important because this is how people are
actually going to make money of their
personal brand and that is lead magnets.
Lead magnets are my pride and joy. I am
obsessed with lead magnets. They have
genuinely changed my life. So what are
they? Lead magnets are something that
you use which is a free resource that
then you lead to people to then having
to opt in into your newsletter, right?
So you bribe them with free stuff so
they can give you their email for free.
And then after a while you collect their
emails, then you can market directly to
them because you own that audience. So
you are not at mercy of the algorithm.
You're not at mercy of being
shadowbanned. You're not at mercy of
anything. You show up on your ideal
customers emails every single morning.
If your emails are good, obviously then
they'll open them, right? So, if you
follow 4321 every single week for the
next 60 days, and then you deliver one
incredible lead magnet, maybe once a
week, maybe once a month, depending on
how much bandwidth you have to create a
lead magnet, and then you redistribute
that traffic to your newsletter, and
then you start sending weekly emails. I
promise that not only your personal
brand will grow, but also your business
one way or the other. There is no way
you can fail. Okay, with the content
part, I'm not meant to be saying this
right now cuz it's not about content
strategy, but if you want to learn how
to create viral content, you're going to
be using my slate framework. I created
it for myself because I like stories,
but then I realized they kind of sounded
cringe because I I didn't want to talk
about myself all the time. But then I
was like, well, stories retain people
and grab attention, but then I retain it
even more when I give education. So the
sleigh framework is you start with a
story, lead with a lesson, have
actionable advice and then end with a U.
[music] So let's say I am an email
marketer and I start my story with
saying I dropped out of university to go
all in on emails. Here's exactly how I
started. So that's the two lines of
story. That's it. Then the lesson. Step
number one, I started by buying Lara's
email course. Step number two, I then
understood how to get my first client.
Step number three, I got my first 10
clients. Then I became I started working
with a Fortune 500 business. Step number
four, etc. Right? That's a lesson.
That's the actual piece of advice.
You're actually teaching someone how to
do something, right? So, let me break it
down for you. So, story. Last year, I
was broke, but today I made my first six
figures. Here's exactly how I did it. I
started by doing one thing, then I did
the other the next thing, then I did
this thing, then I did this thing.
Right? So, when was the last time you
started from zero? So that is the sort
of body and the skeleton of a viral post
using the slay framework. So I started
with a story. Then I led with a lesson.
Then I gave actionable advice by
breaking it up into a listical. And then
I turned it into a you so people can
engage with me. I can connect with my
audience. I can build a community. I can
also fabricate engagement. And then I
can use their comments as more content
ideas for the future. It is literally
that simple. Obviously a bonus tip for
people that are struggling even when
they have all of this. Let's say, "Hey,
Lara, I already tried all of this, but
it's not working." You need to
understand again the power of
positioning. So on LinkedIn
specifically, positioning is important
in the way of how you look and how you
present yourself. The more professional
you seem, the better you're going to be
received. So this is why you'll see a
lot of people using photos from
conferences, podcasts, keynotes. Maybe
they'll have a professional photo shoot.
Like this type of investment up front.
Even if it is taking your friends out to
take photos of you somewhere that you
look somewhat professional is important.
That's how I started. I only went to
networking events so I could get candid
photos so I could use on my LinkedIn to
then leverage and it worked right. You
do the things that you need to do until
you get the thing that you want to have.
Now do personal branding well and it
becomes a multiplier of everything and
anything. It can literally change your
life. It certainly did for me. This type
of multiplier is what takes a $100,000
business into a $500,000 business or
more, even to [music] a million. So,
visibility creates trust and trust
creates demand. So, you need to remember
this anytime you're trying to think
about whether it's worth to build your
personal brand. It definitely is and I'm
going to hone in on it until I die.
Okay. Now, let's talk about the wealth
multiplier and how this actually works
in practice. Once you built your service
business, then you managed to scale it
into something that gives you your time
back, but you're still making more
revenue. Then you've built your personal
brand alongside doing all of these and
getting clients and more opportunities.
You're scaling your revenue and you're
documenting everything live. By now, you
understood the power of building a
parcel run alongside building a
service-based business because it cost
you zero dollars. Then you understood
how to monetize it even more without
trading your time for money. And now you
kind of like multiply that revenue. So
now after that if for a period of time
you talked about doing the thing, you
showed yourself doing the thing, you
documented yourself doing the thing and
then other people are also talking about
you doing the thing. Let's say clients
giving you case studies when you're
launching. You're creating a little FOMO
and demand. You're like literally
pushing everything out. You're using
lead magnets to amplify your presence
because the lead magnets suddenly become
the playbooks that you used to use for
clients etc. By now you will be able to
unlock things that you thought that
you'd never get access such as
sponsorships, speaking engagements,
equity and co-founding on roles, angel
investments and that is the big shift
that happened for me. In the beginning,
you have to fight for every client. But
later, once you build the products, the
system and a brand, opportunities
literally start chasing you. So like I
said at the beginning, I am now building
a B2B SAS. I also have equity in other
businesses. I also became an angel
investor. On top of that, I have I have
the agency. I have the education
business. I'm building another agency.
And I'm building another B2B cohort
coming out in the next few months. So
like here I have four different things.
So all of these things in this site I
created by myself with $0 and doing it
online and the main marketing model was
my personal brand. Right? For the B2B
SAS I found my co-founder on LinkedIn
who is Jake Wood who also my friend and
we started together. We understood that
we could both leverage our audience
because we had a good product and now we
also have winning distribution together.
Him and I, we have around 400,000
followers combined just on LinkedIn. Now
with the B2B stars, we found a problem
that we could fix which was content
creation and then we partnered up to
start this thing and that we're trying
to scale that to a million dollars AR as
soon as possible. Now with the equity
deals, I get offers for these all the
time because I have the power of
distribution which I created through
building the agency, through building
the education business, to building the
other agency and building cohorts that
have led to, you know, $150,000
of worth of revenue in a month or like
$100,000 like multiple six figure
launches, right? And through all of
these experience and expertise and
[music]
also proof, I then get eyeballs or
people seeing my value in the market as
an equity or shareholder, co-founder or
co-owner because I've proven to the
market that I can do certain things that
other people can't or that they don't
have enough experience in. And then the
distribution that I have as well. So
while I stacked my skill set and then
while I stacked clients on top of this
and I built my brand equity through
documenting it on LinkedIn, I gained
access to all of these three things
[music] that then multiply my wealth,
not just my income, right? For example,
so by now I've got about five to 10
deals on either having equity on
different businesses or becoming a
co-owner or co-founder. And the main
reason why these people want me in their
boards is for my distribution and also
my expertise, right? I get to have these
things like and these I don't have to
pay anything. I get paid. Doing the
first four steps is a massive unlock
that people are consistently looking
for. Also spend a lot of money to
obtain. You can get access to all of
these things for free if you do it for
long enough and you do it well. Now the
last thing I want to talk about is angel
investing because I actually get a lot
of questions about how I started angel
investing. So, my first angel investment
was in this drink called New Tonic. Uh,
founded by Chris Williamson and James
Smith. I truly believe in the brand
because I drink it myself every single
day, three times a day. So, the reason
why I invested is it's a founder
business. Uh, it's very much personal
branding back which aligns with my
values. Um, I like the product. I like
the the founders and it just made sense.
And it's also a great brand move if I'm
being completely honest. And on top of
that, you also get access to maybe
sponsorship deals and speaking deals if
you have enough brand equity, right? So,
B2B businesses want to be sponsoring
personal brands that have enough market
reach or brand equity or total market uh
value, etc. So, then they can promote
the tools to the audience for [music] in
exchange for a monetary gain. Okay? And
then speaking is the same. But to be
honest, I usually don't charge for
speaking. I'm still doing it for the
experience and also for the photos. So
that's why I do speak and I also love
it. So it's become a side hustle of
mine. In the beginning you have to fight
for every client. But then later once
you build products, a system and a brand
opportunity start chasing you. And that
ladies and gentlemen is the zero to $1
million road map that I would follow if
I had to start from zero all over again.
Ladies and gentlemen, if you got any
value from this, then please hit the
subscribe button and drop a comment and
tell me what your favorite part was. And
if you have any questions, please drop
them in the comments. I'll be answering
every single one of them. And if you
want to learn my entire LinkedIn
personal branding blueprint that took me
from zero to 250,000 followers, then
watch it here and I'll see you there.
Now, talking about email, I've shared a
few strategies here, but I laid out my
exact email strategies that attributed
to around 70% of our revenue this year.
I also talk about limiting beliefs
around email, how to do it well, how to
write, and the exact tools I use to
write killer emails every single time
that get me clients and generate me
thousands every single time. So, I'll
drop the link down below if you want to
check it