Every single entrepreneur that wants to
grow their personal brand on LinkedIn
this year needs to focus on one thing
first. No one talks about this, but I
know this because I've seen it multiple
times. They don't focus enough on
understanding their unfair advantages.
So, if you're an entrepreneur, you have
different things that you can utilize as
content themes. It's not about
educating. It's not about inspiring.
It's not about storytelling. It's not
about selling. It's about you. That's
what makes a personal brand unique. Most
people are using crazy strategies,
templates, etc. and they don't work or
if they work it's a one-off. What you
need to understand is that you need to
list down exactly what your unfair
advantages are. What this means is the
things that make you unique to the
market. So it could be from people that
you've worked with to things that you
specifically do to your unique mechanism
or system that you have implemented in
your business or for other people.
Right? These are content ideas. Now
let's say you have a unique mechanism.
So it's a sales system. It's seven steps
and you have a name for it. This is an
educational piece of content. You can
tell people exactly how this works. And
then with that piece of content, you're
informing your ideal client of exactly
what you do, who you do it for, and how
in one single piece of content. You
don't have to over complicate everything
like everybody keeps on trying to tell
you. It's not about the perfect
strategy. It's about the perfect way to
communicate what you do every single
time. If you have one single system, for
example, this could be turned into five
different types of content. One is
educational. The second one is a case
study of how you implemented that
system. The third one is a story about
how you even found it. Then the two next
ones could be a lead magnet and a sales
post. That's five pieces of content
ready for you with one single idea. It's
not about over complicating everything.
It's about just knowing exactly what you
do. Stop copying other people. Stop
being yourself in your business cuz
that's what's making you money. Now, how
we create content with that idea every
single week without fail. Firstly, you
need to understand that LinkedIn is not
a quantity game. It's a quality game.
Ignore what Gary Vee is saying. As much
as I love him, quality is what the main
players are doing right now on LinkedIn.
Volume is a long-term play. I can do
volume now because I've got thousands
and thousands and thousands of posts
written. But at the start, I was only
posting three times. That allowed me to
grow from zero to 50,000 followers to
then 100,000 followers at literal rocket
speed. I wasn't posting five times. I
wasn't posting 10. I was posting three.
Three or four pieces of quality content.
That's all you need. So, how you operate
in this way? You think about it in two
ways. So the 80/20 rule, 80% educational
content, 20% storytelling content. Or if
you want to do it another way, you could
do 20% educational content and 80%
storytelling content. Whatever resonates
with you the most. You can go back and
forth every single week until you find
what resonates with your audience.
Because ideally, you need to be treating
LinkedIn like a testing ground. Every
single post is giving you data and
feedback. You're getting live feedback
loops on what is performing well and
what your audience actually wants to
hear from you. Let me give you an
example. When I started LinkedIn, I was
trying to copy everyone. I was trying to
curate content. I was trying to talk
about TED talks. I was trying to talk
about books. I was using someone else's
strategy. And then one day I spoke about
storytelling and then the other day I
started writing about how to actually
make money as a writer. And guess what?
Those posts not only went viral, but
also attributed into the most leads. So
then if I hadn't tested enough formats
and enough content types, I wouldn't
have found the thing that made it work
for me. So then I found the thing, I
doubled down, then I triple down, and
then I 10x from there. So that's exactly
what you should do to create your
content system that you use every single
week. Now, let's talk about the idea of
picking a niche because I've seen a lot
of videos talking about becoming the
niche and that you are the niche.
Honestly, I don't think that works. It
never worked for me and I haven't seen
it work for anyone else. For example,
Alexi, he is the niche, but guess what?
Before being the niche, he was the
person of influence when it came to
fitness. And then after that he went so
big he dominated that single niche that
he was able to scale up to the business
niche and now he is the best known for
being himself. If you think Alexi you'll
think about many multiple things like
business growth, sales and even fitness.
But to get there he had to own every
single niche step by step. The best way
to think about it is that you niche down
then you niche up and then you go broad.
So if you don't know what your niche is
just think about what is your main area
of expertise. What are you doing in the
job that you have if you have a 9 to5
right now? Or what are you actually
talented or even excited about? So for
me, I didn't have a niche. I was just a
broad marketer. Now marketing is the
most broadest term in the industry. It
can be SEO, it could be digital
marketing, it could be agency, it could
be copywriting, it could be YouTube
scripting, it could be anything, right?
So when I realized that that wasn't
going to make me any money, I realized,
okay, I like how to write, I can tell
stories, I dominated LinkedIn because I
was able to write and grow fast and I
was getting leads from it faster than
ever. So I realized, okay, copywriting
is a niche. And then the vehicle to
monetization is being able to get leads
from LinkedIn specifically. So then
guess what? My niche became LinkedIn
ghost writing for founders. It's that
simple. You don't need to over
complicated. It doesn't need to be
copied from someone else. You need to
figure out what you could do on and on
and again even if you weren't paid for
it because guess what? At the start, I
wasn't being paid for it. I enjoyed it.
And then it made it easy to monetize
over the long term. Now you have your
own for advantage. So you know exactly
how you can stand out. you have your
niche, so you know exactly who you're
selling to and what you're being known
for. Now, let's get into content
strategy. Now, let me make it simple for
you. If you're overthinking about what
to write, how to write, this is the
blueprint. Basically, LinkedIn right now
rewards posts that are written with a
photo. Don't do video because that's
going to be a long-term play. If you
want to do video, just know that this is
an authority play. And what I mean by
authority play is that it's not going to
be the most viral. It's not going to get
you the most followers, but it's
definitely going to help you connect
with your audience. So, if that is your
priority, then 100% do it. But if you're
trying to, you know, speedrun to 100,000
followers as fast as possible, quite
honestly, it's going to be a waste of
your time. I love video more than
anyone. You see me on YouTube all the
time. But if I'm being realistic, video
isn't optimized for LinkedIn. Just
naturally, LinkedIn is not a video
platform. So, please, if you want to
grow, use copy first and a good photo.
Now, I need to talk about photos because
I have beef with this issue. Basically,
when I say photo and image, your image
needs to position yourself as an expert.
A lot of people use photos from holidays
or even photos from Pinterest. Please do
not do this. You are an authority and
you are a leading expert. So you need to
look like that. Photos speaking on
stages, on a podcast, high quality
photos that are professionally taken or
even candid photos of you speaking to
someone else at a networking event.
These are the photos that actually work.
This is the reality. And I know it's
hard, but what I did to get myself to
this position is that I said yes to
every single networking event I could go
to so I could just get the photos and
use them for my LinkedIn. And over time
I started getting more opportunities
speaking etc. This is also how you build
authority over time. The more places
you're being seen at doing cool things,
the more cool opportunities are going to
come your way and the better things
you're going to have to talk about on
your LinkedIn. So with this, you're
creating a literal flywheel of
opportunities coming your way from the
first networking event you go to. Then
you're getting a photo at it. Then
you're meeting cool people that will
invite you to the next one and so on and
so forth. and the next thing you know,
you're going to be speaking at one of
these events just because you posted
that one time on LinkedIn and it maybe
changed your life. Now, on to writing
the perfect LinkedIn post. I've got good
news and I've got bad news. The bad news
is that templates, hawks, etc., they do
work, but not as well. The good news is
that LinkedIn has changed. They are
prioritizing content that is not
perfectly optimized. So, I know for a
time you probably seen on your LinkedIn
that the best way to write a LinkedIn
post is probably having a short hug,
then a space, then another line. Right
now, that doesn't matter as much
anymore. What matters the most is your
subject matter expertise. So, if you
were a sales expert and you wanted to
write about your recent time at an expo,
you would say something like, I just
came back from this specific expo and I
did this exact same thing. The hook may
not be eight words long, but what you
have is keywords. So, you have sales
expo. You just said, "I came back and I
did this thing." That as a result
attracts more attention than the perfect
most well-created hook. I've seen it a
lot over the last three weeks. We've
been analyzing this specifically and
closely because a few months ago during
counts, LinkedIn actually hosted this
specific event talking about what they
are prioritizing on LinkedIn right now.
And what they are prioritizing right now
is expert-led content, not the best
curated content. So, please do not worry
too much about the perfect outline or
the perfect framework or the perfect
template. Just focus on being the
leading expert and making sure that your
content within the first two lines makes
you look like that. Now, for those that
want a specific writing framework, I've
got you. So, if you've got two, you've
got pass and you've got slay. So, pass
is problem, agitate, solution. First,
you open with a hook that's eight words
long and a rehook at the end. So, a
problem if you were this exact same
salesperson, it's like you are losing
out on leads if you're not using SEO,
right? And then the next line would be
here's exactly how to fix it. And then
the solution is you actually outline
step by step the solution. Simple. You
don't need to over complicated. Just
fill in the blanks. Now if you want to
tell a story about this exact same sales
expo, you need to use the sleigh
framework. So you tell the story. I just
came back from this event and I learned
this thing. This is exactly how I did
it. And what about you? So story lesson
actionable piece of advice and a you.
It's so simple to use. You just need to
think about the main story and what's in
it for the reader. Because obviously
every story is interesting only if you
make it interesting to read. And how you
make something interesting to read is
you connect it to a solution that your
ideal audience wants. Basically what's
in it for me? Always think about it like
that when you're storytelling on
LinkedIn. Now next you're going to be
putting all of this effort into creating
content. The perfect strategy you know
writing your LinkedIn content. So the
thing that you need to be aware of is
that in order for people to see your
content you need to become visible. And
the fastest way to do this is not a
oneoff viral post. is actually
leveraging the one thing LinkedIn is
built under and that is networking and
connections. So the connection game on
LinkedIn is very different to any other
platform. Most platforms just have
followers. LinkedIn has followers and
connections. The easiest way to get seen
is to build that connection base by
engaging and connecting with people
directly. So you connect with people
directly by adding them one by one. The
easiest way is to just add 10 people or
20 people every single day within your
niche or adjacent niches so you can get
that volume and distribution from
different parts of LinkedIn. So over
time as you create more content then it
gets seen by more people. Now to
leverage those connections and actually
nurture them, you actually need to talk
to them. So how do you talk to people
that are strangers online? Just like a
networking event really. You're going to
be commenting on their content. You're
going to be engaging with it. You're
going going to be liking it. And even if
you actually want to go a step further,
you're going to DM them. When I started
LinkedIn, I spent about 8 hours
commenting, engaging, and hopping on
networking calls. Coffee chats, I call
them. And these exact same coffee chats
have allowed me to literally leverage
every single one of their connections to
now grow from zero to 250,000 followers
and even more because I made the time to
build those connections. But if I
hadn't, I am certain that I wouldn't be
in the position that I am today. Now,
with commenting, I have one tip that I
need to give you because this is going
to be super useful for you. When you're
trying to comment, please do not just
comment great post or thumbs up. You
actually need to give them something to
relate to. So, treat every single
LinkedIn comment as a mini post. In the
past, when I was trying to grow my
LinkedIn, I didn't know what to comment
and my comments were vague, too basic,
too fluffy. They didn't really matter.
They didn't make an impact. And what
happened was I was technically wasting
my time. So the best way to look at
things is look at the post and then see
where can I add value? Can I actually
relate? Can I tell a story behind the
scenes of this or can I make a funny
joke? That is the best way to create the
best comments. And also if you think
about it, LinkedIn right now is counting
the impressions your comments get. So
you can tell how important LinkedIn
comments are right now for the platform
because they enhance the experience of
every single LinkedIn user. Again,
making it a networking platform, not
just a social media platform where
people are creating viral content just
for the sake of it. LinkedIn genuinely
wants people to connect with each other
and build professional relationships.
So, think about it like that. Even if
it's not your style, even if it's not
your thing, it needs to become your
thing if you want to win. So, that's
everything you need to know about how to
build a personal brand on LinkedIn in
2025. We've gone from unfair advantages
to content strategy to the best
frameworks to even how to comment. The
playbook is now yours. And now all you
need to do is implement it. But if you
need more help, you can download my
7-day free crash course on how to grow
and scale your personal brand on
LinkedIn. It's down below. Check it out
and I'll see you in the next