I just made the boldest prediction of my
career and it's about LinkedIn in 2026.
And if I'm right, 90% of current
LinkedIn users are about to become
completely irrelevant.
Look, I've been tracking early signals
in the algorithm, studying emerging
content patterns, and watching what the
smartest creators are quietly testing.
And what I'm seeing is a massive shift
that's going to change everything about
how growth works on LinkedIn right now.
I just hopped off a call with my team.
Together, they've analyzed thousands of
LinkedIn posts from the last 6 months.
The data is clear. 3 years ago, when I
started blowing up on LinkedIn, the feed
rewarded nearly anything. Simply posting
at all could lead to more reach.
LinkedIn's algorithm rewarded people
creating more content. That's it. They
wanted to supply the overdemand that we
still have right now. We can even see it
in the videos that were blowing up back
then. How to optimize your profile, how
to use sales navigator, how to write an
about section. the bare minimum effort
would lead to the highest return. And
that's where we saw the boom of cringe
storytelling, the here's what I learned
about B2B sales post, the motivational
quotes that even Tony Robbins would even
cringe at reading. It was a true blue
ocean. But now, like in any other
platform, the algorithm has begun
rewriting itself. It's no longer
rewarding quantity. It's rewarding
expertise, but not the expertise in the
way you think. LinkedIn is now hunting
for domain authorities. people who can
actually prove they've done the thing
that they're teaching. And just so you
know, I'm not making this up like every
other LinkedIn expert. This is
information directly from their can
event LinkedIn themselves hosted 3
months ago indicating this exact same
shift. And although my invite got lost
in the mail for this alongside my
influencer box with LinkedIn merch in it
and a DJI mic, we also found content
written by the news editor from LinkedIn
confirming this again. And yeah, I got
my own DJI mic anyway, so it doesn't
matter. So, here's how LinkedIn is
starting to shift. Now, let's take Adam
Robinson. He has 138,000 followers on
LinkedIn. But that isn't the most
impressive thing about him. Adam has
blown up his account, ignoring common
LinkedIn advice. Instead, he focused on
being seen as a domain expert, which has
led him to drive millions for his
business. His content is truly
expert-led, sharing results, sharing
trends, even sharing unique opinions he
has as someone who is in the true
trenches of his industry. Meaning that
he gets pushed to the right audience for
him and rewarded by LinkedIn because
shockingly enough, this is the content
they like to see the most. Expertled.
Now, this might sound obvious, but the
truth about obvious things is that
people still ignore them. And for a good
reason. If you log on to LinkedIn right
now, you'll see three viral posts with a
quote on them. 10 leadership hacks that
will change your life. Thousands of
likes in them and then a post like Adams
with 500 likes. But here's the thing.
Likes are no longer the metric that
matters for true personal brand
performance, especially if your goal is
to drive sales to your business. Because
while those feelood posts are collecting
dopamine and engagement, Adam's posts
are collecting qualified leads. And
speaking about collecting leads, there
is an easy and effective way to start
collecting them. I actually used this
when I had no time to build a landing
page or set up a new website or a new
email list or pick and choose between
different platforms and connect to them.
And the thing that I'm referring to is
Stanto. It's like the digital shop
window for your business except it
doesn't suck. You can host free
resources, collect emails, sell digital
products, launch offers all in one
place. And the best part, it literally
takes five minutes to set up. I've done
it myself multiple times. You don't need
a website. There's no tech headaches.
Just a clean link you can drop on the
every single post or even in your
profile or your bio. I've used it many,
many times. I actually even used this to
launch my first ever lead magnet.
Collected thousands of emails before I
even had a real offer, literally. So, if
you're building your personal brand and
you don't have a link that collects and
converts, then you're probably leaving
some money on the table. So, if you want
to make your first online dollar on
LinkedIn or even your first $100,000,
Stanto store is the easiest place to
start. I'm dropping a free trial link in
the description so you can test it out.
Now, back to Adam. His business is
growing. His offers are converting. His
audience are also his customers. That's
the shift most LinkedIn users are
missing. You don't need viral content.
You need the right content in front of
the right people delivered with real
credibility. And eventually, these posts
become viral posts. I've done exactly
that as well. Every single one of my
LinkedIn posts is expert-led. Yet,
they've reached virality not because
they're broad and generic, but because
they're useful. They position me daily.
Data collected via my own account and
clients further emphasizes on this
point. Posts from verified experts gets
increasingly more reach than generic
advice posts. Expertex expert engagement
triggers massive algorithmic
amplification just naturally by how
LinkedIn connects people behind the
scenes. Think about it like this. Every
time two domain experts engage with each
other, LinkedIn goes, "Interesting." Two
domain experts in the same topic are
engaging with each other. So instead of
showing it to your usual circle, it
pushes that content out to people just
like them. Almost like when you talk
about a celebrity and then Instagram all
of a sudden shows you them on your feed
the next day, or when you like a cat
post on Twitter and then you get 10 more
of them. Now, here's my bold prediction.
By the end of 2026, LinkedIn will be
dominated by expert prneurs. Not content
creators, not motivational speakers,
expertreneurs. Now, if you're not a
domain expert yet, I'll get to you in a
second. I promise I've got good news for
you, too. But expertreneurs are people
who combine both deep expertise with
entrepreneurial execution. The ones who
live and breathe speed over motivational
fluff. The ones who are seen doing the
thing rather than just talking about it.
The blue ocean is still there for
LinkedIn, but is shifting from an anyone
can post to an expert-led content wins.
The era of the micro niches where no one
has claimed expert status yet has just
begun. And I've seen this done to near
perfect execution. This is my friend
Jake and also one of my co-founders for
a software business. He saw the wave of
viral storytelling and decided not to
hop on it. Instead, he microniched down
on the one thing, SEO. At the time, SEO
content looked like this and like this.
Broad, boring, vague. So, he decided to
share the entire playbook out for free
every day for 2 years. Today, he's
nearly at 200,000 followers. He's a top
expert for SEO on LinkedIn. And he's
never shared a crying selfie or a
productivity carousel. Whenever anyone
thinks about SEO, they think of him,
which drives hundreds of leads to his,
drum roll, SEO agency. Now the thing
here and this is important when he
started he was just like many of you
too. Not a domain expert not a renown
founder no fancy titles no online clout
just someone with a mini agency and one
goal lead generation. And over time he
earns the expert title. And this can
happen to anyone who does the exact same
thing. I see it happen nearly every
single month. AI consultants going from
zero to 50,000 followers in months and
then adding an extra $100,000 in revenue
in one single month. LinkedIn
strategists building seven figureure
agencies, niche experts becoming the
go-to voice in their industry. The
entrepreneurs who move fast in 2026 will
dominate. But the ones who hesitate will
spend years trying to catch up. Now,
here's why I'm sharing this prediction
so early in the year. There's still a 12
month window before everyone else
catches on because even if they hear it,
people won't actually do it until it's
too late. I've seen this pattern before.
Instagram in 2012, basic content,
massive growth. YouTube in 2015, simple
videos but millions of subscribers. Tik
Tok in 2019, anyone could go viral.
LinkedIn is having its expert moment
right now. But like I said, the blue
ocean has moved and it's becoming
smaller. The algorithm is actively
looking for domain experts to amplify.
Not just another influencer, not just
another viral creator. That's why
creators with viral content who tried to
hop on LinkedIn failed because that's
all they had. Viral flashy content, but
no real showcase of insights. And the
saddest part, most of them would
actually crush it on there. But they
lack the right frameworks to turn their
content into expertled content. And if
that sounds like you, I actually put
together a 7-day free course teaching
you exactly how to write, strategize,
and position yourself on LinkedIn. Check
it out in the description. It's free.
And while you're there, please subscribe
to my channel. My editors are going to
kill me at how long this video actually
is right now. So, please subscribe so
they don't quit. It helps us both. Thank
you. See, while everyone's trying to be
funny or inspirational, you can focus on
being useful. Now, here's the exact
strategy I'd use if I had to start from
zero. Today, you're going to go hyper
niche in your topic of expertise. So,
forget about saying I do marketing or I
do sales. Go microspecific like email
automations for e-commerce brands doing
1 million plus a year. With this, you
want to be the only person talking about
the specific thing or if not, you want
to be the best. Someone who's doing this
incredibly well is Daniel Bamante. He's
absolutely nailed expertled positioning.
Had the pleasure to meet him. Actually
had consulting with him and I found him
via LinkedIn. He's making thousands of
dollars off of his LinkedIn. So pretty
validated example here. And I also
reached out to him organically. So
that's double validation. Now step two
is that your headline needs an upgrade.
The headline formula has changed
completely. The old way is I help
businesses grow with marketing. That's
vague. Now the new way is something like
scaled 47 e-commerce brands past 5
millions with email automation free case
study below with an arrow lead with
proof then the promise then the delivery
mechanism and then your banner then aids
that process the more professional and
clean your banner looks the better. But
again, look at Adam Robinson's. You
don't need a mega designer for this.
Don't worry. Just show results, show
clients, show authority. Period. Now,
step three is your proof first content
strategy. 80% tactical post based on
your lived experience, 20%
behind-the-scenes content of you doing
the work. Every post needs to answer,
how do I know this person has actually
done this? screenshots, case studies,
before and after results. And if you
don't have them, then make sure your
content itself solves an issue for the
reader right then and there. It needs to
be applicable instantly in order to get
that social proof you may be lacking
right now if you don't have any case
studies or testimonials or social proof
or any of those things. But please, and
I say please, no more here's what I
learned post because they don't work.
Only here's what I did and here's what
happened posts. Please. And by the way,
you can also use storytelling to aid
this, too. I did this last week with
several of my posts where I referenced
personal stories, conversations, and
moments that I had in my real life. Then
I linked them back to one tip or one
lesson or one single thing that makes me
look like an authority in that field,
but I put a story on top of it so I felt
more emotionally connected to my
audience. And it works. Which leads me
to step number four, expertled
engagement system. Your comments need to
add expert level insights. Don't just
say great post, share a mini case study,
challenge an assumption, add a tactical
tip. Your comments become a mini post
that drive traffic back to your profile.
Now, for the bad news, you need to block
one to two hours daily for this. Yes, 2
hours. It's worth it. I promise. Now,
this is what I tell my extremely busy
clients because look, I get it. It's
tiring. It's long. But you need to do it
yourself for a while. then you can hire
people to do it for you once you
understand your own tone of voice and
your type of replies and who you
actually like engaging with. Now, I
still do this myself for at least 2
hours a day because it matters and it's
worth it. Now, here's the one thing I
want to talk about that no one on
YouTube has touched on yet, and it's
part of my new blueprint that I'm
building for 2026. Thought leadership
ads. This is where 2026 gets
interesting. See, thought leadership ads
are kind of new, but have proven to be
incredibly effective so far. You can't
even tell they're ads. So, the success
rate is massive. You're basically
boosting your own organic post and
putting them onto different feeds
manually every single day, but people
will perceive them as a normal post.
This is so smart. So, if you want to try
it, build some good organic content that
is proven to work. Showcase your
authority, have social proof, build a
case study, have a testimonial, have a
framework, then promote it as a thought
leader ad. reach thousands of more
people without creating more content.
This is like Facebook in 2015 all over
again. All right, so back to my bold
prediction. 90% of current LinkedIn
users will become irrelevant by 2026.
But not because their content is bad,
but because they're playing the wrong
game. They're still in the content
creation era. That is long gone. The
market has sophisticated way too much
for this. But now you know this before
literally anyone else. I need to tell
you this one last thing. You don't need
to be an expert to start doing all of
these things, but you do need to start
if you want to be seen as an expert in
the future. Quick recap because I know
so many of you have been requesting
them. This is the 2026 LinkedIn and
beyond blueprint. First, we covered how
the LinkedIn game completely changed
since 2024. The algorithm shifted from
rewarding quantity to rewarding
expertise. If you're still posting
motivational content, then I outlined
exactly how to get to expert level
content immediately. Then we broke down
exactly what this means in practice with
tactical examples. And finally, I
revealed the one thing that no one else
is talking about on YouTube or even on
LinkedIn. Thoughts leader ads, the new
secret weapon for entrepreneurs. So, if
you enjoyed this video, please subscribe
to the channel so we can keep up the
cadence. And also, maybe LinkedIn will
send me a suitcase if I hit 100K on here
or maybe a Top Voice badge or anything
like that. I'm not picky. All right.
Bye.