If I had to bet on one thing that could
guarantee your success as a business
owner today, it would be storytelling.
No doubt. Learning how to tell stories
is the fundamental pillar behind any top
brand [music] and personal brand you see
today. You've seen brands relentlessly
tell stories across the years. Take Nike
or Dolby as an example. And right now,
there is a storytelling framework that
is spreading across social media like
wildfire. I've watched creators in
completely different industries use the
exact same structure and get millions of
views and thousands of likes. So, I
decided to put it to the test for 6
weeks consecutively and the results
outperformed my usual content strategy
by 3x. Accumulated over a million views
just by using this format. And the best
part is I am seeing complete beginners
and creators who were stuck at no views
get thousands of views with it too. And
honestly, this is an insane entry-level
way to storytelling. No one has time to
read all of these storytelling books on
how to tell stories to tell stories to
other people that tell stories. I mean,
I didn't and I know you don't have time
either. So instead, I analyzed those who
were telling stories well and realized
that what makes this format and
ultimately all stories work on social
media today isn't just about following
an old school framework. It's actually
all about understanding key parts of
your story and connecting them back to
one key person, [music] your reader.
They need to become the focal point of
your story. Good stories are never about
you and always about them. This is
exactly why the POV format blew up
across YouTube, then Instagram, and it
can even be replicated on written first
platforms like LinkedIn. Because think
about it, this creates a character that
your audience immediately connects with
themselves. Every single successful POV
stories is about the audience, [music]
their potential, and the creator showing
them what's actually possible. A thing
that I noticed that most people actually
get wrong about storytelling is that
they always start with them. Common
storytelling like post on LinkedIn
sounds something like this. I am happy
to announce that I got a promotion at a
company that you've never heard of.
Okay? Or something like I woke up at
5:00 a.m. and journal for an hour. Okay?
But now, if you were to use the POV
format, this allows you to tell the
exact same stories via a different lens,
which completely flips the psychological
dynamic of how your audience consumes
your content. Instead of them being a
passive observer of your life, they
become an active character in their own
transformation story through your own
story. And this is amazing. Just think
about it. in basic content marketing
principles. There are three core pillars
being recited by the industry
consistently. Educate, entertain, and
storytell. [music]
This format does all three
simultaneously and easily. If we were to
break it down, you basically educate by
using the POV angle to link it to your
journey and leaving a key piece of
insight or education. If the one insight
is excellent, the post has done its job
in the education front. Then you
storytell by creating this narrative arc
that has a clear beginning, a
transformation, an outcome. And if you
pair it with the right images that
emphasize the key parts of the journey,
your job here is done. Now, lastly, we
have the entertainment pillar in written
form. This is often the hardest to crack
for most people because how could you
possibly make a piece of text
entertaining for someone? Most people
think that entertainment can only come
from videos, images, or memes. But in
written form, you can actually do it
using something else. Rhythm. Rhythm in
your lines. Let me show you. If I pull
out every single one of the POV posts
I've written over the last 6 weeks, you
can notice something similar. The lines
are strategically longer and shorter
with spaces in between for a reason.
They all flow like a song. They become
easy to digest. To achieve this, all you
need to do is mix a combination of
short, long, and medium length sentences
to keep the reader reading. And I could
talk about rhythm and flow for ages
because this has personally been such a
key part of my journey as a writer and a
creator. But instead, to save you and me
time, I'll leave you with this example
that emphasizes it well. Landing pages
today are formatted in a very similar
way because researchers noticed that
humans don't actually read content, they
scan it. There is this thing called the
F-shaped reading pattern. Eye tracking
studies show that when people look at
content online, their eyes move in an F
shape. So basically, people scan the
first line horizontally, then they scan
down the left side vertically, then they
scan another line horizontally onto
about halfway down, and then they go
back to scanning vertically down to the
left. And if we follow exactly how the
eyes are moving, you can literally see
the letter F when you map out the heat
zones of where the eyes go. And this is
why the first few words of every single
line that you actually write are
absolutely critical because if they
don't hook the reader, then they'll
never read the rest of your post and you
won't be able to educate them, entertain
them, or inspire them. All right, so now
you've got the context. Let's get into
the how to actually implement all of
this information. Let's go. Now, let's
say that you and me want to write the
typical LinkedIn I am so happy to
announce post I reacted to earlier, but
in a POV way. The way I'd rewrite it
would be POV, you get your dream tech at
27. Easy. How you need to be thinking
about POV stories is by asking questions
about what you've actually been doing.
If you got your first high ticket
client, then the POV would be POV. you
landed your first high ticket client on
LinkedIn. Here's how. What I really want
you to focus on is that there is always
an angle that we can take from our own
stories through a public lens or a
shared sort of belief. Look, the entire
point of storytelling is to be
interesting or at least try to become
interesting in the process. And so to do
that, you need to be doing interesting
things. Write about them, do more
interesting things, and see the results
in your storytelling. By adding the POV
angle, you remove the selfishness to the
post and it becomes something your
reader's brain can actually feel. The
moment someone reads POV, you are their
subconscious mind goes, "Wait, that's
me." And suddenly they are locked in
into your story. They have to keep
reading because they think that the
story is literally about them,
especially if the first line resonates.
Now, on screen here, I've got three of
my favorite POV posts that I've written
over the last 6 weeks. And what I'm
going to do is I'm going to explain
exactly how each one of them was thought
of to a topline level. And then at the
end, I'll show you exactly how you can
write your own one in seconds, literally
right now. So, we have my favorite
three. And this one was actually the
first time I tried it, and it got nearly
2,000 likes and 60,000 impressions. Now,
the second one got over a 100,000
impressions on LinkedIn and nearly 3,000
likes. And the third one got nearly
200,000
impressions and 2.6,000 likes. And so, I
know this works because I've seen it
multiple times for myself and I'm going
to show you someone else that did this
incredibly well on screen right now.
Now, let's start with the similarities
each one of them have, which is the
hook. POV, you woke up on January 1st
and decided to change. POV, you're
building a sevenf figureure online
business in Dubai. And then POV, you're
building a business in Austin with your
friends. These three posts share the
exact same hook but in different ways.
You can see POV, you are building a
business. POV, you are building a
business. POV, you are doing something
new. What I'm doing here and the reason
why this worked is because on LinkedIn,
most people are actually trying to build
a business or they're actually trying to
work in a business that they love,
right? So I am tapping into total
addressable markets because I know that
most people on LinkedIn are doing that
exact same thing. The next thing that
I'm optimizing for is this. So here I
mentioned friends and awesome which
means travel and then friendship which
then taps into fundamental values that
people actually care about wealth health
and relationships. And in this one I am
actually covering all three health
wealth and relationships because for
most people changing actually can mean
either of those three things. So when
you go ahead and write your own, think
about how can I tap into bigger markets
with a single sentence. You talk about
things that everybody actually cares
about, which is again friendship, making
more money, building a business,
changing, taking a leap or a
transformation or even travel. Now the
body of every single one of the posts is
actually quite similar even if it tells
a different story. So here I say at 23 I
did this, at 24 I did this, at 27 I did
this. And then statistically I had a 3%
chance of making it and a 0.1% of making
building a profitable business. So what
I'm doing here is that I am continuing
the storytelling arc but I'm still
trying to relate to my reader because I
know that a lot of people reading this
right now are either unemployed and
young and ideally at the end I want to
mention something aspirational without
bragging. So if you see how I've
actually manufactured this post
basically is I am going from low to
high. I'm not starting with a crazy high
and then I keep continuously going high
high because that is very braggy and we
want to avoid that. We want to make it
aspirational by being relatable. And so
even if I'm talking about big numbers
like building a sevenf figureure
business, I then go back to how I
started which makes this a lot more
aspirational and relatable because it's
simple. Hey, I was where you are. I am
now here, but I understand the gap that
you need to fill and I'm going to tell
you exactly how I did it so you can do
it, too. And then I end the post with
something like a reminder that makes
them feel good. So, I like to think
about this like a Pinterest quote or a
platitude that makes people remember the
post, makes them not feel too
overwhelmed by the amount of information
that I'm telling them, but they remember
the feeling that they got when they read
it. This post also follows that exact
same narrative. POV, you're building a
business in Austin with your friends.
So, hey, I am traveling the world,
building businesses with my friends in
the USA. I know you guys know I'm from
London. So, that to some people is
aspirational, being able to travel
around the world with your friends while
building a business of your dreams. But
then again, I go back down to where I
started. And again, the reason I'm doing
this is so I can go head-to-head with
people that have not achieved that exact
same outcome, but they aspire to do so.
So, I said, "Not long ago, I was just an
invisible freelancer posting on LinkedIn
to try and land a client." What does
this do? It's relatable. I'm not
bragging. I'm literally saying I was
where you are right now. And then after
those two short sentences, I can move
ahead and transcend time in the
storytelling framework. So it doesn't
take me far too long to tell a simple
story. Because what people do wrong with
storytelling is that they try to give
too much detail. What I try to do
instead is to give as little detail as
possible while this maintaining an
emotion and a strong feeling and a lot
of reciprocity. So what I mean by this
is, hey, I'm giving you some
inspiration. and giving you some
motivation and giving you one simple tip
so you can do this as well. All I'm
going to ask for you is for you to
finish reading this entire post and
maybe like it if you liked it. That's
what I mean by reciprocity. I personally
liked how I wrote this entire post
because it was short, concise, it told
that entire story, but then it finished
with a piece that a lot of entrepreneurs
don't actually talk about, and that is
how much work it actually takes to build
one business, let alone three. So, I
said, "I've had little sleep for over
the last few months, but I've never felt
more alive." which then taps onto
another emotion which is the
entrepreneurial spirit. So essentially
you need to understand your audience
well enough to understand what cards you
need to play in order to make them feel
something and relate to you. I know that
I have three types of audiences. I know
that there are the entrepreneurs who are
exactly where I am at. I know that there
are the aspirational entrepreneurs who
want to do something like me or I know
that there are the CEOs and like really
cool founders that have been in my exact
situation. So again, I am tapping into a
larger total addressable market because
I am tapping into a single emotion that
can be felt by three types of different
people. And then again, I finish with
three key lines that actually make this
a feelgood post. The proudest I felt in
a long time. Thank you. And this is just
the beginning. almost like a finishing
piece of a Marvel movie or a Harry
Potter movie that makes you feel like
you want to keep on watching the next
films. You know, now that I've explained
exactly what my thought pattern was
behind these POV stories and the
framework that I actually used, you can
also see the one thing that I haven't
said, which is the image use. This is
incredibly powerful, especially when
storytelling because we are using
written form. So, we need to actually
use another element to obtain as much
attention as we possibly can within 3
seconds. And that can be using a photo
or multiple photos. On LinkedIn, you
have the option of using photos. And I
use this every single time I post
because I know that this maximizes my
chances of my post being seen and
therefore read. So, when storytelling,
ideally, you want to add a photo that is
immediately related to what you're
talking about. So here I said I'm
building a business with my friends in
Austin. So here I am in Austin with said
friends looking like we're building a
business. So you can see the laptop, you
can see the nicotine spray, you can see
the hats, you can see the whiteboard.
And what this is doing is something that
no one on LinkedIn talks about. And I'm
tired so I'm going to explain. Giving
context to people is essential for your
success as a storyteller because in the
most simple form you are able to
eliminate many many words and long
sentences by simply having them on site
in your photos. This is key. So I don't
have to say that I traveled that I had a
hoodie and that I was tired and that I
had my laptop and that I was with my
co-founder Rob and my other co-founder
Jake because they can see them. I don't
have to say it. Context is key. So then
if I give them visual context, I don't
have to verbalize it unless it's
important. But the things that I do
verbalize are things like I am building
a million dollar business. They cannot
see the million dollars, but they can
see me acting like a founder. They can't
immediately tell that I'm in Austin, but
they can tell that I'm somewhere sunny.
So it is important for me to sort of
like add those piece of context so I
don't have to overexlain myself. People
can also make their own assumptions and
have a little bit more fun looking at
the images and truly make it seem like
it's a story from a movie that they are
watching. Essentially, this type of
storytelling, I try to call it the
tiktoication of LinkedIn where by seeing
things, you assume things and then you
actually want to stay on the video. When
you're looking at a trend video with
audios, etc., you're looking at
different things like this girl dancing
to this really cool trend or this person
doing their makeup or this person you
know breaking something down that has a
lot of graphs. So like you are
interested because of that one thing and
then you stay for the rest when you
understand the context. On LinkedIn, you
get to do exactly the same thing, but
without having to have a videographer
following you for a YouTube vlog that's
a POV video or a Tik Tok where you have
to sit down and edit it for hours and
pick the right music, pick the right
sound effect. And you don't even have to
pay an editor to edit your Tik Tok with
subtitles, etc. Like, you can just do it
with photos and text, which is
essentially free. And here's where I
truly rest my case on LinkedIn being one
of the most powerful platforms because
you don't have to spend that much money
to actually become good at it and then
being known, then seen, then viral, then
gaining thousands of followers because
you only have to write good content and
have good photos. All right, analysis
done. Now, let's write the script or the
post together for the first hug that I
actually showed you. So, the way I'm
going to do this is via using AI. And
the tool of choice is going to be Cleo.
Cleo is honestly the best AI tool in the
market when you're trying to minimize
failure and you're trying to write
outstanding content on the platform. I'm
going to be leaving the link for Cleo
down below in the description if you
want to try it. And also, if you are
enjoying this video, please subscribe to
this channel. These videos take me hours
to script. They take our editors hours
to edit because I make so many mistakes.
And it would make me really, really
happy if you subscribed because I do
enjoy making these videos. But I don't
have that much time anymore cuz I run
three businesses. So please, if you want
to see more of these, subscribe so I can
hit 100K and get a nice black and then
show it to my mom. Thanks. Bye. So I
logged on to Cleo. I clicked on swipe
files and you can see my saved swipes
which I can save from anywhere like
Twitter, Tik Tok, Facebook, even
LinkedIn as well. So what I've done is I
saved my favorite POV post that I've
written. So you can also see them. And
what happens here is that once I save
them, they save onto my personal swipe
file, but they also save onto the local
swipe file. So, you can see everyone
else's favorite posts that they've taken
from multiple different places for
inspiration, too. The idea here is that
you get to save your favorite post when
you're scrolling around on social media,
so you can then reference them later and
use them when it's time to write your
next post for social media.
>> [music]
>> So I not only get to see my own saves,
you can also see thousands of posts that
have been saved by Cleo users. So it's
basically like a live trending library
filled with content other people liked
but also you liked. And this is
essentially what I call the inside of a
marketer's brain but without the years
of learning to be honest. So now let's
say I want to write exactly like I just
wrote my other POV post. So what I'm
going to do is I'm going to select the
post that I liked from my swipe file.
So, I'm going to go to my swipes on
here. I'm going to add them here and
then here. So, you can see me selecting
both of them. Now, I've checked that my
posts were on the swipe file. So, I'm
going to go on this little toggle here
with the plus. I'm going to go to my
swipes and then I'm going to select the
POV post that I just recently saved. So,
I know one of them is about
transformation. I know one of them is
about breaking generational poverty and
I know the other one is about building a
sevenfigure business. So, you can also
title them so you can find them easily.
And essentially, this is going to help
Cleo understand exactly what you want
your post to look like, sound like, but
it will add your own context that you're
going to give it. So, for example, I
love this POV angle.
Give me 10 ideas like this for my
consultancy
business. So, ideally, follow the prompt
that I just inserted, you'd actually
just add your business or replace it
with your niche. Or if you have
something more specific, you can also
add it. Please be my guest and do that.
What Cleo is doing here is that its AAI
is able to research internally from your
content and web content with similar
ideas to yours and it will connect the
dots where information may be lacking.
So let's say you said to it that you've
sold a 50k high ticket deal, but it
doesn't have any other context. So what
Cleo will then go and do is that it will
try to find the right references that
make the most sense and then it will
create the post based on that and its
intuition and also the hundreds of
prompts we've built it with. So the
content is as specific and excellent as
it could possibly be. So here you can
see that Cleo has given me ideas and
then has written the first part of the
post as if I had written it which is
amazing. It's analyzed the pattern and
trends and it also knows you. So it will
write very specific stories if you are a
user. So now I love all of the ideas. I
selected one of them and then I click on
the button to draft the post and then
you can see here it's generated a full
post based exactly on the prompt that I
gave it and based exactly on the
information that it has about me. So POV
you just turn down a client for the
first time. Once the draft is done, you
can edit it, write with it going back
and forth like an assistant or even get
it to generate you new lines of text.
You can of course do this manually as
well. You can copy and paste the same
post onto Chat GBT or Claude and then
give it a similar prompt and use a
similar editing process like I just did.
You can see by the final output of Cleo,
the post is practically ready for you to
post, schedule and add images like I
just did. Now, after learning everything
about the POV storytelling framework
that I love using and even using AI to
write it, you may have three questions.
Number one, what if I don't have any
interesting story to tell? Number two,
will this POV format get old?
Everybody's using it now. And then
number three, how often should I use
this format? Now, let me go through
every single question one by one so you
can leave this video and actually start
doing the thing without being scared of
any other consequences. Now, the answer
to question number one is simply, look,
everybody has a story to tell. Your
boring life to someone else is the
number one thing that they wish that
they were doing. And if you still don't
believe it, then try and tell stories
until your life becomes storyw worthy.
Look, my life didn't always look like
this. And I'm certain every single
person I've highlighted in this video or
on the examples also didn't. The biggest
difference between those people that are
telling really cool stories now and
those that don't is that the people that
do have stories told the same stories
that they had until they got the stories
that they wanted to tell. The simple
conversation that you had on the train
with someone or with a client is a
story. The new thing that you just
learned overnight for a client or at
school is a story. The small challenge
you overcame you think no one cares
about is a story. And to be honest, let
me prove it to you. Let me prove that
anything can be a compelling story. So,
in the comment section right now, give
me three things you think might be
storyw worthy, and I'll write you an
entire LinkedIn post for you to use it,
or you can even use it as a script or as
a newsletter. This is a challenge from
me to you because any story is actually
compelling if you know how to write it.
Well, I am personally going to be doing
this for the first few people who
comment and are subscribed to this
channel. So, leave the comment down
below, leave the three things, and I'll
write you a great story using this POV
framework. Trust me when I say this, the
stories you think are boring are exactly
what someone else needs to hear right
now. All right. Now, answer to question
number two. The powerful thing about
viral formats is that they may get old,
but not for you if you own them. Formats
don't die because they get popular. They
die when they stop working
psychologically. What actually happens
when a viral format gets old is that the
story being used is being overused.
Everybody's telling this exact same
story and then it loses its touch and
its magic. So as long as you keep on
writing new stories or with a different
lens, then you'll remain at the top. For
example, the POV format is over a year
old now and it hasn't died because it
plays into imaginary situations you, me,
and the reader wants to live or is
currently living. And so as long as
humans have aspirations and want to see
themselves succeeding, this format will
always work. And also there are infinite
ways to execute this. I've seen POV
posts about productivity, relationships,
[music]
business, fitness, parenting, cooking,
traveling. So this format adapts to
literally any niche or any topic. So you
can always recreate it as many times as
you wish. So if you pivot from talking
about B2B SAS to entrepreneurship to
then lifestyle, then the format remains
fresh. In essence, this is really not
about it getting old, but it's all about
can I tell stories that actually matter
to my audience? Now, finally, question
number three, how often should I use
this format? Well, once a week is ideal
if you're doing it on LinkedIn. It gives
you the chance to test and iterate and
also use the other remaining posts of
the week to educate on the [music] POV
topic. So for example, let's say that on
a Monday you pick a POV post that is
about you building a business and how
your life is 10 times better. The
[music] post after should be exactly
about how you built it step by step. So
now on screen you can literally see how
I would execute this from a POV
standpoint and then turn it into an
educational post. The effectiveness of
this and any other storytelling
framework is all about using the right
strategy. So if you aim to not make your
audience bored of the exact same story
and you help them, then you are becoming
useful and unique, not just another
person talking about themselves
consistently. And what this is really
doing, if you think about it, is that
you're inspiring, you're educating, and
you are entertaining all at once and
every single week. All right, so I
actually created an entire template that
you can copy paste right now. It's going
to be on screen. I actually try to read
it out loud where I sound kind of silly.
So I'm just going to leave it there
until I finish speaking right now. So
you can screenshot it, copy paste it,
and start writing. Okay, ready? Done.
This template has generated millions of
views across thousands of posts. But I
must say templates are just like
training wheels. Once you understand the
psychology within the writing, you can
actually start breaking rules and create
your own variations, which is my goal at
all times when teaching something. So
let me recap all of this. I gave you the
framework. I gave you the template. I
gave you the psychology behind why all
of this works. And I gave you a tool to
speed the entire process up. The only
thing left is perfect execution. And
that's where most people fail. Not
because they don't know what to do, but
because they don't put 100% in. If you
want to master this type of storytelling
format, then all you need to do is
follow the exact steps and almost mimic
the way these posts are structured. From
the literal hook to the structure of the
lines to even the images used, do your
best to find the photos that match your
story best. And always, always, always
try to keep your cook short and concise
and less than eight words, please. Your
audience is out there right now
scrolling through LinkedIn looking for
someone who understands their struggles
and can show them what's possible and
that literally could be you. Because
let's be honest, people are not looking
for another I am happy to announce post.
They are not looking for another humble
brag. They are looking for someone who
can help them see themselves winning.
That someone could be you. Now, if
you're a business owner, an
entrepreneur, or even a creator, and you
want more tactics like this, then you
should join my private mentorship
program on content, branding, and online
business that has been used by over
3,000 entrepreneurs. Or even better, you
can also join the wait list for my
four-week program where we enroll a
select group of founders every single
quarter. Oh, and by the way, I almost
forgot to say if you want an entire
breakdown on how I went from zero to
nearly 250,000 followers on LinkedIn,
then I recorded an entire breakdown for
free for you to watch right now. See you
there. Bye.