If you want to make content that
actually grows your LinkedIn account and
gets you clients, then in the next few
minutes, I'm going to show you exactly
how anyone can do it. The reality is
that LinkedIn has changed, but it
actually favors smaller creators.
Truthfully, most people don't have a
content problem. They have a positioning
problem. And that's why no matter how
consistent you are, posting content
every single day won't give you the
results you want. Look, I've got 280,000
followers on LinkedIn, millions of
views, hundreds of viral posts, but what
people know me for is for spending hours
on LinkedIn every single day over the
last 3 years researching, analyzing, and
obsessing over every single shift I see.
And right now, I'm watching creators
skip three fundamental steps that
separate content that gets buried from
content that actually grows their
followers and converts them to
customers. And to have this happen to
you, you need to understand three core
things. Hawks, distribution, and
positioning. See, what's holding you
back is in posting more. Is that you're
missing the framework that makes your
content actually work. Because while
your LinkedIn feed and even YouTube may
be filled with viral tactics that sound
sexy, the key is in the strategy behind
why certain content works and why, not
just what to post. Your favorite
creators know this and it's why they
invest thousands of dollars into
strategists like myself to decode this
for them every single week. There is no
one-sizefits-all approach, but after
analyzing thousands of posts and working
with top creators and entrepreneurs,
I've identified the different patterns
that across different niches work and
I'm about to break them down for you
right now. Step number one is to forget
everything you know about content
algorithms and virality because LinkedIn
is changing. There is an oversaturation
of overly perfect and clickbay AI
generated content. Right now, every post
looks the same. People have built GPTs
based on top creators posts like myself
and use them to just copy and paste. But
market sophistication has also increased
and people's BS radar is higher than
ever. Like truly, there is not a single
day I don't see people calling this out.
Which means we are at a turning point.
The old playbook of viral hawks and
engagement bait is dying and the
creators who adapt first are going to
dominate the next phase of LinkedIn.
Look, people on LinkedIn want to know
one thing. What am I going to get from
this? Whether you answer that question
with a perfectly formatted hook or a
ramble of three lines, it does not
matter. What matters is that you prove
within the first few lines that their
time investment will pay off and then
you actually deliver on that promise.
Now, for those that have watched my
content before, you would have seen me
talk about optimization of Hawk, so it's
mobile friendly, short, eight words,
etc. But this is no longer a necessity.
In fact, the post that I see performing
the best right now are the ones that
sound like actual human conversations,
messy, real, and unpolished. So, even
though I personally still optimize for
all of it, I wouldn't recommend focusing
too much on this yet if you're trying to
get more impressions, reach, and
clients. What I focus on is on authority
signals. See, LinkedIn's algorithm isn't
looking for more punchy weliner hugs.
It's looking at you, your content, your
profile, and the people who engage with
you. And even down to the other micro
levels, such as your comments. These
signal whether you are the type of
person your ideal customers would trust
with their business challenges or
someone that just scroll past. And
LinkedIn uses these actively. Look,
there are entrepreneurs and creators who
literally post, "Here's what I learned
today," and get a thousand likes there
and there. But here's the thing that no
one is actually saying. Their name is
the authority signal, not their content.
And how you do it for yourself isn't by
copying their hook, their template,
their carousel, whatever it is, but by
authority signaling in your content in
your hook. You want to create the
illusion that you know something that
people don't or that you have the
missing piece of the puzzle that they
need to make something click. Let me
show you exactly what I mean. Look at
this post. This is following traditional
LinkedIn advice perfectly. It's got the
picture, the perfect hug. It's even got
the winning infographic. But why is it
not performing well even though it's got
every single winning element? Well, it's
missing the how I know this or more so
something like why can you trust me that
I know this type of angle. It's also
missing a personal anecdote to add to
the story line. It's missing the proof
that the person has actually done the
thing that they're talking about. And
this looks like something that blends in
with every other generic business advice
post that we see on LinkedIn. Now, even
looking at her profile, she's got the
winning elements of a successful
LinkedIn profile. The title, the
achievements, the businesses, her
content isn't reflecting that, though.
The solution, let's rewrite this
instead. Love this. I think this
reflects the idea that she's a mother.
Like, we can see it in the photo. It's
also showing a personal side to her. So,
saying, "I used to feel guilty every
time I'd say no." Then it burned me by
out by 30. I couldn't work. So, we're
also giving a time frame and a feeling
of what happened and how it felt so
people could also relate. Again, using
her photo is a lot better than using an
infographic because this also indicates
to people that she is a human rather
than another AI infographic that we keep
on seeing online. I don't think there's
anything specifically wrong with these,
by the way. I I know I I hone in on not
doing them, but I do honestly believe
that toning them down and increasing the
volume of personality allows people to
create a true personal brand that they
are actually searching for. Now, we use
the rule of three here like sort of like
again relatable. We actually took some
from original post and then I actually
tone it down to three tips to keep this
very much so specific but not too
educationally because saying no is quite
obvious in itself. Right? And what I
wanted to do here is position her as an
authority but not as an authority in
saying no but more so an authority at
being a legend. Right? That is the idea
of personal branding. You have to decide
what angle you want to take with your
educational content and the storytelling
content. Every single piece of
storytelling content, it's a rule of
mine should always educate but not
overly do it, right? You don't have to
overeducate to make a story make sense.
Like here, that's why we did that
because we wanted to pan out the story
so it felt enough. The idea of saying no
was clear. We don't need the hacks. I'm
just going to say no next time because
you showed me how to say no. You've
inspired me to say no. I don't feel
guilty anymore. That that is the vibe
that we're going for. Um I've done
educational posts many many times. We
can do another one later. So now it
looks much better. She looks like an
authority. She doesn't need a full 30 on
the 30 title. She doesn't need to be the
Google CEO. She just needs to be
positioned as a CEO and as a mom. we
didn't have to go get her another full
30 under 30 title or we didn't have to
wait until she was the CEO at Google or
at a massive company where you know
people believe that you need these
massive awards to be an authority. She
didn't need that and you don't need that
either. We just used what we had to our
advantage and created the perception of
authority that works immediately, not
after years of building a personal
brand. Now, if you want to learn exactly
how to write content like I just did
above, then you can check out content
code. is my writing course. It has every
single framework that I use to write
content fast using psychology, cognitive
biases, and other winning frameworks
that work every single time and work so
seamlessly on LinkedIn. I'm going to
leave the link for it in the
description. And while you're down
there, if you liked how I rewrote that
post and you want to be next, then
comment your name in your LinkedIn URL
so I can roast your content in the next
video. Now, let's get into the second
most critical step to manufacture
visibility. And most people aren't going
to like me for this, but I must mention
it. Last week, in a call inside of my
private mentorship, one of my members
came to the call thinking she had a hook
problem. But in reality, she had a
distribution problem. See, LinkedIn is a
connection to connection game, a
visibility game. The entire platform is
built on the idea of networking. There's
first connections, there's second
connections, and there's third
connections. The more connections you
have, the wider your pool of people who
can actually see your content and most
importantly trust you. I looked through
her engagement that day and she was
making two crucial engagement mistakes.
Mistake number one is that she was
engaging, so commenting on profiles who
would never reciprocate. So, she was
engaging with people who weren't a
profile content fit. Let me break this
down for you. See, engaging with top
creators is one of the key ingredients
I've mentioned in many of my past
videos. But just like a chocolate cake
can't just be made out of one egg, your
strategy can't just stop there. Getting
in the engagement from top creators is a
necessity, but so is aiming to increase
your network every single day. So what I
mean by this is you need to find people
who will bring you up to not just get
your engagement and then move on. Like
you need to find people that connect
with you, resonate with your content and
then can push you higher in the content
algorithm game that we're playing in
LinkedIn. So for a profile like Bonitas,
we need to find more marketeteers or
people who are adjacent to her industry,
connect with them and start
conversations with them. This indicates
to the algorithm who to feed her content
to on the feed. And this is how we hack
the algorithm. Doing exactly this
indicates to the algorithm who to feed
her content to on the feed, which then
allows us to hack the LinkedIn feed and
the algorithm so she can start being
shown to the right people, increasing
her chances of her well-written post
finding the right people. It's simple,
but most people fail because it's too
long. But so is waiting for your
overpriced ads to work. So is waiting
for the referrals to come through. The
thing with commenting is that the
comments compound over time. And after a
few months or even years later, this
isn't an issue anymore. It becomes
automatic because you've gained
positioning. How bad do you want it is
the question. Because subpar efforts
lead to subpar results. People will
spend thousands of hours and days and
years writing content that never gets
seen because they try to cut corners.
Yet, these corners are what attributes
to the greatest gains. And just to
remind you, I'm not making this up.
LinkedIn creator managers encourage
users worldwide to do this commenting
thing every single time. The second
mistake is engaging with people who
aren't a content profile fit. Let's say
I'm in finance and I'm engaging with
someone like Dan Go. Dan is a fitness
guy with people who follow him for his
fitness. And again, I'm in finance and
marketing. This is not a fit. His
content isn't nor his followers. So my
efforts here on engaging and connecting
with people like him would be wasted.
and it would give me a false negative
telling me that oh engagement doesn't
work for my profile. But the moment I
start engaging with someone like who is
a killer in her game, suddenly
engagement starts converting because the
content is in front of the right
audience. I'll then magically start
seeing fast attraction in leads and
results because suddenly I am in the
right bubble now. I'll either get them
over to my page bringing me their
distribution or I'll find new people to
engage with as the algorithm will then
feed me similar content from similar
accounts. It's like magic. And back to
the chocolate cake analogy that I used
earlier. We find the right ingredients.
That's how we make a 10 out of 10 cake.
And I like chocolate cake. Okay. Now,
the third and last critical step most
people miss is their positioning. You
must pick a lane. Stop trying to be your
own niche. This entire thing about
becoming the niche or being the niche or
the fact that you are the niche is
keeping you broke and stuck. You can't
be all of it at once, especially if you
are at the start. Before you become the
niche, you need to figure out your
monetizable positioning. So, here's a
formula that you can use. What do you
want to be hired for? What are you
specifically great at? And who is
demanding your service or product? Some
examples, helping women save $10,000 a
year without doing X. This is better
than financial advice for seauite.
Another example would be helping
introverts go viral without dancing on
Tik Tok. This is better than content
coach. Lastly, helping e-commerce brands
recover 25% of lost sales via email
flows. This is better than email
marketing experts. And all of this
doesn't just go on your headline. It
spills throughout your content. Let me
take the last example as a draft so I
can rewrite it for you and you can see
exactly what I mean. So this is the
niche that we're going for. Excuse my
helping e-commerce brands recover 25% of
lost sales via email flows. Okay, so
that is the main thing here or she's an
email expert. So for this we're going to
hop onto Cleo and we're going to try and
test if we can actually write a post
using the tool. So I've just said I want
to write for my niche helping e-commerce
brands recover 25% of lost sales via
email flows. Please give me 10 post
ideas and hooks to write plus a listical
so I can draft it. So, I've prompted it
correctly so it can give me the hooks
that I want because that's going to
initiate the idea and then bullet points
so I know what to put inside of the post
cuz usually here's where people just
lose it. And this is where blank page
syndrome starts and procrastination and
all these things. So, I've gotten it to
give me 10 post ideas based on different
types of pain points, frameworks and
strategies that Cleo has inside. So,
problem story, contrarian hooks, data
hooks, whatever. So I want to use let's
say this one the framework hawk which is
pretty much my style. So I've got the
perfect hawk style from Cleo which is
based on authority, relevance and
positioning. The authority comes in
after helping 50 plus e-commerce brands,
right? Then the solution or more so
positioning as someone that can solve
problems comes with a recover loss sales
because that's what potentially their
clients are looking for like finding the
perfect way of how to stop the problem
which for them is recovering loss sales
and then to give value and to
incentivize people to read more and also
perceive him or her as the authority.
Then we're giving a five-step email
sequence that converts 25% of abandoned
cards back to purchases. And then after
this, ideally, our email copywriter
would then write the step-by-step
framework. By the end of the whole
process, we should have something like
this. I'm not an email pro, so don't
take this advice. But this is exactly
how I would write it. Again, the
formatting is not that necessary,
especially if the steps are longer.
Obviously, they will be like this won't
be that short, but just for property, I
just kept it short. So, basically, the
TLDDR is we need to position you as the
authority. How do we do that? We give
either case study or some sort of like
resonance so your ideal client can be
like okay this makes sense I want to
read more and then I built a system that
works like clockwork okay please show me
the system that's what people are going
to be thinking about and then what is
the system then we're solving that
question as well or it's a five-step
email flow okay it is very tangible for
me I want to implement it what is it and
you give away the whole framework 100%
of it not 99 not 98 100% because
realistically even if you give away your
full playbook people want to implement
it. That's why they pay people like you
for to implement it. Like people don't
pay for the information, they pay for
the implementation, right? So give it
away all for free or at least 99% but
ideally 100%. And then at the end, we're
going to end with something that kind of
ties everything up. So most brands wait
too long to follow up. Others send weak
messages that don't convert. This fixes
both. So we're like establishing like
we're hitting hard. It's like, I just
solved your problem. Now hire me. And
then at the end I'm adding some sort of
like engagement bait so people can
actually comment more and then your post
can be seen by more people etc. be seen
in different feeds. Uh someone else are
going to like it. Maybe someone's
friends comment on this they see it. It
increases engagement and so on and so
forth. Your post starts doing better and
then we love it for you. You become a
LinkedIn legend and you come back and
pick me. Perfect. Done. Now you
understand how LinkedIn strategy
actually works right now. But you want
to learn how to write content fast using
AI. Then watch this video where I broke
down exactly how you can create content
using AI. You've got the strategy. Now
let's get to the content.