I'm about to show you the six AI [music]
tools I've used over the last year to
speed up my content workflow. And this
won't be like every other video showing
you hundreds of AI tools that promise
you the world but don't actually work.
I'm going to be breaking down the step
by step of how they have been key for me
when creating viral content across
platforms. Look, I've got over 300,000
followers on LinkedIn, daily viral
posts, millions of views, done it on
Instagram, YouTube, and even X. So trust
me on this one. The tools that I'm about
to show you work if you follow the
processes I use for each. And I
guarantee that by the end of this video,
everyone watching this right now will be
using at least one of these tools.
Because these tools are what's allowed
me to build multiple six and seven
figure businesses based on just organic
content. Now, before I reveal these six
tools, all I ask from you is that you
subscribe to this channel because this
is about to upgrade your content game
forever. Now, let's start with the one
tool that is criminally all underrated
and barely anyone talks about. This is
every viral content creator's hidden gem
and it's called one of 10. It taps into
the largest viral content database in
the world, YouTube. And even if you're
not creating YouTube content, [music]
this is why you still need to use it.
Look, most people get the content game
wrong. They're trying to come up with
original ideas from scratch. But you
don't need to when viral blueprints are
sitting right there. The most important
part of winning in the content game, no
matter what platform you're on, is
finding what is called outlier ideas.
And one of 10's job is exactly that. An
outlier idea is something that's already
worked in a different niche or platform,
and you can take it and reverse engineer
it for your own niche. One of 10's AI
does this instantly. All you need is a
keyword or a short sentence. It analyzes
every YouTube video ever created,
filters the top performing videos, and
you can set a range of how viral these
videos went and how recent they are. And
here's exactly why I like it. YouTube is
the hardest platform to crack. So, when
you take these proven ideas that
performed in a long- form setting and
take them to LinkedIn, Twitter, or even
Instagram, you were already ahead.
Here's exactly how I've been using it to
ideulate content over the last year.
What I do is I put in a keyword of
something I want to talk about, i.e.
email strategy. Then I'll get a bunch of
viral videos with examples which makes
me get the point faster. Then I'll copy
some of them that I liked and put them
all into a Google document. And from
there I'm ready to go with ideas I know
worked. This post here I actually ended
up writing inspired by one of 10's
outliers using a keyword. Got the hook
idea from one of the videos here. And
then I wrote the rest of the post using
another AI tool which I'll reveal in
just a second. But the reason why I
genuinely love this tool, and I think
every single entrepreneur or creator
should genuinely be using it, it's
because of its database of outlier
content. It recognizes viral content in
the most saturated niches, which means
that if you have a smaller niche, this
has an even stronger chance of working
for you if you do it well. And even I
saw a tweet the other day of how people
use it daily to find outliers and use
them in their own niche and blow up in
days rather than years. But here's the
thing. Great ideas mean nothing if you
can't actually write them. And here's
where tool number two comes in. Cleo,
this tool is about to blow your mind.
How many times have you seen a great
hook or gotten a great idea, but you
just don't know how to write it? If
you're anything like me, then this
happens way too often, but then you go
and try all these other AI writing tools
and they just don't sound right. Well,
Cleo solves this problem instantly
because it knows you, or at least it
will. As soon as you log on to Cleo, it
will ask you a series of simple
questions that make it understand you
immediately. Your tone, your ideas, and
even business. So when you go in to
write, it already knows exactly what you
should talk about. For example, let's
say I add one of the hawks I liked
earlier. Then since it knows me, it will
write me a post based on my own
thoughts, but using the main idea and
hook I liked. What Cleo is doing here is
that it's pulling from viral frameworks,
content, and strategies used by top
content creators, but writes like you.
Instead of using an overused template
that you've seen hundreds of times
before, it also doesn't just write it.
[music] It tells you why it wrote it and
how you could even make it better. You
can then edit the post within the
website, get to view exactly how it
would look like if you posted it, and
then generate variations of specific
sentences if you wanted to. And here's
my favorite part. You can now import
your chipd or clawed memories into Cleo,
which is key for those who like me talk
to it every single day. This allows Cleo
to increase its accuracy in the content
it writes for you. But here's what makes
it a 100 times better than using JBD.
Our team spent hundreds of hours
analyzing top creators writing styles
and built them into the system. With
Cleo, you're not just getting AI
writing. You're getting AI that writes
like the best writing fast creators in
the world. Literally. I mean, for full
transparency, I built it alongside my
business partner Jake. We currently are
the top creators on platforms like
LinkedIn next to legends like Steven
Bartlett, Alex Hermosi, and Justin
Walsh. Took us less than a year to rank
right next to them. And the main reason
was Cleo. I could talk about Cleo all
day long, but if you liked how this
looks and want to try it, then I'm going
to be leaving the link in the
description for you to do that. Now,
don't tell my team that I'm about to do
this, but if you subscribe to my channel
and leave a comment in the description,
I will be giving 10 [snorts] of you free
Cleo access for a lifetime. This person
won our giveaway last time and it's
loving it. So, make sure you enter to
win. All right, now moving on to number
three. This is where things level up
because listen, to stand out when
creating content, you need to build
undeniable proof. But we often forget to
capture those moments that actually give
us that proof. And here is where Otter
AI comes in. I've been a paid user for 2
years. Think of Otter like having a
personal assistant that never forgets
anything that you say. It records,
transcribes, and turns every
conversation into a content gold mine.
After every single client call that I
have, I use Otter's AI to extract the
main issues, my solutions, and turn
those things into content ideas. This
leads me to create both data and
storydriven content using specific
examples and [music] anecdotes.
Basically, the way I use it is so
simple. I'll just download my entire
transcription from a call, then upload
it into a great AI tool, [cough] Cleo,
so it can be used as a resource of
information, and then I get it to give
me post ideas from that exact same
transcription. Both combined are a gold
mine for content. When you're using your
own cool recordings, then you can create
educational content breaking down a
problem that you already talked about
and give the solution within that same
post. You can also write storytelling
content using a conversation you had and
even get lead generation content using
the exact language your customers use to
attract more of them. This entire
process is so seamless. I love AI. I was
definitely born in the right generation.
If you liked how this looks and you want
to give it a go, I'm also going to be
leaving the link below so you can use
it. I genuinely think that if you try
it, it could transform your life and
output for your business and everything
else. But number four is actually
chachi, but more specifically chachi
projects. See, in my humble opinion,
everyone is using Chachi PT completely
wrong. They're treating it like Google,
but it can be way more than that. Within
ChachiPT, you have projects and I use
them essentially like a journal. I have
a journal project, I have a business
project, I have a clear project and so
on. Anytime [music] I want to journal, I
just go on a walk and then use the
voiceto text feature so [music] I can
talk to it directly using it hands-free
and it organizes my thoughts. Chachi PTS
are so simple to set up that I've even
given every single project that I have,
no matter how different they are, a
similar prompt. And if you want to use
it like I do, then here it is. I want
you to take these voice notes, don't
generate anything. I want you to
organize them into coherent thoughts so
I can refer [music] to them later. Then
when I need to create content, go on a
podcast or prepare for something that is
content related, I use projects that
then remembers what I said or thought
and even note it down. I really like it
because I have different thoughts in
different folders so everything is
organized which is what I wish my brain
looked like. I then reference the chat
and ask it to give me ideas, updates,
bottlenecks or stories from each so I
can use it for content or even prepare
for a keynote. I actually did this last
month for a big keynote that I had to
do. And all I did was go on a folder, go
on a walk, talk to Chad GBT and it gave
me an outline of what I thought and then
what would be relevant for me to use in
this keynote. The keynote went great and
I actually took less time doing that.
And it's exactly the same for creating
content, going on podcast, etc. And to
prove to you even further that this
workflow actually works in real life, in
real time, this exact process has
actually made my building in public
series work across different platforms.
I've gotten at least one viral post for
each platform created with this
workflow. You can see the examples on
the screen right now. built multiple
posts, thousands or even millions of
impressions and [music] counting. Each
post or video was used referencing what
I'd said to my chachi, which makes the
stories authentic, raw, and real rather
than the typical AI slop royer we see
online. Now, let me lay out the exact
workflow I use so you can copy it. I go
from ideas on chachi, then upload them
onto Cleo to clean them up and lay them
out in a viral sequence, and finally add
my [music] last edit so it sounds like
me. And that's essentially it. I'd love
for it to be more complex, but I
actually like simplicity when it comes
to AI tools. Now, let's talk about long
form because these next two ones are
complete game changers, especially for
long form creators. See, the first four
were all about short form, but here's
how we dominate long form. Poppy AI
revolutionized how I write long form
scripts and this process will blow your
mind. With Poppy, you can upload
examples of how you write, then use its
AI chat [music] to create you long form
emails or scripts based on ideas you've
seen across the internet. So, let's say
you liked a few videos or even emails.
You like the scripts, the cadence, or
even flows. All you need to do is
connect these things onto an AI chat and
use [music] this prompt I actually
learned from a Ben beta video earlier
this year. The prompt is based on what
you know about me, how I speak, and the
topics I write about, please make me a
20page long SOP that I can give to my
script writer to write on my tone and
using my own knowledge. That single
prompt is a game [music] changer. I used
it on Chad GBT and even on Poppy and it
made me a beautiful SOP I can then copy
and paste onto any AI including Poppy or
itself when it generates the next
answer. Then to make this even more
precise, I go in and add a few videos of
mine including podcasts, YouTube videos,
and even short form reals so it 100%
gets my tone of voice. I then connect
those two to the AI chart and ask it to
analyze my tone and tell me how I write
and then sound. Now once all of these
things are all connected, I can then add
inspiration from different videos, blog
posts or anything that I like and then
get it to create me a long form piece of
content in [music] seconds immediately.
I have a great first draft that would
have taken me multiple hours, [music]
lots of caffeine, and one or two mental
breakdowns. However, and I must say this
as a creator, as much as I love Poppy, I
can't say I use 100% of the output and
content it gives me. I'd honestly say I
use around 40 to 60% of the content that
it gives me. But this is all because I
just love to write and love going on
rabbit hole after rabbit hole to create
content. So that's just me. But if
you're not a control freak, this would
give you a 10 out of 10 first draft and
probably would just need to tweak a
little bit after. If you like Poppy, I'm
going to also be leaving a referral link
in the description if you want to try
to. I highly recommend it. All right, so
lastly, tool number six is Cap Cut. This
tool is too underrated still. It adds
subtitles to your videos. You can change
the format from vertical to horizontal.
You can cut videos, take awkward
silences out, and even fillers. And its
AI even autogenerates captions [music]
and has an infinite library of funds you
can use. This tool may not be
surprising, but I think it still
deserves a shout out because here's a
common problem most people face when
editing. They just don't have good
content to edit. So then when they edit
it, it just doesn't look good. And as
someone that has fixed this problem for
many people, here's the workflow I will
always use in standby. Number one is
scripting. You can start scripting your
videos using two things that I mentioned
in this video. Chad PT projects and
Otter. You can then pull the transcripts
from Otter or just whatever Chip
Projects has stored from your memories.
Then you take either or or you can take
both of them. then put them onto Poppy
and get it to give you ideas for short
form viral video for your niche. The
thing that you need to do with Poppy is
to get it to give you a 60second script
and then upload the final video onto
Caput. Then you add music, subtitles,
you make the harsh cuts, you remove all
the silences and then on top of that you
can even add some background music to
make it a little bit more engaging. Once
you've done that, you can then go on to
Cleo to write the copy for your video to
upload onto LinkedIn, X, and even
Instagram. And voila, ladies and
gentlemen, those are the six AI tools
every content creator and entrepreneur
needs to use to speed up their content
workflow. I truly believe that if you
simplify your content tech stack down to
these six tools, you will 100x your
performance across platforms. And look,
I could have kept this workflow for
myself. I actually have for over a year.
My competitors certainly don't know
about it. Everyone is so busy trying new
shiny AI tools and wasting their time. I
just focused on mastering these sex. And
if you do the same, they will become
your competitive advantage in a world
where everyone is fighting for
attention. So ladies and gentlemen, if
you guys enjoyed this video and you love
the AI tools, all I ask is for you to
comment which tool have you actually
tried and why you loved it and which one
did I miss because I actually had a hard
time figuring out which six or seven to
put in. I actually thought it was going
to be seven, but it ended up being six.
And as a bonus, because you made it all
the way till the end, I'm actually going
to be leaving three free resources for
you to use in the description that are
all about content, personal brand, and
writing. And just before you go, if you
want to learn how to build a bulletproof
personal brand that brings you leads
every single day, then watch this video
right here. And I promise 2026 will be
the year you actually win. [music] See
you in the next one. Bye.