This is multi-millionaire founder Teemo.
He built and sold his business fan for
multi-8 figures [music] by the age of
27, proving that he knows how to build
and scale businesses better than almost
anyone. But LinkedIn is his biggest on
[music] opportunity to turn his track
record into his next milliondoll revenue
stream in [music] 2026. And after
speaking to him about how to achieve
this and noticing his engagement was
decreasing [music] and learning about
his next few businesses, I'm going to
give him the five cheat codes that will
transform his entire LinkedIn strategy
forever. And I'm Lara. I have a proven
track record of growing personal brands.
And the [music] five cheat codes I'm
about to show Teemo have gotten me
millions of views, thousands of
followers, and built me six and seven
[music] figure businesses in the last 3
years. The LinkedIn cheat codes are one,
the best content play he [music] should
run to win LinkedIn. Two, positioning
and how to turn his current success into
a platform advantage. [music] Three,
content engineering and how to build a
system that actually works regardless
[music] of the algorithm. Four,
conversion and how to turn attention
into [music] buyers and clients off
LinkedIn alone. And five, the content
formats and hacks [music] he needs to
use to make his content addictive to
read. The plan is simple. look at his
LinkedIn, find a category of one, and
build a full strategy for him to execute
[music] this year. So today I'm with my
friend Timo Amu. And Timo, hi. You've
gained a lot of followers on social
media across Instagram, Tik Tok, and now
LinkedIn as well. Now, we're going to be
covering the problems that you currently
have with your personal brand on
LinkedIn. What do you think they are? Uh
I think we talk about too many things
and we also don't have a direct
conversion funnel from LinkedIn
>> too many things
>> and no direct conversion path although I
think we may have one by the time the
video comes out but let's assume we
don't have one now.
>> Very cool. And so now you are very aware
of this. This is a common problem that
entrepreneurs like yourself have because
you have grown to the point where you've
done too many things. It's easier to
start a personal brand when you have one
thing but you do a lot of things. You
have a lot of things to talk about. Now
what are the topics that you are very
interested to become known for on
LinkedIn?
>> One of the things we have is that we
sell companies on behalf of founders. So
if founders want to build a business to
then sell, we help them do that. So
that's one selling companies but also a
lot of corporates like everyone from
Goldman Sachs to JP Morgan to Samsung
pay me to come in to talk to them about
basically how to reach a younger
workforce and like building an
intergenerational workforce. And then
also there is some very good stuff about
basically how to market to Jenzi cuz my
last company Fan Bites what we did was
that we helped brands like the world's
biggest brands McDonald's Adidas we
helped them to market to Jenzi. So I've
also become quite a thought leader in
that.
>> Okay. So this is what I call monetizable
expertise. So these are the things that
you can actually monetize by just simply
talking about them.
>> Now there's
>> oh at the same time ah oh my god that's
spooky.
>> Oh my god. Okay lock in. [laughter]
>> We have this but now we need to find
your unfair advantages. So things that
you can talk to to a broad market that
don't know what this is about but then
over time you can convert them.
>> Okay. So my unfair advantages, one is
that I have built a number of successful
businesses before in like very
accessible industries. Second one is my
background as someone I grew up in South
London, Oaken Road, Council Estate. I've
basically talked about that a lot. So
people like see me as another kind of
workingass boy who's done well. And then
I think also just um I do talk about
like being a African like being from
Ghana and that whole kind of immigrant
mentality and that whole thing is
something a lot of people also warm up
to. So probably those three I guess are
my unfair advantages.
>> Okay, cool. So I think out of the three
these two are great as well as this one
but we need a little bit more
relatability because you're in the
business niche as entrepreneur. So what
are the top three things within the
business broad that we can talk about
that anytime you speak at a conference
people resonate with? You just wrote a
book.
>> Okay, cool. Let me pick the key thing.
So one would be starting a business
young and having a lot of that kind of
self-doubt and insecurity cuz I started
a bunch of companies young fan bites I
started when I was 21. So there's a lot
of that kind of first time founder
doubt. Another thing is obviously as you
mentioned I wrote a book which became an
instant number one Sunday Times
bestseller. Come on Jeep. But in that
book the reason why people like it a lot
is that it is very relatable and
practical. Like I talk about you know
feeling like nobody or how to build a
network or how I raise funding for fan
bites. We raised 2 million in funding
throughout my business journey. I've now
raised about 18 million now in funding
for different companies. And you know at
first I started off as someone who
didn't know how that worked. I'm so
proud of you. Out of all these things
though, there's one thing that's missing
and it is the mindset bit. In your book,
you speak a lot about mindset and what I
know that resonates a lot is like how to
engineer your own luck, which is part of
one of your key codes. We're not the
stories that you tell yourself.
>> Yeah. So, there's a lot of stuff there
about mindset things like it's not that
deep. That's actually one of the
chapters of my book about basically like
gaining perspective. We are the stories
that we tell ourselves. So in there I
have a ton of different stories about
the fact that like growing up in South
London I had a negative story around me
and then the things that I did to change
into a positive story. Everything big
starts small. So just the importance of
like starting off very small but still
having a big vision. So
>> yeah there's a lot and networking. Yes
man, this is so good. Yeah.
>> Okay. So the reason why I'm asking is
that there are three different pillars
that I like to think about when I do
content. Broad, narrow and niche. Now we
have the monetizable expertise and
you're on for advantages. But these
three topics and themes type are the
ones that are going to expose you to a
new audience. The reason why most people
stagnate in their growth like back in
2023 2024 it was really easy to grow on
LinkedIn you experience that as well but
now most people are in some sort of
plateau which you have also experienced
and the reason is because we stop
creating content to acquire new
followers and start just settling for
the things that work. But then if you
consistently repurpose the content that
used to work, which I think you've done.
I've talked to your team before and it
was that. But that doesn't work because
you need to find a new angle for the
same idea. It needs to be novel. It
needs to be new. One of the most viral
themes and topics that Timmo used to
have on his LinkedIn one year ago was
about the African problems and stuff,
>> right? Yeah.
>> So then how do we turn that into a noble
concept? Understanding that people want
some sort of touch point with you.
Before it was the quote and then some
sort of like tip. But today I think you
can talk about like my favorite piece of
advice growing up is this and you put
the the African proverb and it's a photo
of you. You're telling it from a story
lens rather than just a tip lens.
LinkedIn has changed to the point that
they just want personalities rather than
just tips and tricks. Okay,
>> that's very valuable.
>> So broad, narrow and niche. So the broad
content will be all the mindset stuff so
we can get all the beginners and the new
people coming in. It's almost exactly
what Alex and Rosie did with $100
million offers or whatever because that
introduces a new market of people into
who you are to a at a very basic level
and then over time you can nurture them
as they grow in their business and their
personal brand journey and following in
social media as to understanding what
all the types of businesses really are.
So then the narrow would be all of these
things as well as this and then super
niche will be when you decide to sell
like a product online.
>> So what should be the ratio of broad
narrative? Okay. So this is interesting.
So when it comes to monetization of a
personal brand, there are five key
LinkedIn plays
>> plays. Okay.
>> The five key LinkedIn plays every single
person should be using depend on their
goal and also their experience. So there
are beginners, there are intermediates
and there are advanced people. So one is
the client play and two is the case
study play. So you are not playing these
games because you don't have to look for
clients because you already have that
authority. However, many people giving
advice on personal brand, they are stuck
in these place because that is the
concept that used to work for everyone.
But social media has evolved. So these
are not going to be for you. But if
you're a beginner and you're starting,
these are the content place that you
want to use. Now the other two, number
three and number four are the category
of one play, authority, and distribution
player. So out of those two, I think
you're in between these ones as well.
And then in order to reach number five
which is multiplier player you need to
kind of understand where the point of
inflection here is. So you can then go
into here the category of one player is
people like Dan co Justin Welsh Jake
Wood or even me when you think about a
word people on LinkedIn think of you. So
with Justin Welsh you think solopreneur.
With my friend Jake Wood they think
about SEO. With me they think about
personal brand on LinkedIn. Now with
you, because we've talked about so many
topics before, they do not know where to
categorize you. So we go into the street
and we put 10 people that follow you.
Some people will think tips, some people
will think exiting a business, some
people will think fan bites. The reality
is that we need them to remember you for
one specific thing. So what do you think
that is for you today? Well, so my
question would actually be so we said
earlier the people who engage and the
people who pay from our LinkedIn can be
corporates all around how to hire and
market a jenzi and then you also have
the founders who pay me like 100 grand a
year to basically be their coach to exit
their business. So you basically have
two groups of people. So how do I
determine
>> we find so at any time with any business
that you ever have and any interest
there is an overlap where you are here
and then they all overlap. So with this
higher marketing jensy then coach to
exit you have fan bites and then you
build a business you exited it and
you're good at marketing. So for me the
main thing that would go here is what
people know you for that the person at
HR can use to take to their boss to be
like oh he built and sold fan bites in
this industry so therefore you need to
hire him and then the other people would
be like oh yeah it's a fan bites play or
like the fact that you've built and sold
exitable businesses in this specific
space. So that's it. So, we need to lead
with that social proof as much as
possible because there's so many people
that do not know your story. And the
problem is with most marketing agencies
and people that I work with, people get
tired of using that social proof too
much because they think it's too much.
There's like some sort of like overwhelm
with the founder. However, you need to
think about what was the last LinkedIn
post that you read today. You won't
remember it. And so, repetition builds
repetition at scale. So, you need to
force yourself to repeat yourself a lot.
>> But it's good.
>> Okay. So, anytime you think that you're
going in the wrong direction, it's
because you're steering away from the
main thing, which was talking about who
you are at all times. Out of all of the
post, the cadence should always be at
least three posts every single week. No
matter how many you do, they need to
refer back to your experience that makes
you the unique person to talk to about
this subject.
>> Interesting.
>> Yeah. Now, good.
>> We've got the category of one play,
which you have. So, it's like the fan
bites play, the I built and sold this
business, the eight figure play. I
actually went and analyzed every single
one of your podcast that you had and the
similar keyword that they all use is
either 8 figure exited founder
>> or multi-millionaire and the last one is
your story the racks and riches.
>> So if they are using it on YouTube and
it's performing at an outlier level why
not take that onto LinkedIn as well
because it's a proven concept. You need
to look for keywords. I like to think
about LinkedIn like SEO a little bit and
you need to think okay what are people
clicking on on other platforms and how
can I take this to LinkedIn?
>> Great. Cool.
>> So on the rags to riches thing, right?
Cuz as you know, like our best ever post
was the whole like thing.
>> I got put it up on the screen now. Now
that's cool. It brings in a lot of kind
of I guess fans etc. And I guess to some
degree it does get the attention of the
corporates etc. But that is almost like
just content to build an audience. It
doesn't directly lead to anything.
That's a good way to think about it.
Yeah.
>> So you're saying you don't like it? I'm
saying what proportion
>> you're saying like inspiring people.
>> Well, that's great. I'm saying what
proportion of our content do you think
should be that?
>> Yeah. So, it depends. I usually say four
posts a week is fine, but for you
because you have a team and you have all
of this expertise, you can actually post
five to six times a week. I think
personally three times a week using
story-led content about the racks of
riches, but also the middle like there
are many other stories that you can tell
that actually relate to that middle
round. So the self-doubt, the impulsive
syndrome, getting your first client, we
need to talk about them, but in
different angles. You can always take
one topic and divide it into different
things. But people just start rinse and
repeating templates. And that's why we
run out of content ideas. You literally
have infinite content ideas. If you have
five key topics, you just do how to, a
story, a listical, and a second story
variated from the first story.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. One of the stories people really
like is when we got our first big ticket
deal in fan bites and it was when we we
>> Charlotte Tilbury.
>> Yeah. So we had a proposal and before
that we had been charging lower prices
like 1 grand 2 grand for our services
cuz we basically didn't back ourselves
enough to charge high. And then for some
reason I just thought you know what
we're going to charge a high price. And
so I put the packages there. I put uh
bronze, silver, gold. And then for gold,
I said it was going to be 40 grand. And
at that time, that was the highest that
we charge. And I kind of just said, do
you know what? We got to be big boys
now. And then we did it. And then they
came back and they said, "Well,
actually, do you know what? We'd like to
start off at 60 grand." And I remember
thinking, "Oh my god, like this is
insane. If we had just kept doing one
grand here, two grand here, there's no
chance they would have even said 60
grand because of positioning." So that's
kind of the story, right? And I share
that with your audience there for you to
know.
>> Okay. So basically there are four
different angles and we can actually
even multiply even further. So the same
story different content. Okay. So the
first one educational this is how I
closed Charlotte Tilbury at 20 seven.
Okay. And then you tell the story in the
exact same way. The second one is a
storyled post.
>> Sorry to interrupt. So you know the how
to this is how I do I want to leave the
audience with then like a practical
takeaway.
>> Yes. So I'll I'll get into that in a
second. This is how I. So, it's always
important to use the how I angle because
right now with AI slop, every single
person is how to build and sell a
business and they've never done it. This
is how to build a personal front and
they have 5,000 followers. So, always
use the how I because no one can judge
you for personal experience. Like, and
there's no right or wrong. It is your
way because it worked. Okay? And also,
we're leading with a case study like
Charlotte Tilbury. So, immediately
you're borrowing credibility. You have
the credibility yourself and it's
engaging because you're about to teach
them something. Number two is in 2019 I
made my first $100,000 in a month or
whatever whatever the result was. Uh we
need to quantify something very quickly
from the very beginning so we can retain
people. Today everybody tries to copy
what's working on YouTube, Tik Tok, etc.
But it doesn't work because on Tik Tok
you have a lot of variance like video
music. How you do it on LinkedIn is you
use practicality or specificity and
numbers so you can retain an audience
making them feel like they're about to
get a big payoff if they keep on
reading.
>> Okay. The third one would be a listical
how to get your first big ticket client.
How to make your first $10,000 by
charging one client. And then the next
story is actually important. So here
we're taking the same story here but
we're using a common denominator problem
that people have. Imposter syndrome,
self-doubt, making money online, getting
your first client, I'm shy, I don't know
how to raise my prices. You use a
keyword that we know works. So imposter
syndrome works on LinkedIn because every
single person on earth struggles with it
at some point especially people that are
really content on LinkedIn because
they're either corporates, they are
entrepreneurs or they are just
freelancers or there may be even an
exited entrepreneur like you that still
struggles with it and likes to see you
being honest about your own journey
because some people pedestalize
influencers and big entrepreneurs and
celebrities and it is better to
sometimes come down and be like no I'm
just like you. I just did the thing
instead. And then you get to inspire
them. Quick one. If [music] you want the
strategies, frameworks, and tools I'm
giving business owners like Teemo to
scale their personal brands on LinkedIn
faster in 2026, I give all of these away
inside of my mentorship programs. If you
want to become a client and get access
to all [music] of these playbooks,
frameworks, systems, and so much more,
then click on the first link in the
description and I'll see you inside.
Let's get into how to write each one of
them because it's actually so easy. So
there's two formats that I always back
on like gone to my head. I will always
use the slay framework and the past
framework. Everything else is a bit
irrelevant. So slay when you're doing
storytelling, you always want to
educate. The problem with storytelling
today is that people tell stories that
never end and never get to a point.
Okay? And this is why stories fail. Then
people will come to me and they're like,
"You told me to tell a story." And I'm
like, "Yeah, with a point." You need to
get to the point quickly. So the Slay
framework helps you get there. So you
tell two lines of a story. So in 2019, I
closed my first high ticket client and
it changed my life completely. This is
how I did it. These are the three key
actionable steps on how I did it. How
are you going to implement this today? S
is for story. L is for lesson. A is for
actionable advice. And the U is a way to
engagement hack on LinkedIn. Dwell time
on LinkedIn is one of the most important
metrics that no one is thinking about
today. But the reason why it needs to
happen is because the more time people
spend on your post today, the better it
is along the way. But people don't like
they will know but then they will do
everything to not have that happen. So
when you introduce a question people
will then kind of be tempted to answer
it and then comment more. Okay. And then
pass problem agitate solution. So if you
don't have a high ticket client today
this is why you need one before 2026
ends and then you give the solution.
That's it.
>> Could your path also be like the problem
being you know you should charge more
but you just don't know how to.
>> Yes. as long as as long as it's it needs
to be very direct. So sometimes that
type of post doesn't work because it's
too leading. It may not spark enough
curiosity for them to want to read it.
But if you're like you're going to be
broke if you don't do this thing. Here's
exactly how to do it. Then that's a
little bit more speed like they want to
get into. So let's finish with the four
plays that we have here. The other three
plays. So we have the authority and
distribution play which you also have.
You have a big network and you have all
the authority here. Bestselling author,
exited entrepreneur. So we have the
authority in distribution place. So we
have bestselling book, we have fan
bites, we have the companies that you
built then you sold as well. Companies
sold and we have the network. Huh?
>> Yeah. People in your network
>> in this cuz I've talked with my team
about this. There are certain things
which I don't particularly see as
interesting but then I understand they
are seen as interesting. So, for
example, 4:30 under 13, that was a while
ago, and I was like, "Oh, cool. Should
we talk about that? Should we even
include that in our bio? I don't know."
There's also other stuff like when I'm
like featured in a bunch of different
news sites, etc. I'm just like, "Yeah,
cool."
>> Well, that's positioning. So, we have
the four main things that we know that
kind of work, right? This is where
positioning and pattern recognition
happens. So, you have a lot of exposure
to the market. Therefore, you see so
many different announcements every
single day and you kind of already been
used to it. Nothing is novel to you
because you see it all the time. But to
a beginner audience and an intermediate
audience, the full study on the 30 that
even if it happened a while ago, it's
still relevant because they can
categorize you as this type of person
that did that. The magazine thing, they
categorize it. We need to understand
this. Otherwise, we're going to be
playing a losing game by not talking
about the things that are relevant
enough. So play the winning game by
understanding how people box you into
things immediately. So that's why, you
know, content happens and like the first
three lines of a hug matter because it's
like quick distribution and connection
to what's happening. The fourth thing,
we don't have to talk about it all the
time, but if you talk about it once a
month amongst all the other millions and
millions and millions and millions of
achievements you've gotten, then that
plays into positioning a lot. So don't
see it as bragging. see it as a way for
people to fund you.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Okay. And then the pattern recognition
is the same. Okay. So that's a full send
a 30 person. I feel like I can trust him
more because of that. Oh wait, he also
founded this company found bites. It's
like a little funnel. It's a mini funnel
of people to understanding who you are
in a short space of time.
>> Yeah. And I guess with pattern
recognition as well actually like there
are so many people that I meet and so
many people that we take pictures of, we
put it on story but like we don't talk
about LinkedIn and yeah that's
interesting. Okay, I want to get into
the distribution play.
>> Tell me what that means.
>> Because you don't do it enough. Okay, so
the distribution play is basically when
you're using your network and community
to push you even harder. Every single
social media platform is community-led.
A person needs to like your post so it
can be seen in the algorithm even more.
People are actually liking your post
every single day, like real people. And
we kind of forget that because we just
see the numbers, but we don't see the
people behind them. So, how do we make
them want to engage with us? We build a
community. So you do it by borrowing
credibility, but you already have it. So
you borrow credibility from the forms.
You borrow credibility from your friends
and you borrow credibility from the
people that are platform native like
myself. Every time we've done a post
together, it works because people
recognize me and then they like
attribute that to him as well. And then
they find him and they're like, "Oh,
he's kind of also cool but not as cool
as Lara, but that's enough." Okay.
>> Word for word. That's what they say.
>> Exactly. So we need to leverage this a
little bit more and you can do this with
all the photos that your community and
sons have taken. However, there's a very
specific way to do this because you
cannot just post every single time your
community shares a place with you.
There's another way and I'll show you in
a second. And then the second way of
distribution is the podcast you went on
the BBC and then all of these things
that you can also use as leverage. Okay,
there's another one that you need to
leverage a little bit more and that's
engagement. So engagement on LinkedIn is
one of the most important modes to build
an engaged network. The more you engage,
the better your content is going to be
received because people look at comments
as well as likes to kind of also pattern
recognize if the post is good because
people will see the likes than the
comments and if it doesn't have that
many comments, they'll either think that
is just AI or something else. So how do
we build this? You use the 3+ 1
commenting rule on LinkedIn. So on your
post, you want to leave three comments
underneath your own post. So, you're
going to be hyping yourself up.
Basically, you do a behind the scenes
kind of like, hey, today I'm like
working on this exterable business
strategy and you take a photo of your
laptop and that's almost like bringing
people into your world. The marketers
and all the creatives will call this
world building and in B2B also works
because you're introducing people into
your own mini world as a business owner.
You don't need a large set. You don't
need to create all of these things. You
just need to show them what's going on
behind the scenes, right? And this gives
them a second and third way of engaging
with you if the post wasn't like
something that they wanted to comment
on.
>> So you do this on each post.
>> Yeah. Then the second one needs to be
like an educational tip. So today you
have a library of content that you can
use as comments. What I do is I go
through my old content. I pick the one
that is relevant to the post that I did
that day. So if I tell a story about how
I, you know, just built one of my
businesses, then I can go back and
choose one post that talks about
building a business on LinkedIn. Then I
copy and paste that post onto my
comments and then that's a second shot
of like a good educational post and I
can repurpose my content that way as
well.
>> So as in you take the whole post of
another post.
>> Depends on the length. Sometimes I'll
edit it a little bit. Maybe I just leave
the hook and then give my new thoughts
on the post that I wrote. But that's how
I repurpose my content and then it's
giving value and people appreciate that
because again AI slop is a problem on
LinkedIn. This is how you beat it and
how you humanize yourself. And the third
one can be like a version of this or a
version of this or something else. Okay,
so you're doing that.
>> Behind the camera, by the way, is Jonah.
He has my social. He's great. Shout out
Jonah when you see this.
>> Had to shout out him to sat down. But
yeah, shout out Jonah. Okay, so then now
you understand the play number three and
play number four that you're in the
middle of. You're in that intersection.
We want to learn how to then win the
multiplier.
>> The multiplier. Okay.
So, here is when you've mastered three
and four, you found your inflection
point and you can hit like that momentum
wave where like all content performs
equally as well and there's no like up
and down, up and down, up and down. So,
you're not consistently thinking about
what's going on because you have your
content themes, you have your
monetizable expertise, you have your own
fair advantages, you know how many times
a week you're posting. So, 1 2 3 4 5.
You have your main three, you know,
pillars. Pillar one, pillar two, pillar
three. And then you know exactly what
game you're playing so you don't go out
of it and start trying to see what other
people are doing because this is exactly
what happens here. And that's why it's
up and down, up and down, up and down.
>> Essentially focus is the main thing. You
have the distribution, you have the
content, and you have the social proof.
And all you need to do is do it
consistently and don't let anything else
get in the way. And that's how you
become a multiplier. So now we have all
this attention. We need to make money
from it essentially. What are we
promoting on LinkedIn today?
>> So, I haven't ever really promoted
anything on LinkedIn. The last thing was
the book, which was great. Now, going
forward, I want to effectively promote
two things, and you're probably going to
say I shouldn't promote two things. I
would say I shouldn't promote two
things, but I'm going to say there's two
things, and then you're going to tell me
what I should do and what I shouldn't.
So, first thing is, as I mentioned, I do
a lot of public speaking, and so I want
to promote and I enjoy it. So I want to
promote that as a thing for companies to
get in touch etc. And I want to take
that to the next level this year. And
then the second thing is actually
something called the founder intentive
like we have this whole mastermind to
help people build a sellable business.
And for that the way we are doing it is
we are doing these weekly workshops
which invite people and we talk to them
about building a business and Q&A. So
directing people to these workshops,
offplatforming them is probably the
biggest thing there.
>> Okay. So these are all high ticket,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> There are two concepts that I recently
learned to love and there's the idea of
content market fit and then content
offer fit. There's many people that have
millions of followers but that cannot
convert anything because there's no
content market fit and there's no
content offer fit. So what we just did
earlier and the reason why I asked you
what your main goals with LinkedIn were
was so every single piece of content
that you ever create kind of makes sense
whenever you do decide to promote either
of these things. So when you're talking
about your unfair advantages you're also
making people know that you talk about
self-doubt that you talk about
productivity you talk about mindset you
talk about you know being an author and
your racks to riches and then when you
decide to sell the foundry intensive
when you start promoting it it doesn't
feel like it's coming out of nowhere. So
we've introduced the idea slowly for
when you decide to promote. Okay,
content market fit. We have it and then
we have content of a fit because every
single piece of content that you create
has something to do with building a
businesses a business or mindset and all
these things that people like hearing in
public speaking talks or conferences.
>> All right. So on the public speaking
front the main topic is generally around
hiring and marked into Gen Z.
>> Yeah. So generally the corporates don't
want like a motivational talk about be
your best self etc. It's more about what
are trends going on what are themes
going on in the industry. Okay.
>> So one of my thoughts is what proportion
of
>> so we don't have
>> content should be like the kind of
motivationally stuff cuz I don't think
it should and actually now that I'm
thinking about this I realize that we
have too much content which actually
doesn't really highlight this second
one. this one we talk about it but then
it's actually not as much as we should
do.
>> That's why I covered the monetizable
expertise thing and how to write a post
for it. So after this you will have it.
So once that is fixed then the content
market and the content offer it will be
fixed.
>> Yeah.
>> Back to the speaking cuz I think it's a
main point of discussion that you
usually have. Let's say you want to post
five times a week. I think one of them
should be dedicated to hiring like it
needs to be a topic that is broad.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. to still fit in that broad narrow
niche narrative. And then as an adjacent
whenever you're telling a story, one of
the stories that you tell a week,
because there's two stories a week, so
story is story. One of them has to be
about hiring or Jensen and Teimmo's
experience
>> doing that. But it doesn't have to be
necessarily about hiring in the hook,
but it has to lead to an outcome or a
point where he talks about hiring in one
sentence or two. It doesn't have to be
this long drawn out thing. It can just
be like two points I start hiring more
people build SOPs done and then these
are going to be the educational
monetizable expertise where he talks
about exitable businesses how he's built
it his story about it etc. I think the
best thing is starting with four,
understanding the patterns and how why
things work and then doubling down. The
volume game doesn't work for everyone
until they crack the code on LinkedIn,
which you guys are doing already with
the stories after I talk to you. This is
our second coaching conversation.
>> Great.
>> Quick one. If you liked all the
frameworks that we just used, I just put
them all in a free PDF for you to
download today, completely for free. My
[music] treat from us to you. So click
the link in the description and I'll see
you inside. So now you have a big
audience on Instagram. You get to share
a lot more of the behind the scenes on
your Instagram like the photos etc. You
reshare stories. How do we do that on
LinkedIn and why does it not work when
we do the exact same thing and repurpose
copy paste the same post because the
difference in audiences and interest is
insanely different. LinkedIn's
professional Instagram is consumers. So,
how do we make the same Instagram post
into something that is consumable and
easily resable for LinkedIn? When we're
repurposing, let's say a video that went
viral, right, on your Instagram, how do
we do it for LinkedIn? We can use the
same video, but then the caption needs
to work for you. Instead of using the
same caption as like, oh, we just
roasted 20 books with Lara Costa. is
like this video got 500 million 500,000
views on Instagram. We brutally roasted
the top books in the business space
>> and that's it. You give context before
they have to click on the video because
people aren't watching videos on
LinkedIn. They don't really scroll for
videos. They scroll for written fast
content. So, we need to optimize to give
them as much context as possible before
they decide to click watch. Same with
the carousel. Same with everything else.
Like if it's the same polish, you need
to give as much context. always think
about the word context please.
>> So we did a post recently which is doing
very well which is this thing called
investor next where people came and then
I had to decide whether I was going to
invest in their business or not. The
first video we posted is doing quite
well. I think it'd be a good video to
post on LinkedIn because it builds
credibility, social proof. Yeah. Yeah.
And also I think it would build a fan
base amongst those two people who are
like the entrepreneurial crowd but also
the corporates who are like wow this is
a very interesting dynamic way to reach
entrepreneurs.
>> Okay. So that video did well I saw it
last week I roasted 10 business ideas
live. Did I invest? And then you give
two more lines of context. You know 100
entrepreneurs signed up only 10 came.
One got investment. It's kind of like
using the Buzzfeed headlines just to
grab intrigue.
>> Yeah.
>> Interesting. Okay. Cuz you're right. I
guess on Insta, if you're just growing,
growing, growing, growing.
>> Yeah. It's easy cuz you're already in
like consumer mode. We need to put them
in that consumer mode by giving them
context and giving them the right
keywords to be engaged in. So like we
need to kind of like retain their
attention with something that they want.
So business ideas, I roasted 10
entrepreneurs live, you know, in real
time. And then at the end is important
as well to encourage more engagement
because videos are not going to get as
much engagement. So we need to sort of
like farm it. How do we do it with a
repose this post if you want to be next?
Repose this post if you want to get
access to the next round when we have it
whatever anything like that.
>> Or even like now that I'm thinking about
it or even tag someone that you think
should come for the next thing cuz
always like to support their friends.
>> Cool. So that's it. How are you feeling?
I feel like the most knowledgeable
LinkedIn man in East London.
>> So what's stopping you from going all
in?
>> I see what you did. I see what you did
there. She did that cuz the name of my
book is what's stopping me. Nothing. I
think you've given very good tactical
frameworks. This is great. Thank you.
>> Yeah. So we've got all the cheat codes
and nothing stopping Timo from becoming
a LinkedIn legend. So
>> you just be dropping these germs. Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> Bye.
>> So that's a wrap. I had way too much fun
doing this and hopefully Tim was going
to implement everything else. So, we
walked through the five LinkedIn plays
every single beginner entrepreneur and
advanced entrepreneur should be thinking
about when they start building their
personal brands. I also showed him how
to structure his content to actually
create [music] a systematized strategy
for his LinkedIn so it can run on
automatic in the future. And also, we
had a great time. So hopefully you
enjoyed this and if you love this video,
please leave a comment below telling me
why or who do you want on the hot seat
next time. And also please subscribe to
the channel so it can keep on growing.
And I recorded a similar video breaking
down a beginner's content [music]
strategy step by step. And since then
he's gotten 750,000 views in 28 days. So
click here to watch exactly how we did
it. Bye.