I just got back from the LinkedIn
offices and what I heard blew my mind.
LinkedIn video is about to blow up. See,
the creator economy is worth $104
billion annually. That's 104 billion
flowing to people who figured out how to
monetize their expertise through
content. And LinkedIn is about to become
the perfect place for business owners
and entrepreneurs to get a piece of it.
I first heard about this a few months
ago. See, this is not LinkedIn's first
time trying video. They've attempted it
before, but the timing wasn't right. The
platform wasn't ready, and neither were
the users. Early 2025, LinkedIn pushed
video heavily. Had creators from
Instagram and Tik Tok doubling down
their posting on the platform. But
midway through the year, this completely
dipped. The reason they're positioning
as a B2B platform. LinkedIn wants video,
but the right kind. Not the user
generated, viral, motivational videos,
but true, educational, and deep content
that would thrive in a professional
space. And here's where things get
interesting. They've spent months
studying what actually worked. Notice
that the videos that performed across
users weren't the viral trends or the
motivational fluff. They were the nutty
educational tutorials, the industry
breakdowns, the expert deep dives that
actually taught people something
valuable. And they developed their new
secret weapon, brandling. And I'll get
to what that is in a second. But let me
tell you why this matters to you. See,
we're living through the biggest shift
in how professionals consume
information. Attention spans are
shrinking. The need for true expertise
and expertled content is exploding. CEOs
worldwide are consuming short form
content daily. Even I, as an
entrepreneur, have hired people through
it. And more importantly, I've benefited
from it. Look, the professionals who
really figure out how to package their
expertise into engaging, digestible,
short form content will win. They get
more clients. They get more speaking
opportunities. They even get more
investment because of this unique skill.
and LinkedIn. Well, they finally
realized that they were sitting on a
gold mine of professional expertise that
wasn't being properly showcased. Now,
here's a problem. Even I noticed it. In
fact, I was quite vocal about it.
LinkedIn was not a video native
platform. It was more of a written form
platform, which means that its users
aren't used to video or don't routinely
create it. So to actually fix this once
and for all, there needed to be other
incentives that weren't just a boost in
impressions. So LinkedIn launched what I
believe will make it work. Brand link.
This is LinkedIn's creator monetization
system. It's still in beta and only
being rolled out in the US, but LinkedIn
seems to be all in on this. From the
Khan pop-up events in France, literally
talking about videos to US campaigns to
get creators to film content and post on
LinkedIn. It's happening. Here's what
Brand Link does. Instead of going the
typical ad revenue split like YouTube,
LinkedIn is going straight to brands.
They're matchmaking high value creators
with companies who are actively looking
to spend their marketing budget on
expert-led video content. I actually
predicted this shift in content
prioritization in my last video here.
Companies, consumers, and so on want
niche expertise and professionals with
credibility and also content that
educates, not just entertains. Now,
here's the execution playbook so you can
get started with LinkedIn video. First,
if you've already been posting on
LinkedIn, you literally have a gold
mine, your posts. You can repurpose them
straight into scripts. But to make them
work on a video format, we need to
obsess over the hook. Because the hook
is the only reason why people would
actually stay and watch past second
number three. Here are my favorite
hypertension hook styles so you can copy
them. Number one is a paradox. So
something like I regret improving
myself. That is the hook. Number two is
a bold howto. So for example, here's how
to never waste time networking again.
Third is a counterintuitive claim. So an
example would be cold showers are
ruining your mornings. Then four
emotional bait. It usually goes
something like I was broke last year but
today I'm here. And finally number five
is to just use a number. So something
like in 14 days this changed everything.
We're not giving it all away. We're just
simply sparking curiosity. Second, we
need the body of the video. Once you've
hooked people in, the body of your video
has one job. Educate. Keep it stupidly
simple. Kiss. That's a framework that I
learned at university. The only one.
Anyways, you can use a structure like a
step by step. So, step one, share the
mistake. Step two, break it down. Step
three, deliver the fix. It's that
simple. Or my personal favorite,
problem, mistake, fix. For example, let
me role play here. H, this is exactly
how I would do my video. Most people
script by writing essays. The mistake,
they sound robotic on video. Here's how
to fix it. Write like you think, not how
you speak. Bullet points and not
paragraphs. Now, that's the hook and the
body laid out for you so you can see
exactly how I would make it work. Now,
third is having a strong ending. This is
the most slept on part of any video or
even text content. Don't just drop
knowledge and disappear. End with a
viewer centered call to action. So
something like try this for seven days
and watch what happens or something else
like follow for more shortcuts like this
and my favorite and go to this one
mindset shift changed everything for me
apply it and thank me later. But if you
want to thank me now the best way to do
this is to subscribe to this channel so
LinkedIn keep on inviting me to their
headquarters. See calls to action always
works. sometimes they feel like a lesson
from a mentor or a simple reminder of
something that you can do to support
your favorite creator. So, moving on to
part number four is the filming and the
editing. You don't need a studio. The
only thing that you actually need is
daylight or a $20 ring light. I use a
teleprompter sometimes, but honestly,
bullet points on your phone work
perfectly fine. For editing, I actually
cut empty space on Cap Cut and
autogenerate subtitles and change the
font if I don't like it and add
background music and then that's done.
I've also worked with agencies in the
past and still do to this day. They're
actually editing my video right now. But
I should mention short form videos
filmed and edited using my phone work as
well as videos filmed with my $2,000
camera and an agency. It really depends
on you and your budget. Now, finally,
part number five is the caption. Don't
just copy and paste your script because
it's not going to look good and it's
probably not going to be as engaging.
So, if your video hook is something
like, "I just launched a new AI tool
that's about to change the game for
creators," then your caption hook should
be my AI tool just launched, and it's
going to change everything. Keep your
caption on the 800 characters. Use 8 to
10 words max in the hooks. So, always
space your line. So, one line, then
space, then one line, then space. And
you can try and play with all the
formatting styles like one line space,
one line space, two line space, two line
space, whatever works for you. But
always try and have some visual
formatting going on. And to even
complement this further, you can add
bullet points so people don't just read,
they actually watch the video. Bullet
points are the summary of your video and
the video actually shares the depth. Oh,
and also I actually did just launch my
new AI tool. It's called Cleo. It learns
your voice. It writes 10 times faster
and it helps you script videos like this
one without overthinking. Check the link
in the description. And if you comment
below, I'll give one of you lifetime
access for free. Now you've got
everything you need to know to go all in
on video. And if not, at least you just
learned how to write a better LinkedIn
post. Because honestly, these skills are
transferable. Everything is writing.
Scripts, LinkedIn posts, newsletters,
keynote speeches, all of it. It's really
a win-win. We're literally watching
billiondoll companies pump money onto
this platform. But here's the reality.
This window won't stay open forever.
Every major opportunity feels obvious
until it's gone. The quality bar is at
the lowest it's ever been, and you might
as well try. Your opportunity to start
out as a business owner or creator or
even entrepreneur is right here on
LinkedIn. I want you to win because
LinkedIn changed my life and business
and it's time for you to change yours.